<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-11-11T09:55:55-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Daily writings from Silence</title><subtitle>God grant me the serenity To accept the things I cannot change; Courage to change the things I can; And wisdom to know the difference.</subtitle><author><name>Silence</name></author><entry><title type="html">At what ends, a specific type of politician</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/11/At-what-ends-specific-type-of-politician.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="At what ends, a specific type of politician" /><published>2020-11-11T06:10:59-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-11T06:10:59-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/11/At-what-ends-specific-type-of-politician</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/11/At-what-ends-specific-type-of-politician.html">&lt;p&gt;Similar mistake to the previous post on &lt;a href=&quot;https://silencevosh.github.io/2020/11/10/Not-going-enough-my-characters-motivations-for-traveling.html&quot;&gt;how I didn’t go deep enough into my character’s motivations:&lt;/a&gt;:
My character discovers he has this ability to sound like a native Spanish speaker; no matter the country he’s in, he can perfectly mimic the accent. I had said this is his superpower. But my coach pointed out, okay, but what’s the purpose? What ends is this a means to? My answer was to connect with others. No, she said, at what specific ends?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I brainstormed some options and came back to her with: he’s going to be a politician, a man of the people, helping Spanish communities around Chicago. And still! She pushed me further. What specific outcome is he chasing after?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My current iteration is he will set out to teach and show first-generation born Americans their native culture, where they come from. He will start an organization that gives them the opportunity to travel to their native country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Now, I need to figure out why. Why does this inspire him? How did he learn that’s what he’s going to do? What does that give to him internally?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="mistakes&amp;fixes" /><summary type="html">Similar mistake to the previous post on how I didn’t go deep enough into my character’s motivations:: My character discovers he has this ability to sound like a native Spanish speaker; no matter the country he’s in, he can perfectly mimic the accent. I had said this is his superpower. But my coach pointed out, okay, but what’s the purpose? What ends is this a means to? My answer was to connect with others. No, she said, at what specific ends?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">what happens when we stop dreaming</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/11/what-happens-when-we-stop-dreaming.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="what happens when we stop dreaming" /><published>2020-11-11T02:23:30-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-11T02:23:30-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/11/what-happens-when-we-stop-dreaming</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/11/what-happens-when-we-stop-dreaming.html">&lt;p&gt;In the opening of my favorite comic book, the Sandman, an evil man, Mr. Burgess uses magic to try and capture Death, so that he can live forever. The comic personifies the endless, as they are called, Death, Desire, Despair, Destiny, Destruction, and Dream. Death is a character in the story, who we journey along with as she does her work. In this opening scene, Mr. Burgess, expecting to trap her, traps her brother Dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next panel we see the consequences, shown with four different characters, of no longer having Dream in our lives:
&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SilenceVosh/silencevosh.github.io/master/_posts/assets/images/Sandman-whendreamsleave.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image info&quot; title=&quot;When Dream Leaves&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the upper left, the first three pictures, we see Ellie, asleep, and no longer with dreams, she never wakes up again. Below her, Daniel has his dream taken away from him, and no longer with dreams, he’s forever awake. Upper right, Stefan shocked, without dreams becomes paralyzed. And bottom right, Unity drifts off into a coma, unmoving, dead to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first book is about Dream escaping and recapturing this power, and returning to serve mankind again, so we can go on dreaming.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">In the opening of my favorite comic book, the Sandman, an evil man, Mr. Burgess uses magic to try and capture Death, so that he can live forever. The comic personifies the endless, as they are called, Death, Desire, Despair, Destiny, Destruction, and Dream. Death is a character in the story, who we journey along with as she does her work. In this opening scene, Mr. Burgess, expecting to trap her, traps her brother Dream.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Not going enough: my character’s motivations for traveling</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/09/Not-going-enough-my-characters-motivations-for-traveling.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Not going enough: my character's motivations for traveling" /><published>2020-11-09T06:10:59-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-09T06:10:59-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/09/Not-going-enough-my-characters-motivations-for-traveling</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/09/Not-going-enough-my-characters-motivations-for-traveling.html">&lt;p&gt;Here’s another instance where I didn’t go deep enough into my character; I stopped when the details were still too general:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While traveling he realized how alive he feels when he’s able to speak a foreign language. (Previously he majored in linguistics and “can” speak 3 languages, but so far it’s all been theory.) I then wrote how connecting with foreigners by speaker their language becomes an addition for him. And he decides to extend his trip in order to keep doing that and have fun speaking a foreign language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My coach said, “His decision to extend travel shouldn’t be for the joy of it. Give him something concrete he’s chasing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what she’s so good at, identifying what is a true motivation and what is a facade, appearing as a driving force in the character’s life, when in reality it’s something like simple joy which doesn’t actually motivate us to do much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would be much better is to say, he discovered how much he enjoys hearing the different versions of the Spanish tongue, so he extends travel with the goal of visiting every Spanish speaking country, to learn about their accents and slang.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instantly our character becomes more visual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt; * * * &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deeper: why does he enjoy hearing different versions of the Spanish tongue? What will get achieve by visiting all these Spanish speaking countries? What is his end prize? How does all this make him feel safe?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More concrete would be: he’s trying to woo a particular Spanish-speaking girl, and he believes if he could mimic all the language (for some reason to be justified) he could win her over.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="mistakes&amp;fixes" /><summary type="html">Here’s another instance where I didn’t go deep enough into my character; I stopped when the details were still too general:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">intuition | a final note.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/09/intuition-a-final-note.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="intuition | a final note." /><published>2020-11-09T06:10:59-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-09T06:10:59-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/09/intuition-a-final-note</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/09/intuition-a-final-note.html">&lt;p&gt;In this series, I stressed the importance of becoming more in touch with your intuition, and often I spoke of it as if that’s the only thing that matter and as if the other side is evil, but that’s not that whole truth. The objective, laid out by Osho, is to strip away all of these blockages and move through the world based on your true desires and feelings in the present moment. The problem with that is life isn’t solely about the individual. It’s about the group too. And for a group to function, we need rules, we need our ego in order to get along and to help us survive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;table&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;The Ego is in fact vital to our survival. … Its proper role is to stand back and observe, to scan the horizon, to monitor the data coming in from both the outside and the inside, and then, out of its wisdom make the necessary life decisions. - Robert Moore&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;King, Warrior, Magician, Lover&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
  &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without it, you might scream in a church because you feel like it. Or you might talk to a pretty girl even though she’s with a leather coated biker. It’s these blockages that remind you that’s not the best idea. There is wisdom, built up over a lifetime within some of these. It would be a shame to throw the baby out with the bathwater.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="humanlearnings" /><summary type="html">In this series, I stressed the importance of becoming more in touch with your intuition, and often I spoke of it as if that’s the only thing that matter and as if the other side is evil, but that’s not that whole truth. The objective, laid out by Osho, is to strip away all of these blockages and move through the world based on your true desires and feelings in the present moment. The problem with that is life isn’t solely about the individual. It’s about the group too. And for a group to function, we need rules, we need our ego in order to get along and to help us survive.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">intuition | how to make the leap?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/08/intuition-how-to-make-the-leap.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="intuition | how to make the leap?" /><published>2020-11-08T06:10:59-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-08T06:10:59-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/08/intuition-how-to-make-the-leap</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/08/intuition-how-to-make-the-leap.html">&lt;p&gt;This all got me thinking, like the mathematician how do we make that leap? The ability to do that seems fundamental, seems like the crown jewel of learning. Let’s look at this leap in other fields:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salsa dancers just know when to step on 1 based on the sounds of the music. They don’t need to count 1, 2, 3, 5, 6, 7. They make that leap.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A golfer stands over the golf ball knowing where the ball will land before he even swings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Writers who just know what their character will do next, or know the whole story.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my experience, when you reach a certain point, the leap just one day happens. Recently and suddenly while salsa body my body stepped on 1 without any thinking. It wasn’t until the song was over that I even noticed. Also back in college, I had one round of golf where every time I was within 15 feet of the hole, I knew the ball was in, and it was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In both of these, I had collected thousands of hours of different experiments and play and wathcing others, the whole time gathering data. Most of these countless hours were passed like the mathematician in his beginning stages, thinking, problem-solving, and rationally working out the problem. After enough time, my body was comfortable in the environment and took over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a painter this collecting data could be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;painting various pictures, from anything that inspires him&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pushing paint around with his fingers to see how it feels&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;watching a movie and taking note of things that evoked emotion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;recording a dream he had that was vivid&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;walking through a museum looking at other’s art&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;and so on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often I recall my friend telling me a quote from Atomic Habits: “Every action you take is a vote for the type of person you want to become.” Habits are about your identity, who you want to be. And furthermore, true identity is about making these leaps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I ask, in what area of your life do you want to make these leaps? And what habits will allow you to begin today, begin collecting data to get there?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="humanlearnings" /><summary type="html">This all got me thinking, like the mathematician how do we make that leap? The ability to do that seems fundamental, seems like the crown jewel of learning. Let’s look at this leap in other fields:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">intuition | common theme</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/07/intuition-common-theme.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="intuition | common theme" /><published>2020-11-07T06:10:59-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-07T06:10:59-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/07/intuition-common-theme</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/07/intuition-common-theme.html">&lt;p&gt;The common theme I noticed throughout this week is how these layers are all focused on desires and allowing desires to roam freely. Each layer corrupts you from naturally knowing and naturally acting how you want to act. Making the leap, as Osho says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most of my life, I’ve tried to break free from these blockages from the top down. Typically, I identify the hindering beliefs, or trapped emotions, or harmful patterns of thought, and then I design habits to overcome them. What could be easier is a bottom up approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what the great mathematicians do. They work on thousands of problems and examples and calculations. They work on them one at a time. And over the years and decades, their body collects the solutions. Until one day they intuitively move through the calculations, no longer having to go step by step. They make leaps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can do this with intuition. Collecting moments in our day where we follow our desire, moments in our day where we answer without much thought and simply follow our true self. Over time, as we collect experiences of trusting ourselves, these blockages will naturally be released, back from where they came, and you can begin to make leaps.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="humanlearnings" /><summary type="html">The common theme I noticed throughout this week is how these layers are all focused on desires and allowing desires to roam freely. Each layer corrupts you from naturally knowing and naturally acting how you want to act. Making the leap, as Osho says.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">intuition | corrupted by repression</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/06/intuition-corrupted-by-repression.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="intuition | corrupted by repression" /><published>2020-11-06T06:10:59-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-06T06:10:59-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/06/intuition-corrupted-by-repression</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/06/intuition-corrupted-by-repression.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For example, if your sex center functions as a sex center, it is perfectly good. But people have been repressing it so much that in many people the sex center does not exist in their genitals, it has moved into the head. This is what overlapping is. Now they make love through their head—hence the great importance of pornography, visualization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For starters, the difference between suppression and repression:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Suppression is consciously suppressing impulses. Repression is unconsciously denying impulses.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;With suppression, we recognize the urge to throw something, and we breathe. With repression, we have the same events happen to us, but we smile through it, unaware that inside is turmoil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For years, because of a job that demanded it, I trained myself to repress my emotions. In my work, it was as a sign of achievement if you could go through the job with a statued face. And now I have major energetic problems. First off, most of my energy resides in the only thing I allowed myself to feel, my head. Everything below the neck cut off. This caused grounding issues, and me to become “stuck in my head”. Vocally, all air coming from my belly is constricted and weak. It’s hard for me to yell, be it from fear, sadness, or joy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now for years after, I’ve been undoing all this harm. Through dancing I’ve learned to feel and use my joints, allowing me to intuitively dance. Through yoga, stretching, and ground-work, I’m gaining comfort on the ground; I can shift my weight around, roll my ankles, tumble my body, and the ground —- without inflicting pain —- holds me. And through breathe work and bioenergetics, I’ve begun to break the constriction in my belly and chest, and I can finally feel the joy in yelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Repression may be the longest-lasting harm and takes years of constant healing to even notice to tip of the iceberg.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="humanlearnings" /><summary type="html">For example, if your sex center functions as a sex center, it is perfectly good. But people have been repressing it so much that in many people the sex center does not exist in their genitals, it has moved into the head. This is what overlapping is. Now they make love through their head—hence the great importance of pornography, visualization.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">intuition | corrupted by sentimentality</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/05/intuition-corrupted-by-sentimentality.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="intuition | corrupted by sentimentality" /><published>2020-11-05T06:10:59-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-05T06:10:59-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/05/intuition-corrupted-by-sentimentality</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/05/intuition-corrupted-by-sentimentality.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The fourth layer is emotionality, sentimentalism. It is pseudofeeling, much ado about nothing, much fuss. The female mind is expert at this. It is kind of empty; it is just on the surface. It is impotent sympathy; it does not do a thing. If somebody is ill, you sit by their side and you cry. Your crying is not going to help.** The house is on fire and you cry—that is not going to help either. This pseudo kind of feeling has to be detected; otherwise you will never know what real feeling is. - Osho&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This made me pause because, on one hand, it is how I’ve always thought, what good does it do to cry about your house burning down. Yet it seems like you are grieving, grieving for the loss of your house, which is extremely healthy and freeing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His point is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Whenever you really feel something in your heart, it immediately transforms you; it becomes action. That is the criterion—your feeling becomes action. If your feeling just remains a feeling and never becomes an action, then know well that it is pseudo. Then you are deceiving yourself or somebody else. - Osho&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emotions are for acting. They naturally have a purpose. This purpose could be calling a loved one to tell them you’re grateful for your relationship or it could be having a difficult conversation with someone. The more in-tune you are, the more you make the leap to that purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting this aside, the following day I came across the concept of stigmergy. Stigmergy (or stigmergic cognition) is a mechanism of communication between our body and our environment. It’s a way our minds offload cognition to the body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We don’t see valueless entities and then attribute meaning to them. We perceive the meaning directly. We see floors, to walk on, and doors, to duck through, and chairs, to sit on. It’s for this reason that a beanbag and a stump both fall into the latter category, despite having little objectively in common. We see rocks, because we can throw them, and clouds, because they can rain on us, and apples, to eat, and the automobiles of other people, to get in our way and annoy us. We see tools and obstacles, not objects or things. Furthermore, we see tools and obstacles at the “handy” level of analysis that makes them most useful (or dangerous), given our needs, abilities and perceptual limitations. The world reveals itself to us as something to utilize and something to navigate through — not as something that merely is. - Jordan Peterson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are active beings, evolved to take in information and act. Our body sees a computer chair and knows to sit in it without mental cognition. I think Osho is expressing the same thing. Emotions should from the environment, not from your mental cognition, and not only that, but they should lead to purposeful action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, just days ago, I spent an entire counseling session in this state of puesdofeeling. I entered the session, unsure what I wanted to talk about. I had a lot on my mind. I felt like I should talk about my recent breakup, but I had no idea what I wanted to talk about concerning that. I wasn’t in touch. So instead, I spent 30 minutes, not committing to a subject, until my body just shut down. I remember, after we had decided to talk about the breakup, emotions poured into my chest, wanting me to sob, really sob, loudly. Instead I squeezed it down, knowing if I even opened my mouth the slightest, if I exhaled at all, a dying calf would sound out of me. Squeezing, my head felt like it was going to explode. And on the brink of passing up, I succeeded, the pressure went out of sight, and I could talk again. Afterwards, I spent the rest of the time in a child-like state, silent, unwilling to do anything, even though I felt I wanted to get past this. In those moments, however, the puesdofeeling of resistance was too comforting. I completely blocked myself from properly communicating with my environment, and I left the session no further along my journey than before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt; * * * &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sorry for the wide ranging and long piece. This morning, I didn’t have time to write a shorter one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:right;&quot;&gt; Next: [Repression.](https://silencevosh.github.io/2020/11/06/intuition-corrupted-by-repression.html) &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="humanlearnings" /><summary type="html">The fourth layer is emotionality, sentimentalism. It is pseudofeeling, much ado about nothing, much fuss. The female mind is expert at this. It is kind of empty; it is just on the surface. It is impotent sympathy; it does not do a thing. If somebody is ill, you sit by their side and you cry. Your crying is not going to help.** The house is on fire and you cry—that is not going to help either. This pseudo kind of feeling has to be detected; otherwise you will never know what real feeling is. - Osho</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">intuition | corrupted by rationalization</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/04/intuition-corrupted-by-rationalization.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="intuition | corrupted by rationalization" /><published>2020-11-04T06:10:59-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-04T06:10:59-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/04/intuition-corrupted-by-rationalization</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/04/intuition-corrupted-by-rationalization.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The third filter, the third layer, is pseudoreasoning, rationalization, explanations, excuses. All are borrowed. Not a single one is your own authentic experience, but they give a kind of satisfaction: you think you are a very rational being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can vary from the basic poison of making an excuse not to do something you want to do, such as not calling a friend who you miss because they haven’t called you recently, or the more complex poison where you rationalize away situations and events in order to feel better, instead of exploring what the feeling is telling you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, it’s easy to find comfort in rationalizations. They calm my mind, it seems. Most of my journey has been spent observing myself, explaining my behavior, and trying to understand and rationalize my thoughts. How much harm has this secretly done? What cost is there to rationalizations, no matter how savory, such as one of my favorites: this too shall pass? What deeper seeded feelings and personalities and thoughts am I suppressing with this borrowed language? What if instead of trying to understand and explain – I felt what needed to be felt or I expressed whatever needed to be expressed and let out, whatever personality arose, fearful, hateful, depressed, even psychopathic laughing, screeching. Get it out. It wants me to take action, to say something, to change something, to do something. I, however, breathe and whisper this too shall pass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps this is why these absolute truths and reminders are never effective when you’re helping a friend through a difficult time. Although you can remind them, I know you know this, but this too shall pass – in their emotional, pain-ridden state, that has nothing to do with who they are. Your rationalizations don’t help. They just want to be felt and understood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if instead, we remind them about authentic truths. We talk about their real journey, what they have gone through, how much they’ve learned and grown, how valuable they are. We talked about how they now feel sadness and grief at the loss of a beautiful thing. Something they had the opportunity to experience and to play with and to love. Something that if they made many sacrifices for, and they took many chances for, and if they didn’t change they would have never had to opportunity to be with that beauty. But they tried. They cared. Just something pushed them in a different direction. And all those opportunities to play with that beauty helped them change and see the world with new colors. And now they are here. About to embark on a new journey. Filled with new beautiful things. And even more colors. Just waiting to be seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or you can go on making excuses, rationalizations, and explanations. It’s your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:right;&quot;&gt; Next: [Sentimentality.](https://silencevosh.github.io/2020/11/05/intuition-corrupted-by-sentimentality.html) &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="humanlearnings" /><summary type="html">The third filter, the third layer, is pseudoreasoning, rationalization, explanations, excuses. All are borrowed. Not a single one is your own authentic experience, but they give a kind of satisfaction: you think you are a very rational being.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">intuition | corrupted by beliefs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/03/intuition-corrupted-by-beliefs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="intuition | corrupted by beliefs" /><published>2020-11-03T06:10:59-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-03T06:10:59-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/03/intuition-corrupted-by-beliefs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/03/intuition-corrupted-by-beliefs.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Man goes on burdening himself because he cannot cry and cannot weep, it is “unmanly.” And women have been taught to cry and weep, it is perfectly womanly, so they go on crying and weeping even where it is not needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is often the starting point of stories. In my coach’s system, I first identify the misbelief that has been culturally or parentally or eventually trained. And with that starting location in mind, I explore how my character lives out his life with that misbelief, watching how that belief evolves picking up new harmful beliefs, escalates becoming more harmful and damning, and expands rippling into other layers in his life, until soon the belief corrupts everything he does. And he’s in a dark place, unable to see a way out, a way back to his true self. And then, page 1 of our story begins, as he tries to return home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stories teach us to get more in touch with our intuition by exposing these misbeliefs and these corrupted layers that block us. The next blockage is a fault of my own: &lt;a href=&quot;https://silencevosh.github.io/2020/11/04/intuition-corrupted-by-rationalization.html&quot;&gt;rationalization.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="humanlearnings" /><summary type="html">Man goes on burdening himself because he cannot cry and cannot weep, it is “unmanly.” And women have been taught to cry and weep, it is perfectly womanly, so they go on crying and weeping even where it is not needed.</summary></entry></feed>