<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-12-03T08:38:41-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Daily writings from Silence</title><subtitle>God grant me the serenity To accept the things I cannot change; Courage to change the things I can; And wisdom to know the difference.</subtitle><author><name>Silence</name></author><entry><title type="html">What is a good editing session?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/03/What-is-a-good-editing-session.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is a good editing session?" /><published>2020-12-03T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/12/03/What-is-a-good-editing-session</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/03/What-is-a-good-editing-session.html">&lt;p&gt;Recently, I had a breakthrough while editing a scene. In this scene, two characters, Josh and Dave, strut into the university cafeteria looking for someone to eat with. They had seen a girl, Powder who both had liked for her white hair that made her look like the mystical-type you only see in the movies. Josh and Dave were waiting until someone left her table to slide in and start a conversation when at a neighboring table they spot Tony, the star basketball player in the nation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dave decides that he wants to eat with Tony in order to impress Powder, and takes off, without discussing it with Josh. Now Josh has a decision to follow Dave or to watch from afar. As I was reading my work, the emotion of this moment didn’t feel right and I knew it needed work. Previously this is what I had:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In front of me, the giant spooned fried rice out of a bowl built for composting. “Dude.” I nudged again.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“Tony,” Dave exclaimed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“It’s game-day, too.” I said.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“Let’s kill two birds with one stone.” He peered back to Powder and stood up. “Make friends with Tony, and we make friends with Powder.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“Wait…” But already he was gone.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;F@*k. You can’t just do that. Tony’s alone. Headphones on. He’s zoning, not to be distressed. And Dave proudly charging in. And now I’m sitting here twiddling my thumbs. Barging in on another classmate is one thing. In on the best player in the nation, hours prior to the biggest game of his career, I can’t just follow Dave into that. How is this different from the countless of others you’ve befriended over lunch? People like bantering with us. Conversations flow. And even when they stumble, we take the lead and make it light. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A mob of eyes tracked Dave as he neared, about to do something books can’t teach. And every single beating heart yearning to do what he was about to do. Yet — not one of them free enough to do it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Suddenly on my feet, a jolt of curiosity tossed me racing onward, this was our environment. Dave, few tables in front of me, already had his arms outstretched, greeting the nation’s best basketball player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While editing, I knew the structure was right, I just needed to figure out the emotion, so I began to hack the F@*k paragraph to pieces, knowing that is where the key reaction lies and knowing there’s a lot going on and needs to be ordered. Then it struck me. &lt;strong&gt;I never gave the reader time to understand why Dave taking off would evoke all of this in Josh.&lt;/strong&gt; Instead I had Dave take off, and only afterwards Josh explains why that’s a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going back and pausing, I asked when Josh sees Tony, what does he want and what does he expect? Quickly, it was clear that Josh never expects to go talk with Tony, and it would make his day to simply stay right there and eat close to Tony. He doesn’t need to talk to him to enjoy this lunch hour. There’s something invigorating about eating close to the best player in the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the edited layer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“It’s game-day, too.” I said, watching him bob, sitting alone, getting in the zone.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I began to unwrap my sandwich. Powder had left my mind. Today, I was eating with Tony, the best player in the nation. It was the same egg muffin I eat nearly every day, yet my first bite was one of the most savory I ever remember. Everything was just right, like at the theaters, reclined in a lazy boy while being served a hotdog, with Tommy Boy up on the big screen. Every few bites I spied towards the back corner where he still bobbed and excavated rice.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“Let’s kill two birds with one stone.” Dave said after what must have felt like an hour to him. To my left, Dave peered over his shoulder, back at Powder. Maybe he wants to eat with Powder while watching Tony, I thought.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“I rather—”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He stood up. “Make friends with Tony, and we make friends with Powder.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“Wait…” What? But already he was gone. Marching towards Tony.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can’t do that, Dave. Barging in on another classmate is one thing. In on the best player in the nation, hours prior to biggest game of his career… How is this — the heat from my sandwich’s wrapper collected on my palms. How is this different from the countless of others we’ve befriended over lunch? Conversation will flow. And even if it stumbles, we take the lead and make it light and warm.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A mob of eyes tracked Dave as he neared, about to do something books can’t teach. And every single beating heart yearning to do what he was doing. Yet — not one of them free enough to do it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Suddenly on my feet, a jolt of curiosity tossed me racing onward. Dave, few tables in front of me, already had his arms outstretched, greeting the best basketball player in the nation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now, when Dave just takes off, the reader understands Josh’s dilemma, and then when Josh arrives at his conclusion to go talk to Tony, not only are the stakes higher, but the excitement and emotions are higher. What’s more, I noticed by understanding those desires and expectations, it became so much easier to write the reaction at that moment of Dave leaving. What needed to be cut was so clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt; * * * &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a joyful breakthrough for me because I could clearly see how to get emotion on the page and I could see my progress right there in the reading experience.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="mistakes&amp;fixes" /><summary type="html">Recently, I had a breakthrough while editing a scene. In this scene, two characters, Josh and Dave, strut into the university cafeteria looking for someone to eat with. They had seen a girl, Powder who both had liked for her white hair that made her look like the mystical-type you only see in the movies. Josh and Dave were waiting until someone left her table to slide in and start a conversation when at a neighboring table they spot Tony, the star basketball player in the nation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Setting Expectations with simple insights into the character</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/02/Setting-Expectations-with-simple-insights-into-the-character.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Setting Expectations with simple insights into the character" /><published>2020-12-02T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/12/02/Setting-Expectations-with-simple-insights-into-the-character</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/02/Setting-Expectations-with-simple-insights-into-the-character.html">&lt;p&gt;Scenes are about pleasure transitions, which come from expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just worked on a scene where my character goes to talk to the best player in the nation. His initial expectation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A simple, harmless good luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the scene goes on, he manages to make the player (Tony) smile. And that makes his day. (It’s MORE than expected.) But the scene isn’t over. Now he desires to leave, but his friend is going on and on, to the point that the player is getting annoyed. The tension is growing and now there’s a risk in my character losing that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And eventually, our protagonist, dying to get out of there, looks back at Tony:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tony was no longer smiling, my stomach turned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But his friend goes on and goes until the player explodes. All is lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This interaction happens over a thousand words or so, but I find it interesting that this simple line, 5 words long, “a simple, harmless good luck,” set up the ebb and flow of pleasure/pain. If we, the reader, didn’t understand these expectations of the character, we wouldn’t understand why he wants to escape so desperately.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="writingmentalmodels" /><summary type="html">Scenes are about pleasure transitions, which come from expectations.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">One Plot from the Sandman Comics: a vortex, when our fictional stories become reality</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/01/One-plot-from-the-Sandman-comics-a-vortex-when-our-ficitional-stories-become-reality.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One Plot from the Sandman Comics: a vortex, when our fictional stories become reality" /><published>2020-12-01T02:23:30-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-01T02:23:30-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/12/01/One-plot-from-the-Sandman-comics-a-vortex-when-our-ficitional-stories-become-reality</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/01/One-plot-from-the-Sandman-comics-a-vortex-when-our-ficitional-stories-become-reality.html">&lt;p&gt;In book two, Morpheus, the lord of dreams, has a problem, a glitch in his matrix, what is called a vortex, a portal between the dream world and reality. Morpheus first learns of this when a few of the creatures escape his dream world, two monsters named Brute and Glob as well as one of the nightmares of the dream world, the Corinthian, a man with teeth instead of eyes, who feasts on the eyes of his prey. These monsters have escaped into reality because of the vortex which Morpheus sets out to close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We learn the vortex is an innocence girl, Rose, who is trying to find her way through life. Rose thinks everything is normal even when strange things start happening around her. Her dreams and the stories she knows are becoming reality. After moving into an apartment that looked just like the dollhouse from her grandma’s, she meets her neighbors, Ken and Barbie, and strange sisters who collect spiders. Then typically what she thinks, what’s going to happen before it happens, both negative and positive thoughts, happens as she thinks it. Dreams are becoming reality. So, if she fears someone’s going to find her in this alley, then someone appears and finds her. And then maybe she hopes she’s saved by some superhero and some superhero shows up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can Morpheus capture these escaped monsters and bring him back to the dream realm before they corrupt earth forever?  The whole series plays on this question of what is reality and what are dreams and is there actually a difference.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">In book two, Morpheus, the lord of dreams, has a problem, a glitch in his matrix, what is called a vortex, a portal between the dream world and reality. Morpheus first learns of this when a few of the creatures escape his dream world, two monsters named Brute and Glob as well as one of the nightmares of the dream world, the Corinthian, a man with teeth instead of eyes, who feasts on the eyes of his prey. These monsters have escaped into reality because of the vortex which Morpheus sets out to close.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Surreal Superhero: John Wick</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/30/Surreal-Superhero-John-Wick.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Surreal Superhero: John Wick" /><published>2020-11-30T02:23:30-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-30T02:23:30-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/30/Surreal-Superhero-John-Wick</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/30/Surreal-Superhero-John-Wick.html">&lt;p&gt;In the screenwriting book, Save the Cat, the author lays out his theory on the archetypical plots of story. Humans can only do so many different things. What are the abstracted plots across all stories, the plots we repeatedly see over and over while watching movies? One of the plots he names is called the Superhero plot, where we watch someone extraordinaire do a lot of fun and exciting things. It’s a wish-fulfillment plot, where, for 2 hours, we can forget about our mundane lives and dream of being extra-ordinary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s Blake describing this genre:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Somewhere up on Mt. Olympus is a special guy or gal who is on the way down here. Poor dope! Though imbued with amazing powers, and sent to save us dumb clucks from ourselves, he’s the one who’s stuck: Not quite human nor quite god, unable to date — or tell his plight to anyone who’ll “get it” — Mr. Square Jaw must bear the brunt of the hostility, jealousy, and fear from us Lilliputians. He don’t get no respect, he don’t get no love — he don’t get nada! And yet he has no choice but to be our savior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Wick is the People’s superhero, one of the subsets of this genre. He’s an ordinary guy who rises up the ranks to set things right. These are some of my favorite movies, such as Gladiator and the Patriot. In the first of the series, we sit back and watch John do amazing things while he takes revenge on the guys who killed his puppy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easy viewing, lots of action, legendary fight scenes. Give it a watch!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">In the screenwriting book, Save the Cat, the author lays out his theory on the archetypical plots of story. Humans can only do so many different things. What are the abstracted plots across all stories, the plots we repeatedly see over and over while watching movies? One of the plots he names is called the Superhero plot, where we watch someone extraordinaire do a lot of fun and exciting things. It’s a wish-fulfillment plot, where, for 2 hours, we can forget about our mundane lives and dream of being extra-ordinary.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">there always are consequences, Don</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/29/there-always-are-consequences-Don.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="there always are consequences, Don" /><published>2020-11-29T02:23:30-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-29T02:23:30-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/29/there-always-are-consequences-Don</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/29/there-always-are-consequences-Don.html">&lt;p&gt;Don, out of a need to break through the facade that he has created, cheats on his wife a lot. In Season 2, he dealt with the consequences by being put out of the house, before he rediscovers the love for his wife, and convinces her to give him a second chance. The season ends with a happy moment, of Don placing his hand on top of Betty’s, a symbol of them back together. Then, Season 3 starts out with Don, although more hesitant, back to his old ways, cheating on Betty with a flight attendant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The producers didn’t want to make a big deal of this. Season 3 wasn’t going to be about Betty leaving Don because he’s cheating on her again. But every action must have consequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after Don returns home, while laying in bed with Betty, enjoying the comfort of his loving family (something he previously took for granted), his daughter finds a pair of wings in his suitcase. They are the flight attendant’s.
    “Daddy, are these for me?”
    Don pauses. Glances at Betty, watching for her reaction. Internally demons are screaming at him.
    “Yes, of course,” he says.&lt;br /&gt;
Betty doesn’t react. She trusts her husband now. That night Don doesn’t sleep.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">Don, out of a need to break through the facade that he has created, cheats on his wife a lot. In Season 2, he dealt with the consequences by being put out of the house, before he rediscovers the love for his wife, and convinces her to give him a second chance. The season ends with a happy moment, of Don placing his hand on top of Betty’s, a symbol of them back together. Then, Season 3 starts out with Don, although more hesitant, back to his old ways, cheating on Betty with a flight attendant.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">An Author’s Eye: Forks</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/28/An-Authors-Eye-Forks.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Author's Eye: Forks" /><published>2020-11-28T02:23:30-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-28T02:23:30-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/28/An-Authors-Eye-Forks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/28/An-Authors-Eye-Forks.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Never let a painful event happen on an average day. - my coach&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just a great principle to keep in mind when story building. Whenever something painful happens to your character, make sure there’s something else going on in his life that it affects. This creates a lot of poor decisions and a lot of forks in the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How I’ve been using this: 
When I uncover a painful event, I make sure it doesn’t go to waste, by asking simple questions. What else is going on in his life right now? What is he thinking about? Who has he been talking to a lot? Who hasn’t he been talking to that’s on his mind? And I answer these questions until I discover some fork in the road that he’s facing, where his life’s direction is at a crossroads. Then I send him towards his doom and start the process over again.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="writingmentalmodels" /><summary type="html">Never let a painful event happen on an average day. - my coach</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why do internal motivations and expectations create better writing?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/27/Why-do-internal-motivations-and-expectations-create-better-writing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why do internal motivations and expectations create better writing?" /><published>2020-11-27T02:23:30-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-27T02:23:30-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/27/Why-do-internal-motivations-and-expectations-create-better-writing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/27/Why-do-internal-motivations-and-expectations-create-better-writing.html">&lt;p&gt;when we know their internal motivations, we understand why they want what they want externally, and then we relate to them. And when we relate, we want what they want. And when we want what they want, have a stake in their external desire for the scene and we feel tension about not getting that desire. Tension evokes emotion.s&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="writingmentalmodels" /><summary type="html">when we know their internal motivations, we understand why they want what they want externally, and then we relate to them. And when we relate, we want what they want. And when we want what they want, have a stake in their external desire for the scene and we feel tension about not getting that desire. Tension evokes emotion.s</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Writing the First Draft, Quality versus Quantity</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/26/Writing-the-First-Draft-Quality-versus-Quantity.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Writing the First Draft, Quality versus Quantity" /><published>2020-11-26T02:23:30-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-26T02:23:30-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/26/Writing-the-First-Draft-Quality-versus-Quantity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/26/Writing-the-First-Draft-Quality-versus-Quantity.html">&lt;p&gt;In the last post, I stressed how good writing captures the internal mind-state of the subject, letting you in on their motivations, what makes them tick, and why they want what they want. But that isn’t so easy. That writing takes effort and work and patience. And not always do you have that energy or insight. Sometimes, you sit there and watch the cursor blink without any idea where to begin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When you don’t know what to do, do a lot. - Tiago Forte&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just go! Focus on getting many words onto the page, without caring where it goes. When you can’t produce quality work, focus on quantity. As you dump words onto the page, you start to gain momentum. Then, afterwards, you can always go back and add the layers and make the writing deeper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both methods have pros and cons, but that doesn’t matter. What matters is fitting the method to your mind-state. You can choose how to work. Could you find flow focusing on quality work? If not, flow into quantity. In due time, your mind will be ready for quality work again.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="professionalwriter" /><summary type="html">In the last post, I stressed how good writing captures the internal mind-state of the subject, letting you in on their motivations, what makes them tick, and why they want what they want. But that isn’t so easy. That writing takes effort and work and patience. And not always do you have that energy or insight. Sometimes, you sit there and watch the cursor blink without any idea where to begin.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">emotional writing expresses the psyche</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/25/emotional-writing-expresses-the-psyche.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="emotional writing expresses the psyche" /><published>2020-11-25T02:23:30-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-25T02:23:30-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/25/emotional-writing-expresses-the-psyche</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/25/emotional-writing-expresses-the-psyche.html">&lt;p&gt;In my last post about Don, I found myself jumping moment to moment, speeding along towards an end, stating one thing after another without expressing anything internally with Don.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don visits Anna. He hears from her niece that Anna has cancer and the family decided not to tell her. Don says to tell her or he will. Anna’s sister says no. “Don, you have no choice in what happens within my family.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a tendency of mine. It’s lazy thinking. It’s going from one to the next to the next until a whole post is written. But good writing slows down, and within each sentence, takes into account the character’s emotions, motivations, and misreadings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Don visits Anna, he hears from her niece that Anna has cancer and that the family decided not to tell her. Don, angry and hurt, demands that someone tells her or else he will. Besides his kids, Anna is the one person Don cares about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Besides his kids, Anna is the one person Don cares about.” This line shows us why Don is so motivated to be with Anna and to do what’s best for her and shows why this will be so painful for Don.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously I posted about a &lt;a href=&quot;https://silencevosh.github.io/2020/11/14/Mike-Tyson-fucking-great-character-inspiration.html&quot;&gt;rant by Mike Tyson&lt;/a&gt; that affected me and I think this is how he evoked so much emotion. In his rant, he uses words that express internal turmoil and emotion, in his case one of death, revenge, and war. He’s not saying they feared him because he knocked everyone out he faced. No. That’s not what he tried to do every time he entered the ring. He says, “That’s why they feared me when I was in the ring because I was an &lt;strong&gt;annihilator&lt;/strong&gt;.” He’s trying to kill the other man.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">In my last post about Don, I found myself jumping moment to moment, speeding along towards an end, stating one thing after another without expressing anything internally with Don.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mad Man #1, Don Draper</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/24/Mad-Man-1-Don-Draper.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mad Man #1, Don Draper" /><published>2020-11-24T02:23:30-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-24T02:23:30-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/24/Mad-Man-1-Don-Draper</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/24/Mad-Man-1-Don-Draper.html">&lt;p&gt;In the TV series Mad Men, even though Don appears to have everything, internally he’s deeply flawed and controlled by the pain of his childhood. The core pain that drives him is the feeling that he’s alone and lacks a family. Growing up, his mother died in labor, and his father was killed from a kick by a spooked horse. When he became old enough, he enlisted in the army. He served in a war until his comrade is killed on duty. Wanting out and to start a new life, he secretly traded dog-tags. He sacrificed the last traces of his family name and took on the name of the fallen comrade: Don Draper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the series, Don is driven by this need to not feel alone. It drives his mistakes, his emotions, and his drinking. He just wants to be known for who he is, which is impossible behind the name that isn’t his and celebrating birthdays that aren’t his to celebrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He marries into a beautiful family, but behind his facade, the marriage falls apart after his wife learns of his secret and his true identity. Feeling betrayed, she tries to accept and love him, tries to give him what he really needs, but the deception is too great and she leaves him. Don is alone and just paid a huge price for allowing someone to see his past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the episode “The Good News,” season 4 episode 3, there’s a heart-wrenching moment. Out on the east coast, Don is visiting his friend Anna. Anna Draper, that is, but she isn’t his name, rather, she’s the widow of Don’s fallen comrade. After Don had deserted the war and took on Anna’s late husband’s name, he explained the situation to her and said he’ll take care of her. Anna is the only person who truly knows who Don is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Don visits her, he hears from her niece that Anna has cancer and the family decided not to tell her. Don, angry, demands that someone tells her or he will. Excluding his children, Anna is the only person Don cares about. Anna’s sister says no. “Don, you have no choice in what happens within my family.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still hoped Don would stay with Anna, would take care of her, and spend some time with her to express his endearment. But driven the by pain of learning he has no say in this family, reading into that that he’s not family, and has no family, he pretends work called, hugs her, and leaves. He never talks to her again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pain makes us go mad.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">In the TV series Mad Men, even though Don appears to have everything, internally he’s deeply flawed and controlled by the pain of his childhood. The core pain that drives him is the feeling that he’s alone and lacks a family. Growing up, his mother died in labor, and his father was killed from a kick by a spooked horse. When he became old enough, he enlisted in the army. He served in a war until his comrade is killed on duty. Wanting out and to start a new life, he secretly traded dog-tags. He sacrificed the last traces of his family name and took on the name of the fallen comrade: Don Draper.</summary></entry></feed>