<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-12-10T07:54:11-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Daily writings from Silence</title><subtitle>Live by the harmless untruths that make you brave and kind and healthy and happy. - Kurt Vonnegut</subtitle><author><name>Silence</name></author><entry><title type="html">Thor catches a sea serpent.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/10/Thor-catches-a-sea-serpent.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thor catches a sea serpent." /><published>2020-12-10T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/12/10/Thor-catches-a-sea-serpent</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/10/Thor-catches-a-sea-serpent.html">&lt;p&gt;Thor, the thunder god, and Hymir, a giant, go on a fishing trip. Thor wanting to catch the biggest fish he could find steers the boat into the deepest and darkest part of the sea. What he ends up facing is Jormundand, a legendary sea serpent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SilenceVosh/silencevosh.github.io/master/_posts/assets/images/ThorFishing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image info&quot; title=&quot;Thor fighting Jormundand&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Imagine from: &lt;a href=&quot;https://thevikingdragon.com/blogs/news/thor-the-giants-kettle-and-the-midgard-serpent&quot;&gt;thevikingdragon.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way Neil Gaiman’s described this earned a blog post of its own:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Thor held onto the line.&lt;br /&gt;“It’s going to drag us under.”&lt;br /&gt;Boomed Hymir in horror. “Let go of the line.”&lt;br /&gt;Thor shook his head.&lt;br /&gt;He strained against the fishing line determined to hold on. The thunder god slammed his feet through the bottom of the boat and used the sea bottom to brace himself, and he began to hall Jormungand onto the boat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thungder god slamming his feet through the boat and using the sea bottom to brace himself, love that. It’s so visual and fun because why can’t the thunder god do that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">Thor, the thunder god, and Hymir, a giant, go on a fishing trip. Thor wanting to catch the biggest fish he could find steers the boat into the deepest and darkest part of the sea. What he ends up facing is Jormundand, a legendary sea serpent.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ensuring Emotion in Important Lines: “it’s game-day too”</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/09/Ensuring-Emotion-in-Important-Lines-its-game-day-too.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ensuring Emotion in Important Lines: &quot;it's game-day too&quot;
" /><published>2020-12-09T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/12/09/Ensuring-Emotion-in-Important-Lines-its-game-day-too</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/09/Ensuring-Emotion-in-Important-Lines-its-game-day-too.html">&lt;p&gt;I had a line of dialogue that heightens the stakes. As I’ve been talking about, my characters are about to talk with the star basketball player in the nation. One of my characters mentions how “It’s game day, too,” meaning look there’s Tony, hours before he plays in one of the biggest games of his career. The line is good, but I wasted it. When he said it, there’s no emotion behind it. If I would adjust where that’s written in the text, there could be fear behind that like when Dave leaves their table to say something to Tony. Or there could be awe behind it, like if Josh, my POV character, thinks it, such as “woah, look, he’s there eating his game-day meal, just hours before he’ll be on national TV.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s important is to recognize these opportunities and make sure they don’t go to waste.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="mistakes&amp;fixes" /><summary type="html">I had a line of dialogue that heightens the stakes. As I’ve been talking about, my characters are about to talk with the star basketball player in the nation. One of my characters mentions how “It’s game day, too,” meaning look there’s Tony, hours before he plays in one of the biggest games of his career. The line is good, but I wasted it. When he said it, there’s no emotion behind it. If I would adjust where that’s written in the text, there could be fear behind that like when Dave leaves their table to say something to Tony. Or there could be awe behind it, like if Josh, my POV character, thinks it, such as “woah, look, he’s there eating his game-day meal, just hours before he’ll be on national TV.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">style | lowercase part 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/08/style-lowercase-part-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="style | lowercase part 2" /><published>2020-12-08T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/12/08/style-lowercase-part-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/08/style-lowercase-part-2.html">&lt;p&gt;I can’t stop thinking of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://silencevosh.github.io/2020/12/04/lowercase-texting-is-fascinating.html&quot;&gt;lowercase post.&lt;/a&gt; I value every single keystroke in writing and pick apart each stroke to ensure it’s the right one. It blows my mind thinking there are circumstances that writing in lowercase will communicate more effectively. And I’m already seeing it in my own communication with my friends and family. A text: “how’s your day going?” reads so much more friendly than “How is your day going?” I’m not overthinking this. The capital letter contains more pressure to respond, it’s serious and has an authoritative command. There’s a time for that, just not then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe a friend is going through a hard situation, like his grandpa — who he used to share a snickers with every 1st of the month — just passed away. Now, “How is your day going?” is better, since it’s more sincere, and more wanting to truly know. Please, tell me. Followed by a simple lowercase, i’m around if need. It’s caring yet no pressure. You take your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I will make a lot of mistakes on my way to figuring this out, but that won’t stop me. I will continue to play and tinker and learn from those mistakes how to use writing to better connect with my family, friends, and community.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="writingstyle" /><summary type="html">I can’t stop thinking of the lowercase post. I value every single keystroke in writing and pick apart each stroke to ensure it’s the right one. It blows my mind thinking there are circumstances that writing in lowercase will communicate more effectively. And I’m already seeing it in my own communication with my friends and family. A text: “how’s your day going?” reads so much more friendly than “How is your day going?” I’m not overthinking this. The capital letter contains more pressure to respond, it’s serious and has an authoritative command. There’s a time for that, just not then.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Every manuscript I mistakenly have at least one bit (too) conceptual.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/07/Every-manuscript-I-mistakenly-have-at-least-one-too-conceptual-bit.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Every manuscript I mistakenly have at least one bit (too) conceptual." /><published>2020-12-07T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/12/07/Every-manuscript-I-mistakenly-have-at-least-one-too-conceptual-bit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/07/Every-manuscript-I-mistakenly-have-at-least-one-too-conceptual-bit.html">&lt;p&gt;Let me show you an example of a moment in my character’s life where he wouldn’t be thinking conceptual or logical thoughts. Here’s a clip from the scene:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I felt Dave’s head whip forward. “Tony!” he exclaimed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It was him. He wore a black, sleeveless hoodie, our mascot, Phil the Phoenix across his broad chest. A pair of headphones clamped over his hood, hiding him from the world and the world from him.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“It’s game-day, too,” I said, watching him bob, sitting alone, getting in the zone.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I began to unwrap my sandwich. Powder had left my mind. Today, I was eating with Tony, the best player in the nation. It was the same egg muffin I eat nearly every day, yet my first bite was one of the most savory I ever remember. Everything was just right, like at the theaters, reclined in a lazy boy while being served a hotdog, with Tommy Boy up on the big screen. Every few bites I spied towards the back corner where he still bobbed and excavated rice.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“Let’s kill two birds with one stone,” Dave said after what must have felt like an hour to him. To my left, Dave peered over his shoulder, back at Powder. Maybe he wants to eat with Powder while watching Tony, I thought.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“I rather—”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He stood up. “Make friends with Tony, and we make friends with Powder.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“Wait…” What? But already he was gone. Marching towards Tony.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can’t do that, Dave. Barging in on another classmate is one thing. In on the best player in the nation, hours prior to the biggest game of his career… How is this — the heat from my sandwich’s wrapper collected on my palm. &lt;strong&gt;How is this different from the countless others we’ve befriended over lunch? Conversations flow. And even if they stumble, we take the lead and make it light and warm.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A mob of eyes tracked Dave as he neared, about to do something books can’t teach. And every single beating heart yearning to do what he was doing. Yet — not one of them free enough to do it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Suddenly on my feet, a jolt of curiosity tossed me racing onward. Dave, few tables in front of me, already had his arms outstretched, greeting the best basketball player in the nation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My character here isn’t thinking about how people like talking with them. There’s no time for thoughts like that. His friend is doing something unforgivable. It’s survival mode. He’s freaking out. And he has a sense of urgency to get to a solution. No time to wonder lust about people liking him. How can he save the situation before Dave does something drastic?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could have been noticed beforehand if I would have paused to ask a simple question, the question from yesterday: what is his mind-state at this moment?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="mistakes&amp;fixes" /><summary type="html">Let me show you an example of a moment in my character’s life where he wouldn’t be thinking conceptual or logical thoughts. Here’s a clip from the scene: I felt Dave’s head whip forward. “Tony!” he exclaimed.It was him. He wore a black, sleeveless hoodie, our mascot, Phil the Phoenix across his broad chest. A pair of headphones clamped over his hood, hiding him from the world and the world from him.“It’s game-day, too,” I said, watching him bob, sitting alone, getting in the zone.I began to unwrap my sandwich. Powder had left my mind. Today, I was eating with Tony, the best player in the nation. It was the same egg muffin I eat nearly every day, yet my first bite was one of the most savory I ever remember. Everything was just right, like at the theaters, reclined in a lazy boy while being served a hotdog, with Tommy Boy up on the big screen. Every few bites I spied towards the back corner where he still bobbed and excavated rice.“Let’s kill two birds with one stone,” Dave said after what must have felt like an hour to him. To my left, Dave peered over his shoulder, back at Powder. Maybe he wants to eat with Powder while watching Tony, I thought.“I rather—”He stood up. “Make friends with Tony, and we make friends with Powder.”“Wait…” What? But already he was gone. Marching towards Tony.You can’t do that, Dave. Barging in on another classmate is one thing. In on the best player in the nation, hours prior to the biggest game of his career… How is this — the heat from my sandwich’s wrapper collected on my palm. How is this different from the countless others we’ve befriended over lunch? Conversations flow. And even if they stumble, we take the lead and make it light and warm.A mob of eyes tracked Dave as he neared, about to do something books can’t teach. And every single beating heart yearning to do what he was doing. Yet — not one of them free enough to do it.Suddenly on my feet, a jolt of curiosity tossed me racing onward. Dave, few tables in front of me, already had his arms outstretched, greeting the best basketball player in the nation.My character here isn’t thinking about how people like talking with them. There’s no time for thoughts like that. His friend is doing something unforgivable. It’s survival mode. He’s freaking out. And he has a sense of urgency to get to a solution. No time to wonder lust about people liking him. How can he save the situation before Dave does something drastic?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Grounding Concepts through Character: ask, what mind-state could have a conceptual thought like that.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/06/Grounding-Concepts-ask-what-mind-state-would-have-a-thought-like-that.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Grounding Concepts through Character: ask, what mind-state could have a conceptual thought like that." /><published>2020-12-06T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/12/06/Grounding-Concepts-ask-what-mind-state-would-have-a-thought-like-that</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/06/Grounding-Concepts-ask-what-mind-state-would-have-a-thought-like-that.html">&lt;p&gt;One of the constant challenges in writing fiction is hiding the concepts and ideas within the text. Over the last few manuscripts, I’ve had a few breakthroughs in my path to ground these concepts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last manuscript, my coach and I reviewed one of my scenes. At some point within the scene, I wanted my character to express that how he believes when he’s socializing in the lunch hall he learns more about his linguistics major than he does in any of the classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a point I want to make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the whole challenge is (1) when/how the character would think or say that organically, and (2) how to ensure the character sees it as organic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My coach had been talking it out, where this would fit in the scene, and I paid close attention to her thought process. Quickly she ruled out two moments of the scene because the emotion is too high. (noted) Then, she leaped to knowing it had to be the moment where he’s in a flashback talking with his girlfriend. Why? Because at that moment, his agenda is aligned with this logical thought. In that flashback he’s trying to convince his girlfriend that being in the lunch hall is a good thing. This idea completely aligns with his intentions in that moment. So he uses it as persuasion power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It goes back to what are the character’s motivations and why (what’s going on inside him that brought him to that). But here it goes further, what is his current mind-state? Does he have a sense of urgency? Is he anticipating something dramatic? Does he have time to review and survey? Once you ask these questions, it’s easy to see, okay, he would actually be in too heighten of a state to be thinking about something so conceptual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To answer #2: You can ensure the thought is organic by making sure the reader understands why they have it, what their internal state was before they had that thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grounding always comes back to the character, what’s going on internally moment to moment, both emotionally and psychologically — and why.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="mistakes&amp;fixes" /><summary type="html">One of the constant challenges in writing fiction is hiding the concepts and ideas within the text. Over the last few manuscripts, I’ve had a few breakthroughs in my path to ground these concepts.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A welcomed metaphor.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/05/A-welcomed-metaphor.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A welcomed metaphor." /><published>2020-12-05T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/12/05/A-welcomed-metaphor</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/05/A-welcomed-metaphor.html">&lt;p&gt;In my last scene, I had two metaphors that I want to note because both of them are good examples of two different types of metaphors (or similes) that work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Metaphor #1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All morning, I sit, spinning my pen, while my linguistics professors click through slides, side after slide lecturing about language and rhetoric without ever allowing me to exercise that muscle. &lt;strong&gt;It’s like an actor memorizing his lines without ever seeing how others respond to them being spoken.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first wrote this to be: It’s like a mathematician speaking of numbers without ever solving a problem. I thought that fit quite well, but it didn’t show who my character was. It’s a generic metaphor. So I dove into his past when he had been an actor. And this metaphor fits quite well because it expresses exactly what he’s trying to express and it’s visual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Metaphor #2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Repeatedly she peered back over her shoulder. Actually, her whole table seemed to spy towards the back corner. Suddenly this whole pocket felt quieter &lt;strong&gt;like we had just stepped into the library and the whole student body mulled over the same problem.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once my character notices her whole table focused on something, it instantly becomes clear that the whole pocket of the cafeteria is focused on something. In this scene that something is a someone, a famous basketball player at their school. To me, this is a feeling. It felt like walking into a library, where a group of students all studied all studied together; they are respecting the ambiance of the room, while still whispering back and forth about what to do. In the cafeteria, everyone whispers back and forth about how to act or how to say something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both of these metaphors served different purposes and both work by providing understanding and emotion that couldn’t be expressed any other way.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="mistakes&amp;fixes" /><summary type="html">In my last scene, I had two metaphors that I want to note because both of them are good examples of two different types of metaphors (or similes) that work.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">lowercase texting is fascinating</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/04/lowercase-texting-is-fascinating.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="lowercase texting is fascinating" /><published>2020-12-04T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/12/04/lowercase-texting-is-fascinating</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/04/lowercase-texting-is-fascinating.html">&lt;p&gt;i recently started talking with someone who only uses lowercase in her sentences, seemingly consciously fighting off auto-correct to keep itas such. at first, i didn’t even notice it, but quickly it became apparent. i did what i always do when i find something surprising, i googled it, and learned, many people do it as a way to make texting informal and not so rigid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i love thinking about how to use style to better communicate and connect. you can see this in my titles, most of all. often i play around with punction, writing in lowercase, and title lengths. but never did i think it could be applied to the message itself. here are two rules i must keep in mind going forward:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;rule #1: only break the rules after you’ve mastered the rules. not capitalizing and following grammar rules must purposeful. don’t break the rule to break it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;rule #2: Beware, the reader’s first instinct will be that you made an error, and that should be avoided at all costs. What you don’t want is to suddenly slow down your reader and take them out of your writing so “you. can. be. creative.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of writing I’ve always thought is to communicate clearly. And although that should &lt;del&gt;never&lt;/del&gt; rarely be sacrificed, the primary goal actually is to share experience and to evoke emotion. Sometimes to do that YOU NEED TO YELL AT THE READER. Other times, you just have to say something genuine, to my few friends who read my meanderings – I appreciate you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt; * * * &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. I’ve noticed with titles that I generally choose the style based on how the text looks. If all lowercase looks right, I go with that. If punctuation looks right, I go with it. After seeing this blog posted, I thought it was quite ugly and unappealing. So, I have a third rule:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;rule #3: Trust your eye!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="writingstyle" /><summary type="html">i recently started talking with someone who only uses lowercase in her sentences, seemingly consciously fighting off auto-correct to keep itas such. at first, i didn’t even notice it, but quickly it became apparent. i did what i always do when i find something surprising, i googled it, and learned, many people do it as a way to make texting informal and not so rigid.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What is a good editing session?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/03/What-is-a-good-editing-session.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is a good editing session?" /><published>2020-12-03T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/12/03/What-is-a-good-editing-session</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/03/What-is-a-good-editing-session.html">&lt;p&gt;Recently, I had a breakthrough while editing a scene. In this scene, two characters, Josh and Dave, strut into the university cafeteria looking for someone to eat with. They had seen a girl, Powder who both had liked for her white hair that made her look like the mystical-type you only see in the movies. Josh and Dave were waiting until someone left her table to slide in and start a conversation when at a neighboring table they spot Tony, the star basketball player in the nation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dave decides that he wants to eat with Tony in order to impress Powder, and takes off, without discussing it with Josh. Now Josh has a decision to follow Dave or to watch from afar. As I was reading my work, the emotion of this moment didn’t feel right and I knew it needed work. Previously this is what I had:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In front of me, the giant spooned fried rice out of a bowl built for composting. “Dude.” I nudged again.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“Tony,” Dave exclaimed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“It’s game-day, too.” I said.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“Let’s kill two birds with one stone.” He peered back to Powder and stood up. “Make friends with Tony, and we make friends with Powder.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“Wait…” But already he was gone.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;F@*k. You can’t just do that. Tony’s alone. Headphones on. He’s zoning, not to be distressed. And Dave proudly charging in. And now I’m sitting here twiddling my thumbs. Barging in on another classmate is one thing. In on the best player in the nation, hours prior to the biggest game of his career, I can’t just follow Dave into that. How is this different from the countless of others you’ve befriended over lunch? People like bantering with us. Conversations flow. And even when they stumble, we take the lead and make it light. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A mob of eyes tracked Dave as he neared, about to do something books can’t teach. And every single beating heart yearning to do what he was about to do. Yet — not one of them free enough to do it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Suddenly on my feet, a jolt of curiosity tossed me racing onward, this was our environment. Dave, few tables in front of me, already had his arms outstretched, greeting the nation’s best basketball player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While editing, I knew the structure was right, I just needed to figure out the emotion, so I began to hack the F@*k paragraph to pieces, knowing that is where the key reaction lies and knowing there’s a lot going on and needs to be ordered. Then it struck me. &lt;strong&gt;I never gave the reader time to understand why Dave taking off would evoke all of this in Josh.&lt;/strong&gt; Instead I had Dave take off, and only afterwards Josh explains why that’s a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going back and pausing, I asked when Josh sees Tony, what does he want and what does he expect? Quickly, it was clear that Josh never expects to go talk with Tony, and it would make his day to simply stay right there and eat close to Tony. He doesn’t need to talk to him to enjoy this lunch hour. There’s something invigorating about eating close to the best player in the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the edited layer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“It’s game-day, too.” I said, watching him bob, sitting alone, getting in the zone.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I began to unwrap my sandwich. Powder had left my mind. Today, I was eating with Tony, the best player in the nation. It was the same egg muffin I eat nearly every day, yet my first bite was one of the most savory I ever remember. Everything was just right, like at the theaters, reclined in a lazy boy while being served a hotdog, with Tommy Boy up on the big screen. Every few bites I spied towards the back corner where he still bobbed and excavated rice.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“Let’s kill two birds with one stone.” Dave said after what must have felt like an hour to him. To my left, Dave peered over his shoulder, back at Powder. Maybe he wants to eat with Powder while watching Tony, I thought.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“I rather—”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He stood up. “Make friends with Tony, and we make friends with Powder.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“Wait…” What? But already he was gone. Marching towards Tony.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can’t do that, Dave. Barging in on another classmate is one thing. In on the best player in the nation, hours prior to biggest game of his career… How is this — the heat from my sandwich’s wrapper collected on my palms. How is this different from the countless of others we’ve befriended over lunch? Conversation will flow. And even if it stumbles, we take the lead and make it light and warm.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A mob of eyes tracked Dave as he neared, about to do something books can’t teach. And every single beating heart yearning to do what he was doing. Yet — not one of them free enough to do it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Suddenly on my feet, a jolt of curiosity tossed me racing onward. Dave, few tables in front of me, already had his arms outstretched, greeting the best basketball player in the nation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now, when Dave just takes off, the reader understands Josh’s dilemma, and then when Josh arrives at his conclusion to go talk to Tony, not only are the stakes higher, but the excitement and emotions are higher. What’s more, I noticed by understanding those desires and expectations, it became so much easier to write the reaction at that moment of Dave leaving. What needed to be cut was so clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt; * * * &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a joyful breakthrough for me because I could clearly see how to get emotion on the page and I could see my progress right there in the reading experience.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="mistakes&amp;fixes" /><summary type="html">Recently, I had a breakthrough while editing a scene. In this scene, two characters, Josh and Dave, strut into the university cafeteria looking for someone to eat with. They had seen a girl, Powder who both had liked for her white hair that made her look like the mystical-type you only see in the movies. Josh and Dave were waiting until someone left her table to slide in and start a conversation when at a neighboring table they spot Tony, the star basketball player in the nation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Setting Expectations with simple insights into the character</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/02/Setting-Expectations-with-simple-insights-into-the-character.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Setting Expectations with simple insights into the character" /><published>2020-12-02T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/12/02/Setting-Expectations-with-simple-insights-into-the-character</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/02/Setting-Expectations-with-simple-insights-into-the-character.html">&lt;p&gt;Scenes are about pleasure transitions, which come from expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just worked on a scene where my character goes to talk to the best player in the nation. His initial expectation: “A simple, harmless good luck.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the scene goes on, he manages to make the player (Tony) smile. And that makes his day. (It’s MORE than expected.) But the scene isn’t over. Now he desires to leave, but his friend is going on and on, to the point that the player is getting annoyed. The tension is growing and now there’s a risk in my character losing that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And eventually, our protagonist, dying to get out of there, looks back at Tony: “Tony was no longer smiling, my stomach turned.” Still his friend goes on and goes until the player explodes. All is lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This interaction happens over a thousand words or so, but I find it interesting that this simple line, 5 words long, “a simple, harmless good luck,” set up the ebb and flow of pleasure/pain. If we, the reader, didn’t understand these expectations of the character, we wouldn’t understand why he wants to escape so desperately.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="writingmentalmodels" /><summary type="html">Scenes are about pleasure transitions, which come from expectations.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">One Plot from the Sandman Comics: a vortex, when our fictional stories become reality</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/01/One-plot-from-the-Sandman-comics-a-vortex-when-our-ficitional-stories-become-reality.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One Plot from the Sandman Comics: a vortex, when our fictional stories become reality" /><published>2020-12-01T02:23:30-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-01T02:23:30-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/12/01/One-plot-from-the-Sandman-comics-a-vortex-when-our-ficitional-stories-become-reality</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/01/One-plot-from-the-Sandman-comics-a-vortex-when-our-ficitional-stories-become-reality.html">&lt;p&gt;In book two, Morpheus, the lord of dreams, has a problem, a glitch in his matrix, what is called a vortex, a portal between the dream world and reality. Morpheus first learns of this when a few of the creatures escape his dream world, two monsters named Brute and Glob as well as one of the nightmares of the dream world, the Corinthian, a man with teeth instead of eyes, who feasts on the eyes of his prey. These monsters have escaped into reality because of the vortex which Morpheus sets out to close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We learn the vortex is an innocence girl, Rose, who is trying to find her way through life. Rose thinks everything is normal even when strange things start happening around her. Her dreams and the stories she knows are becoming reality. After moving into an apartment that looked just like the dollhouse from her grandma’s, she meets her neighbors, Ken and Barbie, and strange sisters who collect spiders. Then typically what she thinks, what’s going to happen before it happens, both negative and positive thoughts, happens as she thinks it. Dreams are becoming reality. So, if she fears someone’s going to find her in this alley, then someone appears and finds her. And then maybe she hopes she’s saved by some superhero and some superhero shows up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can Morpheus capture these escaped monsters and bring him back to the dream realm before they corrupt earth forever?  The whole series plays on this question of what is reality and what are dreams and is there actually a difference.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">In book two, Morpheus, the lord of dreams, has a problem, a glitch in his matrix, what is called a vortex, a portal between the dream world and reality. Morpheus first learns of this when a few of the creatures escape his dream world, two monsters named Brute and Glob as well as one of the nightmares of the dream world, the Corinthian, a man with teeth instead of eyes, who feasts on the eyes of his prey. These monsters have escaped into reality because of the vortex which Morpheus sets out to close.</summary></entry></feed>