<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-20T08:04:56-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Daily writings from Silence</title><subtitle>God grant me the serenity To accept the things I cannot change; Courage to change the things I can; And wisdom to know the difference.</subtitle><author><name>Silence</name></author><entry><title type="html">Manuscript Example: life purpose | before and after the realization</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/20/Real-example-before-and-after-life-purpose-realization.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Manuscript Example: life purpose | before and after the realization" /><published>2020-09-20T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-20T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/20/Real-example-before-and-after-life-purpose-realization</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/20/Real-example-before-and-after-life-purpose-realization.html">&lt;p&gt;Before I fall off the deep end, I want to include a concrete example. Here’s scene sketch I had submitted in a manuscript before I learned about a character’s life purpose. Afterwards, I’ll update it with this knew knowledge in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Scene idea: What if Em (female lead character) brings Josh (male lead character) to a painting class; at first Josh is hesitant to go because he paints to much like a robot and doesn’t want Em to see that. Nevertheless he goes. Unexpectedly the opposite happens. Too much of his insides end up on the canvas and he feels vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expanded on this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;He goes to the class and to start he’s rigid, drawing perfect lines. The teacher pacing around sees Josh, stops and asks if he will try an exercise. “Close your eyes,” he says. Imagine you’re back in first grade, painting. The teacher goes describing a visualization, then says open your eyes and just go. Josh puts the brush down, scoops up a blob of paint with his fingers and just goes. Feeling the paint slide between his fingers, he gets lost in the art, spending the next hour in a state of play. When they’re done, he and Em show each other. Em says something like omg, this might be the first time I truly understand you (or see inside you). [Not so literal but something along those lines.] Josh instantly feels vulnerable, and never does that again. Learns that playing like that without control is dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right there I stopped my work on this sketch. I thought, okay, this is a scene caused by his internal problem, the fear of emotions and feeling vulnerable, and he learns to protect himself. From now on he’ll be careful with creative work. And I thought, this is has an external cause, because Josh going forward no longer will take artistic risks. The scene-sketch felt complete. And I stopped there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, it’s clear to me this isn’t tethered to anything of importance in Josh’s life. It’s a one off, a scene that just floats away, never to be remembered again. A scene that I could forever forget about without consequences to Josh’s story. The story he sees from his deathbed is the exact same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to add consequences?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting with life purpose: let’s say, Josh has a life’s mission to become a polyglot, speaking 7 languages. Currently, he’s only working to earn money for the next trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And let’s say, recently him and Em started discussing to take their next three month trip. One of the worries that Em keeps bring up is about losing their jobs, since that happened after their first trip. She wants to ensure they make a responsible decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, this art scene happens. And Em sees Josh’s insides. And Josh believes that she’ll read into it that he’s a mess, and that he’s not in a good place to go on this trip. And later that night, they discuss travel again. Josh brings it up. Em says she doesn’t want to leave her job. Josh misreads her meaning, believes she won’t travel. He’s scared they won’t go. He feels like a mess. So, to not feel that way, he gets angry, he yells, he demands they go. He books his ticket in rage. Em leaves him. He goes alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, that has huge external cause/effect. That he certainally will see on his deathbed. And that resentment or that need to feel put together will carry through and affect more of his deicisons. That just doesn’t float away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt; * * * &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To arrive at the above, I actually sketched a doodle out to guide me. Imagining how this scene could affect Josh’s overarching desires in life — here’s the image I saw:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SilenceVosh/silencevosh.github.io/master/_posts/assets/images/ArtClass.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;image info&quot; title=&quot;Life's Purpose&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just something I’ve been as of late childishly playing around with.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="professionalwriter," /><category term="lifespurpose_series" /><summary type="html">Before I fall off the deep end, I want to include a concrete example. Here’s scene sketch I had submitted in a manuscript before I learned about a character’s life purpose. Afterwards, I’ll update it with this knew knowledge in mind.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Coaching: The Power of Deadlines</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/19/Coaching-The-Power-of-Deadlines.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coaching: The Power of Deadlines" /><published>2020-09-19T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-19T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/19/Coaching-The-Power-of-Deadlines</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/19/Coaching-The-Power-of-Deadlines.html">&lt;p&gt;Ever since I started working with a story coach, it has changed the way I manage my writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting back in February, each thrid week, she reviews and we discuss my recent progress on my current novel. Each third week, a deadline, a manuscript due. Forced out of necessity, I’ve designed a system to manage this, a system for processing coaching notes, for deciding what to work on, for managing what to work on (writing, research, digging up scene details), for keeping track of mistakes and learnings. A system for becoming a professional writer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember, after my first call, I had a dozen different things to work on. Completely lost what to start with. With no system, they all floating around my head, never allowing me to be immersed in the task at hand. In the end, I did the bare minimum on each. I was unsatisfied. And learned, if I’m unable to figure a system out, I’m just wasting my money…and what better motivator is there than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next week, I had another dozen things to work on. I spun my wheels some more. I created nothing with substance. Money wasted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chugged forward, learning manuscript by manuscript, how to do each slightly better. Until one day, enough spinning in place, enough unsatisfaction, and enough little tweaks, I suddenly had a system filled with value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would have been impossible without deadlines, I believe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Keep spinning, you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="professionalwriter" /><summary type="html">Ever since I started working with a story coach, it has changed the way I manage my writing.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Setting the Tone: Vikings</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/18/Setting-the-tone-Vikings.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Setting the Tone: Vikings" /><published>2020-09-18T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-18T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/18/Setting-the-tone-Vikings</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/18/Setting-the-tone-Vikings.html">&lt;p&gt;Another example of this. A great one: episode 2 of the show Vikings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few of the Vikings who we’ve been following and have grown to like arrive on an island of monks. I imagined them taking the island, robbing the gold and valuables, and going about their way. Suddenly, my favorite character begins to slice these innocent, arm-less monks into two. The slaughter begins. They massacre every single one of them. Then go on their merry way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
That’s a promise to us. This show will be about a bunch of savages. Get used to it or move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt; * * * &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A final note: pay close attention to the first couple of scenes in anything you watch, anything you read, and you will see these promises. In Indiana Jones, the movie opens with Harrison Ford running from a boulder. After they promise you this adventure, they cut to him in a college where the action slows down, so they can set up some details of the story, before the real adventure. And in Game of Thrones, the show opens with a scene showing the white walkers. We won’t see them again until the last 10 seconds of the season, showing their army approaching.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">Another example of this. A great one: episode 2 of the show Vikings.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jurassic Park: how does it get away with the midpoint change in tone?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/17/Jurassic-Park-how-does-it-get-away-with-the-midpoint-change-in-tone.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jurassic Park: how does it get away with the midpoint change in tone?" /><published>2020-09-17T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-17T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/17/Jurassic-Park-how-does-it-get-away-with-the-midpoint-change-in-tone</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/17/Jurassic-Park-how-does-it-get-away-with-the-midpoint-change-in-tone.html">&lt;p&gt;Where many movies and books go wrong is suddenly changing the tone and the emotions of the story. If you’re going along watching a rom-com and midway through the movie Scream-mask-guy shows up and kills the male protagonist in his sleep and now the female protagonist spends the rest of the movie fighting for her life, you’ve been lied to. At least it feels like it, so you walk out or watch something else. You never agreed to feel those emotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Jurassic Park, they promised horror from the very first scene. The movie opens with a raptor eating a construction worker. Then the danger of them is foreshadowed throughout. On top of that, everyone is asking morality questions, hinting at mother nature having her revenge. So when a T-Rex shreds the lawyer into two, we’re okay with it. We were emotionally prepared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Last night, I watched a movie that played out right on the border of emotional preparation. In ~Drive~, we’re watching a crime film, so we know there will be violence, but it isn’t until 60% into the movie do we watch a girl lose her head from a shotgun. I’m sure that surprised many and even caused some to turn it off.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">Where many movies and books go wrong is suddenly changing the tone and the emotions of the story. If you’re going along watching a rom-com and midway through the movie Scream-mask-guy shows up and kills the male protagonist in his sleep and now the female protagonist spends the rest of the movie fighting for her life, you’ve been lied to. At least it feels like it, so you walk out or watch something else. You never agreed to feel those emotions.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jurassic Park: midpoint genre (emotion) change</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/16/Jurassic-Park-midpoint-genre-(emotion)-change.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jurassic Park: midpoint genre (emotion) change" /><published>2020-09-16T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-16T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/16/Jurassic-Park-midpoint-genre-(emotion)-change</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/16/Jurassic-Park-midpoint-genre-(emotion)-change.html">&lt;p&gt;The first half of Jurassic Park is an idea story: what if we could bring back dinosaurs? As movie goers, we desire to explore the ramifications of that. Here are some of the beats we get to explore:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When Dr. Grant arrives, in awe, we see the dinosaurs resurrected. Dr. Grant begins to match his theories to their behavior, something he never in his wildest dreams thought would be possible.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next, we learn how it all was possible, how these dinosours were brought to life. Climaxed with being able to watch one in real time hatching out of an egg.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next, in horror, we watch a feeding; a raptor, in a blink, devouvers a cow.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Triggered by the fright, we begin to discuss the morality of having something that horrifyingly dangerous here.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lastly, we summarized all of this with a grand tour of the park.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a fun, carefree exploration. Never do we feel in danger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Half way through the movie, everything changes. The storm clouds slide in. Under the moon-light, the monsters are set free. Now we run. We run for our lives, verses something we can’t comprehend. And we spent the rest of the movie in fear and running, unable to do anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I like this pacing, as it gives two different distinct emotions. The first is exploring and awing. The second is anxiety and dread.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">The first half of Jurassic Park is an idea story: what if we could bring back dinosaurs? As movie goers, we desire to explore the ramifications of that. Here are some of the beats we get to explore:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">intuition: Confusion verse Questioning</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/15/intuition-confusing-verse-questioning.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="intuition: Confusion verse Questioning" /><published>2020-09-15T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-15T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/15/intuition-confusing-verse-questioning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/15/intuition-confusing-verse-questioning.html">&lt;p&gt;Let me pause. This series – I realized while writing this post – seemed to be unfocused, debating something incredibly abstract and likely pointless: how do I distinguish thoughts which confuse my direction in life and thoughts which wisely question the decision. So instead I want to slow down and make sure I understand my agenda with this series. The purpose is to understand how I can get in touch with my true desires, with how I feel and what I want, both moment to moment and with life’s big decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I started my blog, for example, I had many internal criticisms: care for the reader; write well; only post essays which have value; no one cares about what makes you laugh. Just laugh and stop thinking about it. Definitively, for the sake of god and all his children, don’t write a whole blog post about what makes you laugh. While these are healthy questions and thoughts, they blocked me from doing what I truly wanted…to blog every day. They caused confusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through this series, I want to figure out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What blocks me?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are the dangers, both with being blocked and being too free?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to distinguish these?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How does someone who’s rightly in touch with their intuition move throughout the world?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To jump the gun, my short answer to my agenda is to simply be in touch with what I want. What do I want in this moment? What do I want in my life? And ensuring I’m healthily in touch with those desires.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="humanlearnings," /><category term="intuition_series" /><summary type="html">Let me pause. This series – I realized while writing this post – seemed to be unfocused, debating something incredibly abstract and likely pointless: how do I distinguish thoughts which confuse my direction in life and thoughts which wisely question the decision. So instead I want to slow down and make sure I understand my agenda with this series. The purpose is to understand how I can get in touch with my true desires, with how I feel and what I want, both moment to moment and with life’s big decisions.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Origin memory, the root of life’s problems: Westworld’s Benerad</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/14/Origin-memory-the-root-of-life-problems-Westworlds-Benerad.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Origin memory, the root of life's problems: Westworld's Benerad" /><published>2020-09-14T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-14T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/14/Origin-memory-the-root-of-life-problems-Westworlds-Benerad</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/14/Origin-memory-the-root-of-life-problems-Westworlds-Benerad.html">&lt;p&gt;In the first season of Westworld, towards the end, one of the main characters, Benerad, finally confronts the past memory of his son dying. Throughout the whole season, this memory revisited him again and again, yet it was too painful to let fully play out. Every time it arose, he ran away. Until finally, he gets the strength he needs to face it and relive it. What happens is an incredible scene and an idea that I see a lot in stories and life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once he relives it – he breaks into the other side. Suddenly previous memories which he used to be blind to he can remember, memories that he didn’t know existed. The memory of his son dying was so overwhelming that he was unable to experience anything else. But he did what we must do, he faced the trauma, he relived it, accepted it instead of suppressing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We all have these blockages, these unconscious defensives. Often with people who care and are persistent, we can break through them. People who love us enough to make us uncomfortable when the time is right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my all-time favorite movie scenes is when therapist Sean (Robin Williams) does this, pushing deeper and deeper into Will Hunting’s defensives. “It’s not your fault.”
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZQht2yOX9Js&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZQht2yOX9Js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These types of blockages also extend beyond unconscious reactions, into deep layers within the patterns of the body which too we must breakthrough. In my own life, I’ve always had a poor relationship with my voice. It lacks power and wholeness. I mumble and eat my words. And most tragically, never have I sung karaoke for discomfort with shouting, singing, talking in a voice louder than a mouse’s whisper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once, in Vancouver, I witnessed a guy applaud another stranger from 100 yards away with a booming howl. I wanted that ability, but layers of my past block me from experiencing that. I must relive these stored emotions and fears and abuses to my body so that my voice can be free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only now, I’m starting to make true progress towards that, by playing around with my belly and my voice —- daily making all sorts of sounds, moans, sighs, screams, whimpers, releasing it all. Often I within my body I can feel these blockages. I feel these points of resistance, especially in my chest. And day after day, I uncomfortably face, feel, and release those. Soon, with persistence and presence, I will break into the other side, where I’ll feel a deeper layer of myself, layers of myself before these build up blockages, returning to child-like freedom. Heck, perhaps I’ll even sing a karaoke song.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="likestoriesofold" /><summary type="html">In the first season of Westworld, towards the end, one of the main characters, Benerad, finally confronts the past memory of his son dying. Throughout the whole season, this memory revisited him again and again, yet it was too painful to let fully play out. Every time it arose, he ran away. Until finally, he gets the strength he needs to face it and relive it. What happens is an incredible scene and an idea that I see a lot in stories and life.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">intuition: this blog</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/13/intuition-thisblog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="intuition: this blog" /><published>2020-09-13T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-13T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/13/intuition-thisblog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/13/intuition-thisblog.html">&lt;p&gt;For at least 4 years, I’ve wanted to start a blog. My good friend, who was the inspiration for this, blogged every day, more as a commitment to himself than as a blog. See, the word blog has so many meanings and rules and restrictions in my head. A blog should be united around a theme, I thought. It should be quality over quantity. Each post must contain a value for the reader and be well-written. All of those preventing me from starting. I needed to strip the meaning, strip that word from my mind, and think of it differently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friend calls his, his own little corner of the internet. I’m going to climb on his shoulders, and follow his lead. This isn’t a blog. It’s my little corner where I can post whatever I please.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Last night, I gathered with a few friends and we had a creative night. We brought art supplies and it turned into a pure improv night. One guy mentioned he designed an alter-ego so that when he wasn’t working he could free himself up to relax and slow down. We flowed with it, that night creating an alter ego for each of us. We just played with them, weaving these together about how we each knew each other and about our dark secrets, about our dark selves. It was the most freeing night I’ve had in years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And today I realized, I’m writing under a pen name to free myself up. From behind this mask, I can choose my rules. And I can post parts of me, which might otherwise be suppressed by my critical voice. It frees me up to play and to follow the muse, the muse of my intuition. I drop my self so that my little corner expresses all of myself.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="professionalwriter," /><category term="intuition_series" /><summary type="html">For at least 4 years, I’ve wanted to start a blog. My good friend, who was the inspiration for this, blogged every day, more as a commitment to himself than as a blog. See, the word blog has so many meanings and rules and restrictions in my head. A blog should be united around a theme, I thought. It should be quality over quantity. Each post must contain a value for the reader and be well-written. All of those preventing me from starting. I needed to strip the meaning, strip that word from my mind, and think of it differently.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Eyes Wide Shut: the mask scene.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/12/Eyes-Wide-Shut-Blinks-the-mask-scene.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Eyes Wide Shut: the mask scene." /><published>2020-09-12T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-12T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/12/Eyes-Wide-Shut-Blinks-the-mask-scene</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/12/Eyes-Wide-Shut-Blinks-the-mask-scene.html">&lt;p&gt;One of the most haunting scenes I’ve seen is the famous mask party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom Cruise finds out about a secret sex society from his friend who plays music at these parties blindfolded. He begs his friend for the details of the party, and after learning about it, he goes. Arriving late, he’s let in because he knew the secret password. He enters this grand castle, surrounded by the world’s elite. Everything is fine and easy to join, as he’s wandering the halls with beautiful women and people having sex all over. Everyone with a mask. He’s doing it. He’s here, no one batted an eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a while, he’s asked to go to a certain room. As he enters this is awaiting him:
&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SilenceVosh/silencevosh.github.io/master/_posts/assets/images/EyesWideShut.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image info&quot; title=&quot;Horror, as you walk into the room knowing you're exposed&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A huge pleasure exchange, going from the highest high, to the lowest low. He’s questioned and quizzed and exposed. Told to get naked in front of everyone. He’s completely helpless. These elites could make him disappear with the snap of their fingers. It’s horrifying.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblind" /><summary type="html">One of the most haunting scenes I’ve seen is the famous mask party.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What a movie trailer promises: What We Do in the Shadows</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/11/What-a-movie-trailer-promises-What-we-do-in-the-shadows.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What a movie trailer promises: What We Do in the Shadows" /><published>2020-09-11T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-11T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/11/What%20a-movie-trailer-promises-What-we-do-in-the-shadows</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/11/What-a-movie-trailer-promises-What-we-do-in-the-shadows.html">&lt;p&gt;I watched this trailer without any idea what it was about. A smile sat on my face the whole time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a mockamentary, like the office, but filming what vampiers do when they aren’t hunting and sucking blood. The first clip was two vampiers arguing about doing the dishes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trailer takes so many elements of vampiers which we consider outer worldly and makes them mundane and normal, like one of the vampier’s showing off his torture camber to the film crew. Also the the flip side, taking the mundane and making it outer worldly, like watching these people with special powers struggle to get into a club. This is why I couldn’t stop smiling, every clip I was watching these two opposites clash together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for storyline…I’m not entirely sure. I think it’s an idea story, where we are watching because it’s fun to think about what it would be like to be a vampier living in the real world, and we’re exploring the ramifications of that, in a comedical way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will watch this soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">I watched this trailer without any idea what it was about. A smile sat on my face the whole time.</summary></entry></feed>