<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-11-01T08:08:12-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Daily writings from Silence</title><subtitle>God grant me the serenity To accept the things I cannot change; Courage to change the things I can; And wisdom to know the difference.</subtitle><author><name>Silence</name></author><entry><title type="html">intuition | what is a corrupted intuition</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/01/intuition-what-is-a-corrupted-intuition.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="intuition | what is a corrupted intuition" /><published>2020-11-01T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-11-01T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/01/intuition-what-is-a-corrupted-intuition</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/01/intuition-what-is-a-corrupted-intuition.html">&lt;p&gt;Back in &lt;a href=&quot;https://silencevosh.github.io/2020/09/26/intuition-What-are-the-extremes.html&quot;&gt;intuition: What are the extremes&lt;/a&gt; I talked about how Osho was the pinnacle of someone following his desires —- and solely his desires. When you study his work on intuition, you can start to understand his intentions and understand how he got to a place where he was misbehaving sexually and spending money without real purpose. His goal I believe was to strip away any and all cultural rules, and follow whatever desire is at the center. He wrote a book on intuition that delves into these cultural layers, and which he pinpoints as the corruption of intuition. Let’s examine those to get a look at how we can be more in touch with our true desires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, what does he mean when he talks about intuition? He says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Intuition is a totally different kind of phenomenon from reason. Reason argues; reason uses a process to reach a conclusion. Intuition jumps—it is a quantum leap. It knows no process. It simply reaches to the conclusion without any process. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Many mathematicians have been able to do any kind of mathematical problem without going into its process. Their functioning was intuitive. You just say the problem, and before you have even said it, the conclusion will come. There has not been a time gap at all. You were saying it and the moment you finished, or even before you finished, the conclusion has come. Mathematicians have always been puzzled by these freak phenomena. These people—how do they do it? If a mathematician was to do this problem, it might take three hours or two hours or one hour. Even a computer will take at least a few minutes to do it, but these people don’t take a single moment. You say it, and instantly … So in mathematics, intuition is now a recognized fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it’s a force that can make leaps without thought interfearing. If you are getting ready to go to dinner with your wife and she asks where do you want to eat? Your intuitive answer makes the leap to your real desire, let’s say Mexican food, without rationally knowing why. You don’t have to weigh the pros and cons, and you don’t have to reason a decision. You just know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A corrupted intuition, then, would be a blockage to that force. Osho laid these blockages; there are five of them that I will go through one at a time, starting with physical blockages.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="humanlearnings" /><summary type="html">Back in intuition: What are the extremes I talked about how Osho was the pinnacle of someone following his desires —- and solely his desires. When you study his work on intuition, you can start to understand his intentions and understand how he got to a place where he was misbehaving sexually and spending money without real purpose. His goal I believe was to strip away any and all cultural rules, and follow whatever desire is at the center. He wrote a book on intuition that delves into these cultural layers, and which he pinpoints as the corruption of intuition. Let’s examine those to get a look at how we can be more in touch with our true desires.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Skeletons in the Closet</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/31/Skeletons-in-the-Closet.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Skeletons in the Closet" /><published>2020-10-31T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-10-31T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/10/31/Skeletons%20in%20the%20Closet</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/31/Skeletons-in-the-Closet.html">&lt;p&gt;The juice of a story manifests when a character’s fatal flaw begins to cause skeletons in his closet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two ways this happens: Secrets and Lies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secrets and lies create false realities. Lying is the obvious form of betrayal. But even keeping secrets can create betrayal. For example, in my story, Josh who’s in a struggling relationship, asks his girlfriend, Em, to come on an adventure with him. He advertises the adventure by saying, “Hey, Em, look, this trip, this spark of excitement, could be what we need to save our relationship.” His secret, however, is he needs Em to travel with him because in order to enter the community that he wants to visit, he’s required to have a female partner. So in reality, he couldn’t go without Em. So under this pretense, they will travel together and spend months there, until eventually, Em finds out his intentions weren’t to save the relationship but for his work. Spooked, she learns she’s been living a lie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By exploring secrets and lies, we can discover where realities begin to diverge and can push that even more until we break one of our characters, spook them so much that they are unable to recover. Because it’s only from that space that we learn to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Halloween.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="mistakes&amp;fixes" /><summary type="html">The juice of a story manifests when a character’s fatal flaw begins to cause skeletons in his closet.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MadMen, Season3: Peggy’s Character Arc, a prediction</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/30/MadMen-Season3-Peggy's-Character-Arc-a-prediction.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MadMen, Season3: Peggy's Character Arc, a prediction" /><published>2020-10-30T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-10-30T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/10/30/MadMen-Season3-Peggy's-Character-Arc-a-prediction</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/30/MadMen-Season3-Peggy's-Character-Arc-a-prediction.html">&lt;p&gt;In just two seasons, Peggy has been on a rollercoaster. Introduced as the new office secretary, quickly she fell into the trap of a New York office building in the 60s and was seduced by one of the male workers. She had his child in private, meanwhile, continue to show up and work every day. Working hard, she wanted to be more than a secretary, and eventually earned her place at the creative table, surrounded by all advertising men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beginning season 3, she’s different from the rest of the office floor. She can’t fit in with the men, no matter what she does, and now she’s the only woman with an office of her own. Throughout the first couple of episodes, we notice her watching the other women and how they sweet-talk visiting clients. Afterwards, she goes home and acts pretty in the mirroring, singing a Marilyn Monroe “Happy Birthday, Mr. President” type performance. Later, she’s in a bar, surrounded by women who seem to naturally attract the eyes of a man. She awkwardly gets a man to buy her a drink, and while conversing with him, she feels his immaturity. She feels different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She knows this difference, and although she’s proud of it, wants to cover it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my prediction this season: we will watch her first succumb to this desire to be one of the girls, to regress into the role of a ditzy secretary, then by the end, after making many mistakes, maybe getting pregnant a second time, she’ll overcome it and embody that she’s different and that’s a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">In just two seasons, Peggy has been on a rollercoaster. Introduced as the new office secretary, quickly she fell into the trap of a New York office building in the 60s and was seduced by one of the male workers. She had his child in private, meanwhile, continue to show up and work every day. Working hard, she wanted to be more than a secretary, and eventually earned her place at the creative table, surrounded by all advertising men.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What attracts us to new people, new friends, new conversations, new lovers?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/29/What-attracts-us-to-new-people-new-friends-new-conversations-new-lovers.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What attracts us to new people, new friends, new conversations, new lovers?" /><published>2020-10-29T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-10-29T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/10/29/What%20attracts-us-to-new-people-new-friends-new-conversations-new-lovers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/29/What-attracts-us-to-new-people-new-friends-new-conversations-new-lovers.html">&lt;p&gt;Motivations. How does this other person fit within our motivations. Yes, it’s a selfish, self-centered way of looking at it. That’s the way of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, it’s not, oh you’re sexy, I’m motivated to sleep with you so I will. And sadly, it’s not, oh hey Stephan King, I’m a big fan and am motivated to be your mentee, so let’s begin the lessons. Rather it’s a mutual meshing of motivations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my current work, my character, Josh, just met the soon to be the love of his life, Em. On the first date, where did their motivations mesh? Travel. Em has wanted to travel outside the country for years, but has always been too scared to take the leap. Josh speaks five languages, yet hasn’t stepped foot out of Illinois. Em starts telling herself a story: just think of all the countries we could fluently travel through. Josh, too, imagines experiencing the world, driven by love. So they meet for a 2nd date. And a 3rd. 4th, 5th…soon little Joshs and Ems are born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This often happens in unhealthy ways. For example, be it sexual or just a friend, let’s say one partner gives too much because fulfilling someone’s else’s desires fulfills their own. While the other leaches on givers and takes and takes and takes. Even though these two have motivations that mesh, it’s an unhealthy relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all this in mind, it’s an illuminating experiment to examine your relationships, examining the motivations on both sides. What ones are healthy? What ones are one-sided? Where can you give more? How can you cherish your shared motivation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Personally, I need to give more to my father. He’s always there for me, anytime I need him. Can I say the same?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="likestoriesofold" /><summary type="html">Motivations. How does this other person fit within our motivations. Yes, it’s a selfish, self-centered way of looking at it. That’s the way of the world.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Character Blink: Mike, adding layers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/28/Character-Blink-Mike-including-layers.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Character Blink: Mike, adding layers" /><published>2020-10-28T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-10-28T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/10/28/Character-Blink-Mike-including-layers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/28/Character-Blink-Mike-including-layers.html">&lt;p&gt;One character in Better Call Saul is Mike, an no bullshit, and always short with people, old man. In the show’s prequel, Breaking Bad, Mike is a pro’s pro assassin. Better Call Saul starts from the beginning, and we watch his evolution from a freshly retired police office into that man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the show, Mike is central to two types of scenes. (1) he gets a job where he must outwit another in order to get it done, and the violent nature of these jobs escalate, getting him deeper and deeper into the game. Or (2) he plays with his granddaughter and we see his softer side, we see the reason he’s doing it all, making the money to support her, since her father, (his son), has died.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s those promises repeated over and over that we grow to expect when Mike’s face on the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently one moment didn’t fit that pattern, a super refreshing moment. During his daily diner visit, he has like three lines of banter with the waitress, and a slight smile afterwards. It’s this tiny interaction that breaks that pattern of doing a job, seeing the granddaughter, doing a job, seeing his granddaughter. Suddenly — once broken — he because more real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is this? Because of the layers my coach always talks about, I believe. Humans are complex characters with hierarchies of agendas and emotions. For the most part, we only see Mike the character’s agenda. When in reality Mike the human has many different agendas. So this little flash of him potentially interested in the waitress gave him another layer of humanity. He does have a voice whispering in his head about women. I can relate to that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my recent manuscript, my coach highlighted when I did this well, when I gave my character extra layers. My character just got put on probation. I was exploring how that event had affected him mentally and emotionally. I wrote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;He also has his father’s voice replying in his head. You’re the first in our family to attend	college. Make the most of it. Josh thinks I can’t even tell them that I’m on probation. He	would be knocking at my door in 2 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s these simple layers that add complexity and force us to get closer to the characters.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">One character in Better Call Saul is Mike, an no bullshit, and always short with people, old man. In the show’s prequel, Breaking Bad, Mike is a pro’s pro assassin. Better Call Saul starts from the beginning, and we watch his evolution from a freshly retired police office into that man.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“Everything gets its meaning compared to something else.”</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/27/Everything-gets-its-meaning-compared-to-something-else.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="&quot;Everything gets its meaning compared to something else.&quot;
" /><published>2020-10-27T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-10-27T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/10/27/Everything-gets-its-meaning-compared-to-something-else</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/27/Everything-gets-its-meaning-compared-to-something-else.html">&lt;p&gt;This is a helpful model from my coach. Nothing is deemed meaningful unless it has something else to be compared with. For example, if you came from a planet filled with dinosaurs, an elephant would look small.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This is important in the early stages of character creation when you’re trying to figure out where is meaning and pain for them, where are triggers. One mistake I made early on was knowing my character Devon was going to see boyish games like GI-Joes as immature, I jumped to that conclusion, without figuring out why. At one point these toys brought joy into his life, so why do they now bring sourness or the feeling of immaturity?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, if we traveled across the galaxy to our alien’s dinosaur world and then returned to earth, an elephant would seem like a poodle. So what experience gave Devon new meaning into these toys?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s when I realized, oh he had been hanging out with a neighbor girl, Lucy, and most likely something happened around that; perhaps maybe Lucy’s baby brother is annoying them with toys, and Lucy yells at him. And new those figurines take on new meaning. To be close to Lucy means to grow away from those toys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now when Devon enters the playroom, that new meaning is infused in his actions, and I understand why, I understand what it’s compared to.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="humanlearnings" /><summary type="html">This is a helpful model from my coach. Nothing is deemed meaningful unless it has something else to be compared with. For example, if you came from a planet filled with dinosaurs, an elephant would look small.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Curving Dialogue</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/26/Curving-Dialogue.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Curving Dialogue" /><published>2020-10-26T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-10-26T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/10/26/Curving-Dialogue</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/26/Curving-Dialogue.html">&lt;p&gt;Years ago, I studied communication a lot. One of the biggest takeaways that still continually revisits me is indirect communication or speaking A to C as it was called in improv. “A” is the first thing you think of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example of a response in A:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    ”Would you like a brownie,” speaker1 asks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    ”No, thank you though,”speaker2 responds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A deeper response B:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    ”No, I’m on a diet.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even deeper C:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    ”No, I’m trying to fit into my dad-jeans from the 80s.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why does speaking in C create a deeper connection? Because it gives information in who you are as a person, into your past, into your present, and into your desires, rather than an objective, robotic no. When you make that leap, you share more of who you are and you gain a unique voice, all in roughly the same amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example from James Scott Bell, in a book on writing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Let’s say you were writing The Godfather […], and Michael Corleone has come to Las Vegas to tell the older, more established Moe Green that the Corleone family is buying out his interest in the casinos. &lt;br /&gt; 
Moe Green is outraged. What does he say in response? At first, you might write it like this: &lt;br /&gt;
   I’m Moe Green! I was running this place when you were in high school!” &lt;br /&gt;
Not striking enough. So you tweak it: &lt;br /&gt;
   ”I’m Moe Green! I made my bones when you were in high school!” &lt;br /&gt;
A little better. But we can do more with it. In the movie the line is: &lt;br /&gt;
   ”I’m Moe Green! I made my bones when you were going out with cheerleaders!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to put this into practice?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask WHY. Why am I saying no? Why am I am a diet? Each time, you get closer to your values, and you can share those in conversation. Why does this work? “Why?” worries less about the words and more about their meaning, so quickly your brain thinks of other words to express the same meaning…which is step 2.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What other associated thoughts come to mind? Brownies, sugar. Sugar, energetic. “No, thank you, I’m already hopped up on coffee.”
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Another related question: what does this mean? what are they saying? What is Moe Green implying when he says, “when you were in high school!” That he’s been the boss, making money here, while Michael was in high school diddling around.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, I think like a sloth moves, and I still react to questions with the first thing I think of. Perhaps, this is why I love writing so much. With my characters, I don’t need to jump A to C in an instant. I can take my time and ask questions, with each question, getting closer to the truth of what makes them a human being. Then, days later, I can hear my character give his response in an instant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt; * * * &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Original ideas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improv: the Art of Comedy. (A to C rule.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dazzling dialogue, Scott Bell. (curving dialogue, going deeper and deeper)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some “youtube pickup artist”. (indirect communication, how women speak naturally)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="humanlearnings" /><summary type="html">Years ago, I studied communication a lot. One of the biggest takeaways that still continually revisits me is indirect communication or speaking A to C as it was called in improv. “A” is the first thing you think of.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Searching for misbelief: mistaking a rash action with the creation of a misbelief</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/25/Searching-for-misbelief-mistaking-a-rash-action-with-the-creation-of-a-misbelief.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Searching for misbelief: mistaking a rash action with the creation of a misbelief" /><published>2020-10-25T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-10-25T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/10/25/Searching%20for-misbelief-mistaking-a-rash-action-with-the-creation-of-a-misbelief</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/25/Searching-for-misbelief-mistaking-a-rash-action-with-the-creation-of-a-misbelief.html">&lt;p&gt;To start my book, back in February, I began by identifying my character’s misbelief that would take over his life. This would be the belief that ripples out into everything he does, and by page would have a death grip on his desires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A mistake I had made when searching for this was mistaking a rash action with the creation of a misbelief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I had wanted my character to come out to this moment with a belief about his parents and their irrational beliefs in the church. I thought what if his parents donate all their money to the church, so much so that he can’t even buy new clothes for school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My coach quickly pointed out, donating money isn’t a deep change in misbeliefs, even if they donate all the money and cause him and his family to be homeless. That’s a big event. But that’s simply a strong belief by his parents and them backing it up. Nothing about his worldview changed besides his parent’s belief in the church was stronger than he thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, we want him to question everything that came before, including what he believed about his parent’s belief. Cliche extreme example: he’s known his parents have had a strong belief in the church because they are always defending people of the church in court and helping the community. But the court papers came out and they were defending the children pedophiles of the church. Now that would force a belief that could, likely would take over his life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key is to focus on recontextualization, that moment where nothing that came before is ever the same, where you’re suddenly tossed into chaos and forced to question everything before you, even question those people you held most dear to you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="mistakes&amp;fixes" /><summary type="html">To start my book, back in February, I began by identifying my character’s misbelief that would take over his life. This would be the belief that ripples out into everything he does, and by page would have a death grip on his desires.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My notes on Pan’s Labyrinth</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/24/My-notes-on-Pans-Labyrinth.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My notes on Pan's Labyrinth" /><published>2020-10-24T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-10-24T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/10/24/My-notes-on-Pans-Labyrinth</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/24/My-notes-on-Pans-Labyrinth.html">&lt;p&gt;This forever will be one of my favorites. I love magical realism movies, movies that mix reality with fantasy, with psychological elements, questioning the line between fantasy and reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The movie is about a little girl who, after moving in with her suppressive stepfather, is visited by fairies, and told that she has a journey to undertake. Will she become a fairy tale princess or will her stepfather, a captain of a nazi troop, force her to stop her childish games and adventures?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;note-1-why-are-we-watching&quot;&gt;Note #1: Why are we watching?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our wish fulfillment –&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wanting to go on Ofelia’s next exploration, her next journey in a fairy tale.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wanting to see the next blend of reality and fantasy, through Ofelia’s eyes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wanting the evil, dictator captain to lose the war. Wanting to see the maid and the doctor overthrow the captain.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yet the captain is a great character. And we watch, wanting to see his next ruthlessness or meticulous behavior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;note-2-what-emotions-are-driving-the-story-forward&quot;&gt;Note #2: What emotions are driving the story forward?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We see the story through two major points of views —
First, through Ofelia’s eyes —-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A feeling of wonder when mentally explore the fantasy worlds. (during Ofelia’s journeys)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It’s not the emotion of adventure. That is a very different emotion than this mental exploration. Adventure is more about watching a character do something physically challenging. Rather, with Ofelia it’s a curious, childish, playful exploration.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drama is constant, as Ofelia says her step-dad is “not my father,” and she ruins a lot of materialistic things, such as brand new shoes that her mother gifted, in order to explore her fantasy world. Also drama around her doing weird “witch-craft” like, after receiving orders for a Faun, she puts a rooted plant in a bowl of milk, under the pregnant mother’s bed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, through eyes of all verse the captain, the Time Keeper —-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thriller (mental hide and seek): the doctor and maid sneak around, helping out the allies. It’s a feeling of thriller because if they make one mistake and the captain finds out — that’s that.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Little adventure: Can we defeat the captain? Can the rebels win the war?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(Even when it’s just the Time Keeper on screen by himself, we experience it like an outsider because we dislike him. Note: one way to make a viewer more compassionate towards a character, if that’s what you would want, is to show a scene where he’s taking care of his sick mother or having a mental breakdown in the shower.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;note-3-plot-and-character&quot;&gt;Note #3: plot and character&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overarching plot: a quest, which causes a lot of drama with reality.
Subplot: war plot (captain verse allies), told with the tone of psychological, thriller, and adventure.
Character arc: reality verse fantasy. Every scene with Ofelia confronts her problem that she wants to live in fantasy but in reality, she unable to do that. She learns in the end: her brother’s life in this world is worth more than being the princess in a fantasy world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;note-4-mice-elements&quot;&gt;Note #4: MICE elements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more technical note. MICE brackets are the opening and closing of story questions. The easiest version of this is the mystery: who did it? This is “I” in MICE, standing for inquiry. A question is raised and we want until that question is answered. “M” is milieu, the character enters a new land and we wonder how they will escape or we wait for them to do something so that they can go home. “C” is character. A character is unsatisfied with some aspect of life and we watch until their inner struggle has gone away, either by overcoming that aspect or by accepting it. And “E” is event, such as a giant meteor is blazing towards the earth, how will we stop it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;character&amp;gt; “he’s not my father” Will Ofelia admit that he is her father? (4 min 30 sec)
&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;milieu&amp;gt; She meets her step-father. He aggressively teaches her that soldiers shake with their right hand, not a dainty left hand. Will she escape this nazi-driven household? (6min 42 sec)
&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;event&amp;gt; although it started before the story, we’re introduced to the war here. Will the rebels overthrow the captain? (16min 5 sec)
&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;inquiry&amp;gt; Can I become a princess? Ofelia sees a real fairy who asks her to follow to Pan’s Labyrinth. (18min 5 sec)
&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;/event&amp;gt; Allies win.
&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;/inquiry&amp;gt; Ofelia says no to Pan.
&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;/milieu&amp;gt; She makes the decision to take the baby and runs away, never to return.
&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;/character&amp;gt; She decides her brother’s life in this world is worth more than being the princess in a fantasy world.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="mynotesblink" /><summary type="html">This forever will be one of my favorites. I love magical realism movies, movies that mix reality with fantasy, with psychological elements, questioning the line between fantasy and reality.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to write humans, not robots: personifying agendas</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/23/How-to-write-humans-not-robots-personifying-agendas.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to write humans, not robots: personifying agendas" /><published>2020-10-23T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-10-23T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/10/23/How-to-write-humans-not-robots-personifying-agendas</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/23/How-to-write-humans-not-robots-personifying-agendas.html">&lt;p&gt;Back in March, I struggled over a scene mainly because I didn’t find the pain, and I didn’t go deeper into what those painful emotions would cause someone to feel. In this scene, the very first scene I went deeply into, one of my character’s, Devon, walked on stage wanting to play baseball, rather than doing what his friend wanted to stay inside and play with dolls. And I stopped digging into his agenda right there. Since Devon wasn’t my protagonist, I felt like that was enough for me to write the scene. But I learned, by uncovering Devon’s deeper agenda even though he wasn’t my protagnosit, it made the scene so much deeper, so many more human emotions invovled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how my coach went deeper, how she described — on the fly — Devon’s mindset walking onto the stage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;He now spent all this time with Lucy [his first girlfriend]. She’s gone for the summer. And he’s lonely. And he wants to talk about her. He wants to feel close to her. And what makes him feel worthy of her, is the baseball stuff. So he wants to play baseball because that’s what Lucy likes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She targeted the pain, and through that lens asked why does he want to play baseball. His agenda walking on stage becomes so much thicker and more human. There are layers to it. He’s not just a robot with the single desire to play and have fun and he can achieve that through baseball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So a reminder: agendas are a crucial area to pause and look for deeper layers, layers of emotion and of pain.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="mistakes&amp;fixes" /><summary type="html">Back in March, I struggled over a scene mainly because I didn’t find the pain, and I didn’t go deeper into what those painful emotions would cause someone to feel. In this scene, the very first scene I went deeply into, one of my character’s, Devon, walked on stage wanting to play baseball, rather than doing what his friend wanted to stay inside and play with dolls. And I stopped digging into his agenda right there. Since Devon wasn’t my protagonist, I felt like that was enough for me to write the scene. But I learned, by uncovering Devon’s deeper agenda even though he wasn’t my protagnosit, it made the scene so much deeper, so many more human emotions invovled.</summary></entry></feed>