<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-04T12:03:05-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Daily writings from Silence</title><subtitle>God grant me the serenity To accept the things I cannot change; Courage to change the things I can; And wisdom to know the difference.</subtitle><author><name>Silence</name></author><entry><title type="html">Conflicting Moral Decisions #2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/04/Conflicting-Moral-Decisions2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Conflicting Moral Decisions #2" /><published>2020-09-04T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-04T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/04/Conflicting-Moral-Decisions2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/04/Conflicting-Moral-Decisions2.html">&lt;p&gt;In Breaking Bad, a scene that forever scarred me is based in a moral conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walter, who transforming into a major meth dealer, visits his much younger partner’s house. Jessie is like a son to Walter. Recently though he has been struggling with heroin addiction, and Walter feels responsible for his happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jessie fell back into addiction after meeting a neighbor girl. Quickly, she found out about a pile of money that Walter has of Jessie’s which with good intentions he was protecting for Jessie until he’s well. She loses control and makes all these crazy threats about ratting him out and calling the cops and such unless Walter hands over the money. Walter painfully does so, but that night, he returns to set things right and to work it out with Jessie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When he arrives, Jessie and she are out of this world, high on heroin, and he’s forced to break in to make sure everything is okay. Inside the house, the neighbor-girl laying on her back starts to OD. Standing over her, she starts to puke right before his eyes. He has the decision. Be human and save her life-risking being caught. Or let her die in front of him potentially saving Jessie from further drug abuse and certainly saving him from the trouble of what she knows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He watches her choke on her puke…for a deadful minute. God, it’s horrifying.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">In Breaking Bad, a scene that forever scarred me is based in a moral conflict.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lack of control over our future.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/03/Lack-of-control-over-our-future.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lack of control over our future." /><published>2020-09-03T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-03T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/03/Lack-of-control-over-our-future</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/03/Lack-of-control-over-our-future.html">&lt;p&gt;Because it is…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Jonas makes the decision to kill the love of his life it’s a lack of control over his own actions. That’s absolutely horrifying. DARK constantly presents this theme: everything is determined, no matter how much you believe you have free will. And even no matter how it feels and appears you have free will, it’s still all determined. At first that appears to be tragic and sad. Experiencing this, however, experiencing this contradiction of feeling like you’re acting with free will yet this is already determined been liberating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The predicted events of the show always happen as they should, reenforcing everything is determined. Yet moment to moment, we all truly are trying to do what we believe is best. We all are acting with free will. All we can do is what we think is right, then get out of our way. No character is ever doing something that they don’t believe is the right action. They act guided by invisible forces, and whatever happens, happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of us, in our forever misguided ways, is trying. Even the worst among us believe they are doing the right thing. And although it’s completely misguided, sad, horrifying, frustrating, they too are trying their best. We are all in this together.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink," /><category term="humanlearnings" /><summary type="html">Because it is…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Conflicting Moral Decisions</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/02/Conflicting-Moral-Decisions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Conflicting Moral Decisions" /><published>2020-09-02T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-02T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/02/Conflicting-Moral-Decisions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/02/Conflicting-Moral-Decisions.html">&lt;p&gt;The show DARK on Netflix constantly forces characters into conflicting moral decisions, where they must choose between two conflicting paths in life, each path stressing a different moral decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One scene in particular comes to mind. Jonas the protagonist, who seeks to save the world by destroying time travel, re-unites with the love of his life, after many pains and struggles. A few hugs later, his time-traveling future-self walks into the house and tells him, that she must die right now in order to save the world at the hand of young-Jonas. Now he’s presented with two paths and a decision. Young-Jonas still swears he would never do that, even having learned if he doesn’t – no one survives. Although he believes he won’t, we know he will. And we approach that moment with dread, not wanting to believe it’s true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This difference between who we think we are (someone who would choose love over everything) and who we are (someone who will quickly abandon and destroy that love if it means survival) is horrifying. It feels like a lack of control over our own decisions — because it is…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">The show DARK on Netflix constantly forces characters into conflicting moral decisions, where they must choose between two conflicting paths in life, each path stressing a different moral decision.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Studying Scenes on the Fly</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/01/Studying-scenes-on-the-fly.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Studying Scenes on the Fly" /><published>2020-09-01T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-01T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/01/Studying-scenes-on-the-fly</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/01/Studying-scenes-on-the-fly.html">&lt;p&gt;Recently I crossed a threshold in my understanding of how scenes work, an understanding of scene underpinnings. After hundreds of hours, I’ve figured this out so deeply that I can, while watching a show or a movie,  in real-time see the building blocks of these scenes on the fly. This is a superpower, since every scene I consume, I gain associations for scenes in my own story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bolded are the core question I’m able to ask on the fly (for each character in the scene). I included “Going Deeper” as that’s the next threshold to triumphant, being able to answer those questions on the fly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do they want in this scene?&lt;/strong&gt; (Going deeper: how is what they want a stepping stone towards their overarching purpose?)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the first truly unexpected thing? What is the first thing they must choose how they will respond to?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did they choose to respond?&lt;/strong&gt; (Deeper: in what way is that choice meaningful? Who they wish to be verse who they need to be? How it aligned with their overarching yearnings, both internally and externally?)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the consequences of this choice?&lt;/strong&gt; What relationships have changed or how has this character’s world changed? (These are the consequences within the scene. Also we can figure out the consequences in the overall scheme of the story… Deeper: how has this scene affected their overarching purpose? Because of the consequences, how has the pursuit of their goal changed? Have their possibilities in pursuit of their goal shrunken or grown?)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did they learn from this scene?&lt;/strong&gt; (Deeper: why does what they learned matter internally?)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What will they do now?&lt;/strong&gt; (Deeper: what new direction did do they now believe is best in pursuit of their goal?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Okay, too many questions, not enough examples. Future Post: I’ll break down one of my favorite scenes from Game of Thrones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To Note: this list will be ever-updating for me. This is my first draft, expect a second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt; * * * &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Original ideas: I credit Lisa Cron’s Story Genius for the foundation of these questions. She, in that book, presents the idea of a story scene card. It is truly genius. The whole book is.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="writingmentalmodels" /><summary type="html">Recently I crossed a threshold in my understanding of how scenes work, an understanding of scene underpinnings. After hundreds of hours, I’ve figured this out so deeply that I can, while watching a show or a movie, in real-time see the building blocks of these scenes on the fly. This is a superpower, since every scene I consume, I gain associations for scenes in my own story.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">intuition: how to use it as a writer | intro</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/31/intuition-how-to-use-it-as-a-writer-intro.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="intuition: how to use it as a writer | intro" /><published>2020-08-31T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-31T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/31/intuition-how-to-use-it-as-a-writer-intro</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/31/intuition-how-to-use-it-as-a-writer-intro.html">&lt;p&gt;Lately, out of necessity, I’ve thought a lot about intuition. For a little over a year, I have been in a relationship with a beautiful woman. And even though I love her deep and dearly, doubts and thoughts constantly cloud my relationship to her. So, to combat these, I’m working to get more in touch with intuition, and quite frankly wondering what the hell it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems to me many people have different ideas of what it is. For my sake, it’s simply knowing how I should live without constantly being clouded by doubts, confusion, and the devil’s advocate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The devil’s advocate… “One who argues against a cause or position, not as a committed opponent but simply for the sake of argument or to determine the validity of the cause or position.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example, I was talking to my therapist about a recent situation of ours. I kept stumbling over my words and the conversation. I would start to say something and quickly stumble. My therapist says, “You have it. For a brief moment you have it, then confusion arises and blocks your thinking.” This really struck me. My first thought is my intuition, I thought, then all of these counter thoughts and counterpoints pile on – causing me to not trust that first spark of genius. They’re all playing devil’s advocate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a book called the 5 personality patterns, there’s one type of human expression who lives his life controlled by this confusion. It’s called the rigid pattern. The rigid pattern develops often from a rule-strict society or rule-strict parenting. A child grows up being out of touch with how he feels and what he wants because he’s constantly told rules, don’t run in the house, don’t scream, boys don’t cry. And what develops is a strong ego, so that every time the boy feels sadness, his ego, the devil’s advocate, jumps into action, “Boys do NOT cry,” and the boy becomes confused and conflicted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what was happening to me. Let’s say, my thought is I want to buy her roses, I want to get closer to her again. Quickly, my devil confuses me by chiming about how she hasn’t done anything like that for me recently. And on and on, it goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
So my practice of getting in touch with my intuition has started. Once I can recognize this, I can live how I want, without confusion and doubts hindering my freedom. This all has sparked many ideas of how to use intuition in writing. (Being in touch with it is similar to the flow state, I’m thinking.) In this series, I hope to discover and define what exactly intuition is, enabling me to leverage it throughout my life, and to discover how this all applies to my writing.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="writingmentalmodels," /><category term="humanlearnings," /><category term="theMuse" /><summary type="html">Lately, out of necessity, I’ve thought a lot about intuition. For a little over a year, I have been in a relationship with a beautiful woman. And even though I love her deep and dearly, doubts and thoughts constantly cloud my relationship to her. So, to combat these, I’m working to get more in touch with intuition, and quite frankly wondering what the hell it is.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Emotional Register: A Wedding Speech</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/30/Emotional-register-Wedding-speech.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Emotional Register: A Wedding Speech" /><published>2020-08-30T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-30T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/30/Emotional-register-Wedding-speech</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/30/Emotional-register-Wedding-speech.html">&lt;p&gt;On a podcast, Elizabeth Gilbert talked about an emotional register, and I’ve found this idea, not only a fascinating insight into humans, but quite illuminating for fiction writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s her telling the story (original audio included at the bottom):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My friend Kevin once attended a wedding where he heard the world’s most inappropriate wedding toast. The toast began inauspiciously enough. The best man stood up during the meal, clinked his knife against the crystal, and the other guests all quieted down.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“I was thinking on the airplane ride here about what I was going to say today about Danny and Joyce,” the best man began. “And all I could think at first was what a happy day today is.” Good enough start. But then this speech took an interesting turn. “And I realized that what I really wanted to talk about this afternoon is jury duty.”
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“Now, I don’t know how many of you have ever served on a jury,” he went on. “But it’s a fascinating process. I was just on a jury last year for the first time in my life, and I learned a lot about myself and about the legal system. It was a pretty serious case, too. It was actually a murder trial. It was very tragic. It was this old man who got killed. Very sad. He was getting money out of an ATM in the middle of the day and some gang kids came up and robbed him and shot him right in the face.”
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;By now, many of the wedding guests were lowering their champagne glasses gently back down to the table. “It was a cut-and-dry case, really,” he went on. “There were plenty of witnesses, and the forensic evidence pointed straight to one kid as the shooter. The kid was definitely guilty. But here’s the thing. It was actually a capital offense. And my jury had to decide whether or not to give this kid the death penalty.”
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“Now, I don’t know if any of you have ever had to decide whether somebody should live or die, but it’s emotionally intense. We all knew the kid was guilty, but the death penalty is nothing to take lightly. In the end, though, we decided yes, this kid needs to die. And we sent him to his death.”
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The tent was silent. The bride, ashen. The best man took a moment to compose himself and concluded, “That was probably the worst day of my life. And I got to thinking about it on the plane because that day was nothing like today, which is a happy day. A really happy day. So here’s to Danny and Joyce.” Thus concluded the toast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She pondered this story for years, and what she concluded…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I’ve decided that I get it. I’ve heard it said before that the human psyche cannot always tell the difference between good events and bad events. All we can feel is the tremor of the earth. Which is what happened to our best man, I believe. He was so overcome by happiness for his friend and he was so out of touch with his emotions that he couldn’t express that happiness appropriately. All he could do was remember the last time he had felt so moved by something, and so he tried to express that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When he thought of his best friend getting married, he had no relatable thoughts. The only thing his mind presented him was compared in emotional weight. So he tried to express that emotion in the only way he could, by telling about that fateful day when he decided to put a fellow human to death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt; * * * &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The audio:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://shortcut.thisamericanlife.org/#/clipping/234/2884?_k=acgwsc&quot;&gt;Clipping from This American Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="humanlearnings," /><category term="writingconcepts" /><summary type="html">On a podcast, Elizabeth Gilbert talked about an emotional register, and I’ve found this idea, not only a fascinating insight into humans, but quite illuminating for fiction writing.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stories controlling what your mind doesn’t see: Science-Fiction and Fantasy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/29/Stories-controlling-what-your-mind-doesnt-see-Science-fiction-and-fantasy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stories controlling what your mind doesn't see: Science-Fiction and Fantasy" /><published>2020-08-29T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-29T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/29/Stories-controlling-what-your-mind-doesnt-see-Science-fiction-and-fantasy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/29/Stories-controlling-what-your-mind-doesnt-see-Science-fiction-and-fantasy.html">&lt;p&gt;Another captivating way stories convey information, without our minds turning on and questioning it, is by the setting or the genre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say you want to make a point about race issues in America. So you base your movie in America with all the surrounding sides of the issue – Black America, the KKK, the White Americas who don’t speak up, the White Americas who do, all the other cultures and movements, and so on. This clearly will be a movie about that issue. That is fine and great, if that’s your purpose, if you want the audience throughout the film to consciously think about the issue and ask questions around it. If, on the other hand, you want the issue still floating around but hidden in the background, you – as a god – can shift the setting into a new world; let’s call it Pandora. Here, even though the audience experiences the same conflicts, the same issues, they’re not consciously thinking about them, they’re immersed in the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue is hiding in plain sight, unseen by the conscious mind.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="writingmentalmodels" /><summary type="html">Another captivating way stories convey information, without our minds turning on and questioning it, is by the setting or the genre.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Where University Misguides Writers: what matters.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/28/Where-University-misguides-writers-what-matters.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Where University Misguides Writers: what matters." /><published>2020-08-28T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-28T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/28/Where-University-misguides-writers-what-matters</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/28/Where-University-misguides-writers-what-matters.html">&lt;p&gt;To control what the audience doesn’t see, you first and foremost must be in tune with your story, specifically what truly matters in your story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In weird science, they knew the science didn’t matter. They wanted to make a playful, idea story, about a couple dorky high school kids who created a real-life barbie doll slave…who they instantly decided to shower with. Those goofy moments mattered and drove the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Universities (and the majority of non-fiction books on writing) stress things that in the overall picture don’t matter, like lyrical writing or rules of world-building or story structure. Once you start giving importance to those before the story, the audience can feel it. If you’re trying to find the perfect word that completes some poetic pattern instead of finding the perfect word for the story, the audience will know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week’s theme showed up over and over: study, learn, then forget it all, and get hell out of the story’s way.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="writingmentalmodels" /><summary type="html">To control what the audience doesn’t see, you first and foremost must be in tune with your story, specifically what truly matters in your story.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Weird Science</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/27/Weird-Science.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Weird Science" /><published>2020-08-27T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-27T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/27/Weird-Science</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/27/Weird-Science.html">&lt;p&gt;When I browsed trailers, this movie kept showing up because of a 30th-year anniversary. It’s an eighties cult movie with an over the top comical premise which carries us through the movie, laughing and shaking our heads the whole way. What if two teenage boys had a beautiful model as a slave?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create this model, the boys use “science”, computer programming with awful graphics, to bring a doll to life. The movie uses this fake science so overtly, we don’t care. They aren’t trying to pass it off as real, and because of that our minds just accept it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just good communication by the producers. They understood if they walk that line between real and not, the audience will question. But if they show, they themselves don’t care about the science, then a healthy mind naturally understands what they are communicating, and completely neglects it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This is a fundamental skill of a writer: controlling what the audience doesn’t see, controlling what their brain neglects, naturally.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">When I browsed trailers, this movie kept showing up because of a 30th-year anniversary. It’s an eighties cult movie with an over the top comical premise which carries us through the movie, laughing and shaking our heads the whole way. What if two teenage boys had a beautiful model as a slave?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Foreign Films</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/26/Foreign-Films.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Foreign Films" /><published>2020-08-26T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-26T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/26/Foreign-Films</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/26/Foreign-Films.html">&lt;p&gt;Talking with an Argentine movie lover, he told me, he refuses to watch a movie that’s dubbed into Spanish. “It’s loses all its flavor,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing up on Disney and Hollywood films, I wasn’t introduced to foreign films until ‘Crouching Tiger, Hidden Dragon’ became famous, and even then as an egotistical high schooler I wondered why in the world would someone watch a movie that wasn’t in English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, as someone who is constantly controlled by words and thoughts, love picturing how the knowledge isn’t actually in those words. To understand the depth of what’s going on, you don’t even need the words. You just need to experience the tones, the expressions, the emotions of the film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
To taste a new flavor of life, I will try an experiment: Put on a Chinese film, without subtitles, and feel my way through the movie.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="humanlearnings," /><category term="theMuse" /><summary type="html">Talking with an Argentine movie lover, he told me, he refuses to watch a movie that’s dubbed into Spanish. “It’s loses all its flavor,” he said.</summary></entry></feed>