<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-10-27T08:02:50-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Daily writings from Silence</title><subtitle>God grant me the serenity To accept the things I cannot change; Courage to change the things I can; And wisdom to know the difference.</subtitle><author><name>Silence</name></author><entry><title type="html">Curving Dialogue</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/26/Everything-gets-its-meaning-compared-to-something-else.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Curving Dialogue" /><published>2020-10-26T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-10-26T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/10/26/Everything-gets-its-meaning-compared-to-something-else</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/26/Everything-gets-its-meaning-compared-to-something-else.html">&lt;p&gt;Years ago, I studied communication a lot. One of the biggest takeaways that still continually revisits me is indirect communication or speaking A to C as it was called in improv. “A” is the first thing you think of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example of a response in A:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    ”Would you like a brownie,” speaker1 asks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    ”No, thank you though,”speaker2 responds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A deeper response B:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    ”No, I’m on a diet.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even deeper C:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    ”No, I’m trying to fit into my dad-jeans from the 80s.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why does speaking in C create a deeper connection? Because it gives information in who you are as a person, into your past, into your present, and into your desires, rather than an objective, robotic no. When you make that leap, you share more of who you are and you gain a unique voice, all in roughly the same amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example from James Scott Bell, in a book on writing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Let’s say you were writing The Godfather […], and Michael Corleone has come to Las Vegas to tell the older, more established Moe Green that the Corleone family is buying out his interest in the casinos. &lt;br /&gt; 
Moe Green is outraged. What does he say in response? At first, you might write it like this: &lt;br /&gt;
   I’m Moe Green! I was running this place when you were in high school!” &lt;br /&gt;
Not striking enough. So you tweak it: &lt;br /&gt;
   ”I’m Moe Green! I made my bones when you were in high school!” &lt;br /&gt;
A little better. But we can do more with it. In the movie the line is: &lt;br /&gt;
   ”I’m Moe Green! I made my bones when you were going out with cheerleaders!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to put this into practice?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask WHY. Why am I saying no? Why am I am a diet? Each time, you get closer to your values, and you can share those in conversation. Why does this work? “Why?” worries less about the words and more about their meaning, so quickly your brain thinks of other words to express the same meaning…which is step 2.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What other associated thoughts come to mind? Brownies, sugar. Sugar, energetic. “No, thank you, I’m already hopped up on coffee.”
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Another related question: what does this mean? what are they saying? What is Moe Green implying when he says, “when you were in high school!” That he’s been the boss, making money here, while Michael was in high school diddling around.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, I think like a sloth moves, and I still react to questions with the first thing I think of. Perhaps, this is why I love writing so much. With my characters, I don’t need to jump A to C in an instant. I can take my time and ask questions, with each question, getting closer to the truth of what makes them a human being. Then, days later, I can hear my character give his response in an instant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt; * * * &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Original ideas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improv: the Art of Comedy. (A to C rule.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dazzling dialogue, Scott Bell. (curving dialogue, going deeper and deeper)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some “youtube pickup artist”. (indirect communication, how women speak naturally)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="humanlearnings" /><summary type="html">Years ago, I studied communication a lot. One of the biggest takeaways that still continually revisits me is indirect communication or speaking A to C as it was called in improv. “A” is the first thing you think of.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Curving Dialogue</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/26/Curving-Dialogue.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Curving Dialogue" /><published>2020-10-26T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-10-26T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/10/26/Curving-Dialogue</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/26/Curving-Dialogue.html">&lt;p&gt;Years ago, I studied communication a lot. One of the biggest takeaways that still continually revisits me is indirect communication or speaking A to C as it was called in improv. “A” is the first thing you think of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example of a response in A:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    ”Would you like a brownie,” speaker1 asks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    ”No, thank you though,”speaker2 responds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A deeper response B:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    ”No, I’m on a diet.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even deeper C:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    ”No, I’m trying to fit into my dad-jeans from the 80s.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why does speaking in C create a deeper connection? Because it gives information in who you are as a person, into your past, into your present, and into your desires, rather than an objective, robotic no. When you make that leap, you share more of who you are and you gain a unique voice, all in roughly the same amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example from James Scott Bell, in a book on writing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Let’s say you were writing The Godfather […], and Michael Corleone has come to Las Vegas to tell the older, more established Moe Green that the Corleone family is buying out his interest in the casinos. &lt;br /&gt; 
Moe Green is outraged. What does he say in response? At first, you might write it like this: &lt;br /&gt;
   I’m Moe Green! I was running this place when you were in high school!” &lt;br /&gt;
Not striking enough. So you tweak it: &lt;br /&gt;
   ”I’m Moe Green! I made my bones when you were in high school!” &lt;br /&gt;
A little better. But we can do more with it. In the movie the line is: &lt;br /&gt;
   ”I’m Moe Green! I made my bones when you were going out with cheerleaders!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to put this into practice?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask WHY. Why am I saying no? Why am I am a diet? Each time, you get closer to your values, and you can share those in conversation. Why does this work? “Why?” worries less about the words and more about their meaning, so quickly your brain thinks of other words to express the same meaning…which is step 2.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What other associated thoughts come to mind? Brownies, sugar. Sugar, energetic. “No, thank you, I’m already hopped up on coffee.”
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Another related question: what does this mean? what are they saying? What is Moe Green implying when he says, “when you were in high school!” That he’s been the boss, making money here, while Michael was in high school diddling around.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, I think like a sloth moves, and I still react to questions with the first thing I think of. Perhaps, this is why I love writing so much. With my characters, I don’t need to jump A to C in an instant. I can take my time and ask questions, with each question, getting closer to the truth of what makes them a human being. Then, days later, I can hear my character give his response in an instant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt; * * * &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Original ideas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improv: the Art of Comedy. (A to C rule.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dazzling dialogue, Scott Bell. (curving dialogue, going deeper and deeper)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some “youtube pickup artist”. (indirect communication, how women speak naturally)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="humanlearnings" /><summary type="html">Years ago, I studied communication a lot. One of the biggest takeaways that still continually revisits me is indirect communication or speaking A to C as it was called in improv. “A” is the first thing you think of.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Searching for misbelief: mistaking a rash action with the creation of a misbelief</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/25/Searching-for-misbelief-mistaking-a-rash-action-with-the-creation-of-a-misbelief.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Searching for misbelief: mistaking a rash action with the creation of a misbelief" /><published>2020-10-25T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-10-25T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/10/25/Searching%20for-misbelief-mistaking-a-rash-action-with-the-creation-of-a-misbelief</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/25/Searching-for-misbelief-mistaking-a-rash-action-with-the-creation-of-a-misbelief.html">&lt;p&gt;To start my book, back in February, I began by identifying my character’s misbelief that would take over his life. This would be the belief that ripples out into everything he does, and by page would have a death grip on his desires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A mistake I had made when searching for this was mistaking a rash action with the creation of a misbelief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I had wanted my character to come out to this moment with a belief about his parents and their irrational beliefs in the church. I thought what if his parents donate all their money to the church, so much so that he can’t even buy new clothes for school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My coach quickly pointed out, donating money isn’t a deep change in misbeliefs, even if they donate all the money and cause him and his family to be homeless. That’s a big event. But that’s simply a strong belief by his parents and them backing it up. Nothing about his worldview changed besides his parent’s belief in the church was stronger than he thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, we want him to question everything that came before, including what he believed about his parent’s belief. Cliche extreme example: he’s known his parents have had a strong belief in the church because they are always defending people of the church in court and helping the community. But the court papers came out and they were defending the children pedophiles of the church. Now that would force a belief that could, likely would take over his life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key is to focus on recontextualization, that moment where nothing that came before is ever the same, where you’re suddenly tossed into chaos and forced to question everything before you, even question those people you held most dear to you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="mistakes&amp;fixes" /><summary type="html">To start my book, back in February, I began by identifying my character’s misbelief that would take over his life. This would be the belief that ripples out into everything he does, and by page would have a death grip on his desires.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My notes on Pan’s Labyrinth</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/24/My-notes-on-Pans-Labyrinth.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My notes on Pan's Labyrinth" /><published>2020-10-24T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-10-24T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/10/24/My-notes-on-Pans-Labyrinth</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/24/My-notes-on-Pans-Labyrinth.html">&lt;p&gt;This forever will be one of my favorites. I love magical realism movies, movies that mix reality with fantasy, with psychological elements, questioning the line between fantasy and reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The movie is about a little girl who, after moving in with her suppressive stepfather, is visited by fairies, and told that she has a journey to undertake. Will she become a fairy tale princess or will her stepfather, a captain of a nazi troop, force her to stop her childish games and adventures?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;note-1-why-are-we-watching&quot;&gt;Note #1: Why are we watching?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our wish fulfillment –&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wanting to go on Ofelia’s next exploration, her next journey in a fairy tale.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wanting to see the next blend of reality and fantasy, through Ofelia’s eyes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wanting the evil, dictator captain to lose the war. Wanting to see the maid and the doctor overthrow the captain.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yet the captain is a great character. And we watch, wanting to see his next ruthlessness or meticulous behavior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;note-2-what-emotions-are-driving-the-story-forward&quot;&gt;Note #2: What emotions are driving the story forward?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We see the story through two major points of views —
First, through Ofelia’s eyes —-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A feeling of wonder when mentally explore the fantasy worlds. (during Ofelia’s journeys)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It’s not the emotion of adventure. That is a very different emotion than this mental exploration. Adventure is more about watching a character do something physically challenging. Rather, with Ofelia it’s a curious, childish, playful exploration.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drama is constant, as Ofelia says her step-dad is “not my father,” and she ruins a lot of materialistic things, such as brand new shoes that her mother gifted, in order to explore her fantasy world. Also drama around her doing weird “witch-craft” like, after receiving orders for a Faun, she puts a rooted plant in a bowl of milk, under the pregnant mother’s bed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, through eyes of all verse the captain, the Time Keeper —-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thriller (mental hide and seek): the doctor and maid sneak around, helping out the allies. It’s a feeling of thriller because if they make one mistake and the captain finds out — that’s that.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Little adventure: Can we defeat the captain? Can the rebels win the war?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(Even when it’s just the Time Keeper on screen by himself, we experience it like an outsider because we dislike him. Note: one way to make a viewer more compassionate towards a character, if that’s what you would want, is to show a scene where he’s taking care of his sick mother or having a mental breakdown in the shower.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;note-3-plot-and-character&quot;&gt;Note #3: plot and character&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overarching plot: a quest, which causes a lot of drama with reality.
Subplot: war plot (captain verse allies), told with the tone of psychological, thriller, and adventure.
Character arc: reality verse fantasy. Every scene with Ofelia confronts her problem that she wants to live in fantasy but in reality, she unable to do that. She learns in the end: her brother’s life in this world is worth more than being the princess in a fantasy world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;note-4-mice-elements&quot;&gt;Note #4: MICE elements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more technical note. MICE brackets are the opening and closing of story questions. The easiest version of this is the mystery: who did it? This is “I” in MICE, standing for inquiry. A question is raised and we want until that question is answered. “M” is milieu, the character enters a new land and we wonder how they will escape or we wait for them to do something so that they can go home. “C” is character. A character is unsatisfied with some aspect of life and we watch until their inner struggle has gone away, either by overcoming that aspect or by accepting it. And “E” is event, such as a giant meteor is blazing towards the earth, how will we stop it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;character&amp;gt; “he’s not my father” Will Ofelia admit that he is her father? (4 min 30 sec)
&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;milieu&amp;gt; She meets her step-father. He aggressively teaches her that soldiers shake with their right hand, not a dainty left hand. Will she escape this nazi-driven household? (6min 42 sec)
&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;event&amp;gt; although it started before the story, we’re introduced to the war here. Will the rebels overthrow the captain? (16min 5 sec)
&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;inquiry&amp;gt; Can I become a princess? Ofelia sees a real fairy who asks her to follow to Pan’s Labyrinth. (18min 5 sec)
&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;/event&amp;gt; Allies win.
&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;/inquiry&amp;gt; Ofelia says no to Pan.
&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;/milieu&amp;gt; She makes the decision to take the baby and runs away, never to return.
&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;/character&amp;gt; She decides her brother’s life in this world is worth more than being the princess in a fantasy world.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="mynotesblink" /><summary type="html">This forever will be one of my favorites. I love magical realism movies, movies that mix reality with fantasy, with psychological elements, questioning the line between fantasy and reality.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to write humans, not robots: personifying agendas</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/23/How-to-write-humans-not-robots-personifying-agendas.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to write humans, not robots: personifying agendas" /><published>2020-10-23T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-10-23T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/10/23/How-to-write-humans-not-robots-personifying-agendas</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/23/How-to-write-humans-not-robots-personifying-agendas.html">&lt;p&gt;Back in March, I struggled over a scene mainly because I didn’t find the pain, and I didn’t go deeper into what those painful emotions would cause someone to feel. In this scene, the very first scene I went deeply into, one of my character’s, Devon, walked on stage wanting to play baseball, rather than doing what his friend wanted to stay inside and play with dolls. And I stopped digging into his agenda right there. Since Devon wasn’t my protagonist, I felt like that was enough for me to write the scene. But I learned, by uncovering Devon’s deeper agenda even though he wasn’t my protagnosit, it made the scene so much deeper, so many more human emotions invovled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how my coach went deeper, how she described — on the fly — Devon’s mindset walking onto the stage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;He now spent all this time with Lucy [his first girlfriend]. She’s gone for the summer. And he’s lonely. And he wants to talk about her. He wants to feel close to her. And what makes him feel worthy of her, is the baseball stuff. So he wants to play baseball because that’s what Lucy likes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She targeted the pain, and through that lens asked why does he want to play baseball. His agenda walking on stage becomes so much thicker and more human. There are layers to it. He’s not just a robot with the single desire to play and have fun and he can achieve that through baseball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So a reminder: agendas are a crucial area to pause and look for deeper layers, layers of emotion and of pain.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="mistakes&amp;fixes" /><summary type="html">Back in March, I struggled over a scene mainly because I didn’t find the pain, and I didn’t go deeper into what those painful emotions would cause someone to feel. In this scene, the very first scene I went deeply into, one of my character’s, Devon, walked on stage wanting to play baseball, rather than doing what his friend wanted to stay inside and play with dolls. And I stopped digging into his agenda right there. Since Devon wasn’t my protagonist, I felt like that was enough for me to write the scene. But I learned, by uncovering Devon’s deeper agenda even though he wasn’t my protagnosit, it made the scene so much deeper, so many more human emotions invovled.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How my coach thinks. Why?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/22/How-my-coach-thinks-Why.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How my coach thinks. Why?" /><published>2020-10-22T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-10-22T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/10/22/How-my-coach-thinks-Why</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/22/How-my-coach-thinks-Why.html">&lt;p&gt;She asks why relentlessly. Relentlessly. It’s quite inspiring to listen to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often she brings up a situation where I didn’t ask why, where I could have gone deeper into a charcater’s past or concrete intentions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our call yesterday, we talked about a scene that I had written, where two college boys go talk to the star basketball player even though the player has headphones on and it’s his game. The rest of the cafeteria watches the player out of the corner of their eye, but knows better not to talk to him. She asked, why? For me this was because it’s a game for these boys togo and meet people and socialize. That’s too generic for her. Too generic for humans. She gave the idea of perhaps there’s a girl next to the player, who one of these boys wants to impress. Now, the why is concrete and visual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She will do ask this why at times when I wouldn’t have ever thought to ask it. Months ago, we were discussing a hypnosis scene. She stressed for a few minutes why is the college even having this hypnosis in the first place. What are their intentions? Did the students wonder why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, I had thought, that’s just what many colleges and high schools do in the midwest. And after asking the question, I thought the event planner likely would think, okay we need some form of entertainment. What did the students enjoy last year and the years before? Okay, let’s do that. But that’s not deep enough for my coach. She’s looking for a deeper motivation like, what do they want the students to take away from this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems best to error on the side of understand and concreteness. So, I can’t stress enough, ask why relentlessly.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="writingmentalmodels" /><summary type="html">She asks why relentlessly. Relentlessly. It’s quite inspiring to listen to.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Game of Thrones, a mix of emotions</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/21/Game-of-Thrones-a-mix-of-emotions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Game of Thrones, a mix of emotions" /><published>2020-10-21T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-10-21T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/10/21/Game-of-Thrones-a-mix-of-emotions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/21/Game-of-Thrones-a-mix-of-emotions.html">&lt;p&gt;While watching anything, the emotions we feel are dependent on the character POV. What huge casts of characters have the advantage of is making us experience all kinds of emotions, depending on which character we are relating with. Here are a few examples from season1:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jon Snow, one verse the group. We watch him try to earn his spot, while he’s constantly singled out because of his last name. We wait until he either joins, escapes, or destroys the group who opposes him, and when that moment happens it’s so satisfying.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arya, drama. We’re introduced to her as she fires an arrow straight past her brother’s head who just had been struggling to hit the target, and she marks a bullseye. Arya’s desire to do boy-things causes drama all throughout her family.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Daenerys, horror. She’s powerless to anything for the first half of the story. Controlled by her psychopathic brother, who he “would let a tribe of savages rape her if that means he gains the crown”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And on and on, the series goes, with its 52 main characters. An emotion for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">While watching anything, the emotions we feel are dependent on the character POV. What huge casts of characters have the advantage of is making us experience all kinds of emotions, depending on which character we are relating with. Here are a few examples from season1:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jurassic Park: perfect character arc</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/20/Jurassic-Park-perfect-character-arc.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jurassic Park: perfect character arc" /><published>2020-10-20T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-10-20T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/10/20/Jurassic-Park-perfect-character-arc</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/20/Jurassic-Park-perfect-character-arc.html">&lt;p&gt;Something this movie does very well is to subtly give our protagonist character change. Often, when we think of character change we think of these big sweeping changes. But it doesn’t have to be big to have an effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first episode of Brooklyn 99 has always stuck with me for this reason. Jake, a goof-ball cop, refuses to follow the orders of a new captain to wear a tie. He’s more comfortable without. By the end of the episode, after learning it’s about the team and a uniform, he states he’s now a tie-guy. So simple, but we see him become a new person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Novels have more time for a big change. Perhaps movies tend to fail in adoption because they don’t have enough time to make change possible. Game of Thrones Season 8 failed in this way. In the first 7 seasons, we watched the mother of dragons rise to power. Throughout her rise, her heart was always with the people, cared for the people. Then, in the second to last episode, she just suddenly flipped, and became evil as ever, burning a million people alive. It wasn’t believable. The writer knew, okay, last season, the mother of dragons needs to turn dark, and they crammed 3-4 seasons of character change into one. And the game of throne fans turned dark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Jurassic Park, Dr. Grant is introduced as someone who doesn’t like kids. Later on, he’s forced into taking care of two kids as they fight for their lives. Throughout that struggle, he gets to the end, wanting new kids of his own. He evolves.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">Something this movie does very well is to subtly give our protagonist character change. Often, when we think of character change we think of these big sweeping changes. But it doesn’t have to be big to have an effect.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The High Note blink review</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/19/The-High-Note-blink-review.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The High Note blink review" /><published>2020-10-19T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-10-19T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/10/19/The-High-Note-blink-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/19/The-High-Note-blink-review.html">&lt;p&gt;I surprisingly enjoyed the movie ‘The High Note’, just as I surprisingly enjoyed ‘A Star is Born’. I must be a sucker for watching talented musicians, especially singers. I get to experience some major wish-fulfillment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching a great musician, especially a humbly talented one like both of those movies have, fulfills some deep yearning of mine. A voice with power. A voice not hiding anything. And someone who stands comfortably in the spotlight. All while being there for the music and not the fame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only spotlight I have experienced in my life is the invisible one that I follows me around public, the one that I cower away from day after day. There’s probably a correlation here. Just once before it’s my time, I should grab the karaoke mic and voluntarily, stepping out of my invisible one, into the real one, to learn neither of them matter.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">I surprisingly enjoyed the movie ‘The High Note’, just as I surprisingly enjoyed ‘A Star is Born’. I must be a sucker for watching talented musicians, especially singers. I get to experience some major wish-fulfillment.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What a movie trailer promises: Trolls World Tour</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/18/What-a-movie-trailer-promises-Trolls-World-Tour.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What a movie trailer promises: Trolls World Tour" /><published>2020-10-18T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-10-18T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/10/18/What-a-movie-trailer-promises-Trolls-World-Tour</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/18/What-a-movie-trailer-promises-Trolls-World-Tour.html">&lt;p&gt;By changing the tone of the story, you can take the same emotional experiences and make them lighter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, like in &lt;a href=&quot;https://silencevosh.github.io/2020/08/21/Gods-of-Egypt:-Jordan-Peterson.html&quot;&gt;Gods of Egypt&lt;/a&gt;, many of the emotions evoked are from the plot to save the world. Poppy, the main character, sets out to make sure the rock and rollers don’t get all 6 strings because when they do, they will destroy all music that isn’t rock. That’s death to Trolls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though we are still watching a lot of anxious moments where the rock and rollers just about destroy the world, it’s fun and light-hearted.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">By changing the tone of the story, you can take the same emotional experiences and make them lighter.</summary></entry></feed>