<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-10T08:44:32-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Daily writings from Silence</title><subtitle>God grant me the serenity To accept the things I cannot change; Courage to change the things I can; And wisdom to know the difference.</subtitle><author><name>Silence</name></author><entry><title type="html">Summary of 4 months of misunderstanding and misdirection</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/10/Summary-of-3-4-months-of-misunderstanding-and-misdirection.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Summary of 4 months of misunderstanding and misdirection" /><published>2020-09-10T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-10T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/10/Summary-of-3-4-months-of-misunderstanding-and-misdirection</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/10/Summary-of-3-4-months-of-misunderstanding-and-misdirection.html">&lt;p&gt;For the last four months, perhaps longer, every time I submitted a scene, my coach would tell me, this scene “has no legs, no boots on the ground”. Or she would say, “There’s no there, there.” Or “This is just a one-off, it happens and it goes away.” “&lt;strong&gt;There are no consequences.” “There is no cause/effect.”&lt;/strong&gt; “There’s no ceiling that the characters are bumping against.” And on and on. Only now, I realize, each time she was trying to express the same problem to me. Never was it getting through, no matter the words. She even said, most directly, “You know, I don’t know if I’ve ever told anyone this, (since most people &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; focus on this), you need to focus more on the external, stop thinking about the internal.” [Meaning: focus on what’s happening in the character’s life, not what’s happening internally.]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time I had left a call, I took her words and tried to understand what exactly she was expressing to me. Why is she saying there are no consequences? Clearly, the consequences I see are not what she’s referring too. Or why is the phrase “There’s no there, there.” coming to her mind? What does that even mean. And even when said most directly like that, I sought external events in my character’s life, created external events. And believing I figured out what she was expressing, I eagerly submitted my next scene, only to learn my understanding was wrong. I had to start again. Why does this phrase come to her mind…?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, a lot of tears and sweat later, I’m eagerly blogging about it because &lt;del&gt;I believe&lt;/del&gt; I finally understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The answer came in an image. During our last call, my coach said, “Your character is lacking a road, a journey. And these scenes that you have provided aren’t affecting that road in any way.” A picture flashed in my head. My character on his deathbed, looking back on his life. What does he see? And what the hell does this picture that’s presenting itself have to do with my problem?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; we see when we look back? [Even though there’s a quote that sums up this image perfectly, I can’t find it for the life of me. So, instead of butchering the quote, I drew it out, how I see it in my head.]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SilenceVosh/silencevosh.github.io/master/_posts/assets/images/LifesPurpose.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image info&quot; title=&quot;Life's Purpose&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we look back on our lives, we see it has one continuous united story, that has been weaving itself together to get you to this point. Each event was a gear churning the story along. When this man, for example, looks back on his life, he’ll see that every event, every hiccup, everything he learned, all built who he is so he could take care of his family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it. That’s what I’m lacking, in every one of my scenes. She says all my scenes are one-offs and just float away, never to be thought about again. This is why. That scene floats away because it doesn’t have an overarching story to tether it to my character’s memory – the story that he sees churning from his deathbed. The story of his life’s purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s never consequence, never cause/effect because my scenes aren’t causing that life’s purpose to zig and to zag. Instead, they are floating up to space, never to be thought about again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to apologize for the series. First off, it’s going to be a difficult one to get into words. There’s a difference in finally understanding and fully understanding. I want to bridge that gap. Second, this series will become repetitive. This was a fundamental blindness, where my coach was telling me what I needed over and over, yet I read into the words a whole other meaning. I want to explore different attempts of understanding that meaning – how I was misreading it, how I could have understood it with her words altered slightly, and how I understand it now and will apply it going forward.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="writingmentalmodels" /><summary type="html">For the last four months, perhaps longer, every time I submitted a scene, my coach would tell me, this scene “has no legs, no boots on the ground”. Or she would say, “There’s no there, there.” Or “This is just a one-off, it happens and it goes away.” “There are no consequences.” “There is no cause/effect.” “There’s no ceiling that the characters are bumping against.” And on and on. Only now, I realize, each time she was trying to express the same problem to me. Never was it getting through, no matter the words. She even said, most directly, “You know, I don’t know if I’ve ever told anyone this, (since most people only focus on this), you need to focus more on the external, stop thinking about the internal.” [Meaning: focus on what’s happening in the character’s life, not what’s happening internally.]</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Emotional Register: Citizen Kane</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/09/Emotional-Register-Citizen-Kane.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Emotional Register: Citizen Kane" /><published>2020-09-09T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-09T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/09/Emotional-Register-Citizen-Kane</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/09/Emotional-Register-Citizen-Kane.html">&lt;p&gt;One way I’m using this knowledge about an &lt;a href=&quot;https://silencevosh.github.io/2020/08/30/Emotional-register-Wedding-speech.html&quot;&gt;emotional register&lt;/a&gt; is by asking myself what are these emotions reminding my character of?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Citizen Kane, one of the greatest films of all time, the whole movie is based around an emotional register. The opening scene, Mr. Kane passes away muttering his last word: Rosebud. A gang of reporters spend the whole movie trying to answer, what did these words mean? That’s the mystery and to solve it they are scavenging his life, all his past wives, all his achievements, everything he believed in, hoping to link anything to these words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The closet they came was this quote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A fellow will remember a lot of things you wouldn’t think he’d remember. You take me. One day, back in 1896, I was crossing over to Jersey on the ferry, and as we pulled out, there was another ferry pulling in, and on it there was a girl waiting to get off. A white dress she had on. She was carrying a white parasol. I only saw her for one second. She didn’t see me at all, but I’ll bet a month hasn’t gone by since that I haven’t thought of that girl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason, that girl in the white dress carried so much meaning to the man. Yet never will he know why. I suspect a story could be written about that man which explains it. Here is Mr. Kane’s story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scene before Mr. Kane died, his wife had left him, and the god of wrath overtook him. Wrath unlike ever before started destroying everything of hers. In this wave of emotion, his eyes landed upon a snow globe. In a flash, everything changed. He suddenly felt deeply defeated. Emotion of that intensity only been felt one other time in his life. When, in the dead of winter, as a young boy, he was taken from his home, having to leave his favorite sled behind to go to the city. It seemed he hadn’t remembered that sled since that day. Its name came to him as his heart went from him: Rosebud&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="likestoriesofold" /><summary type="html">One way I’m using this knowledge about an emotional register is by asking myself what are these emotions reminding my character of?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Find out if it’s NOT your passion</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/08/Find-out-if-its-NOT-your-passion.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Find out if it's NOT your passion" /><published>2020-09-08T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-08T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/08/Find-out-if-its-NOT-your-passion</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/08/Find-out-if-its-NOT-your-passion.html">&lt;p&gt;In 2020, I have taken a new approach to my goal to become a working author. Instead of learning to be a professional writer (self-improvement approach), like I’ve sought after over the last three years, I’m going to learn if being a writer is a possible next career or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout 2017-2019, I worked hard on my writing, on my craft, and on my writer’s toolbox. I wrote one novel, start to finish. 127,562 words! I spent over a year outlining a second novel. I gathered resources and made writing templates and created a whole system for writing and planning novels. I studied character building, world building, outlining verse discovery writing, and on and on. And on and on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have the drive and persistence for it. Every day, I sit down and uncomfortably work on a piece of writing. Every day, I share something, anything, journaling, emails, letters, blogs. And although these are the keys to becoming a writer, (becoming anything), I still don’t know if this is my calling or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know if I spend 2020 attempting the same things, I will begin 2021, first, not knowing if this is my calling, second, with nothing to share, and third, the biggest problem: not being able to leave it between because I’ve dedicated so much time with no tangible results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how by the end of 2020, can I learn if this, this writing thing, is a career for me or not? My answer: experimentation, experimenting with what it’s like to be a writer by participating with others in the writing world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a list of experiences I want in 2020:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is it like to write something and share it with the world?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is it like to work with a writing coach, or to work with an editor?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is it like joining a writing group and seeing them once a week?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is it like to work on deadlines?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is it like to attend a writer’s conference?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is it like to go through the whole process for publishing a book?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Already, I have begun to check these off and the possibilities have swung open. This blog is an extension of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="professionalwriter" /><summary type="html">In 2020, I have taken a new approach to my goal to become a working author. Instead of learning to be a professional writer (self-improvement approach), like I’ve sought after over the last three years, I’m going to learn if being a writer is a possible next career or not.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A stepping stone to pause and look at the view.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/07/A-stepping-stone-to-pause-and-look-at-the-view.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A stepping stone to pause and look at the view." /><published>2020-09-07T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-07T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/07/A-stepping-stone-to-pause-and-look-at-the-view</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/07/A-stepping-stone-to-pause-and-look-at-the-view.html">&lt;p&gt;After I wrote the post &lt;a href=&quot;https://silencevosh.github.io/2020/08/24/Externalize-Ripple-specificallyJustify.html&quot;&gt;Externalize, Ripple, Justify&lt;/a&gt;, I realized how far I’ve come as a writer. Being able to do what I described there, by free forming events of a story that are centered around a united story significant idea, is a grand achievement. One that almost slipped by without me appreciating the view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here , the view is crystal blue, floating ice everywhere. The land beneath me glides through calm seas, which beckoned me to decend deeper.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="generalblink" /><summary type="html">After I wrote the post Externalize, Ripple, Justify, I realized how far I’ve come as a writer. Being able to do what I described there, by free forming events of a story that are centered around a united story significant idea, is a grand achievement. One that almost slipped by without me appreciating the view.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Zodiac: hiding in plain sight</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/06/Zodiac-hiding-in-plain-sight.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Zodiac: hiding in plain sight" /><published>2020-09-06T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-06T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/06/Zodiac-hiding-in-plain-sight</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/06/Zodiac-hiding-in-plain-sight.html">&lt;p&gt;Never before has a movie exposed so obviously a flaw in my own thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zodiac is a 2007 film that follows a cartoonist, a news reporter, and a detective as we all try and figure out who’s the serial killer that’s been terrorizing the streets of San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Spoilers: I believe spoilers don’t matter unless you like to rewatch and reexperience stories. We watch movies not for what happens but for why it happens. Knowing what happens just adds to the immersion, and allows you to understand why it happens more deeply. Nevertheless, in this case, it’s a spoiler of the experience of the film. So I would recommend coming back to this after you have seen it.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt; * * * &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This film plays with the viewer, knowing the viewer comes into these mystery films with certain expectations and certain typical story beats. First off, they give us a promise very early in the movie. The killer sends a code to be deciphered, and the viewer is given this code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SilenceVosh/silencevosh.github.io/master/_posts/assets/images/Zodiac.png&quot; alt=&quot;image info&quot; title=&quot;Zodiac Riddle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been promised this is going to be a grand puzzle. Us verse the serial killer. Let’s stay aware and find those subtle hidden clues. The movie leans on this, citing old stories about the most dangerous game and more riddles. After your expectations are planted, the story starts to interweave obvious clues, that hint how the zodiac killer right here in front of you. But it’s too simple of a solution in this complex puzzle. It’s not satisfying. So, naturally, we reject it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, after being told who was the killer, I was left scratching my head. That can’t be him, I thought. I discussed it with my girlfriend. We scratched some more. Then, I took to the internet…which also seemed confused. Then it dawned on me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Occum’s Razor: the simplest solution is the most likely the right one.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="likestoriesofold" /><summary type="html">Never before has a movie exposed so obviously a flaw in my own thinking.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What makes me laugh #2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/05/What-makes-me-laugh2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What makes me laugh #2" /><published>2020-09-05T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-05T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/05/What-makes-me-laugh2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/05/What-makes-me-laugh2.html">&lt;p&gt;Okay, too many questions and too much theory and too much posting about how evil men could be seen in a beautiful light and about how I too would be conflicted about whether or not to save someone from ODing. Let’s laugh.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the opening of the movie Kiss, Kiss, Bang, Bang, one character is bantering with his gay friend, and says, “But when you see a naked guy, your brain says, ‘I want that.’ I don’t make that leap. It’s like, Look, there’s an elephant. Quick let’s drain its blood to paint my boathouse. It’s just that that’s not the first thing you think of.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is terrific linguistic humor.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="humorblink" /><summary type="html">Okay, too many questions and too much theory and too much posting about how evil men could be seen in a beautiful light and about how I too would be conflicted about whether or not to save someone from ODing. Let’s laugh.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Conflicting Moral Decisions #2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/04/Conflicting-Moral-Decisions2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Conflicting Moral Decisions #2" /><published>2020-09-04T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-04T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/04/Conflicting-Moral-Decisions2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/04/Conflicting-Moral-Decisions2.html">&lt;p&gt;In Breaking Bad, a scene that forever scarred me is based in a moral conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walter, who transforming into a major meth dealer, visits his much younger partner’s house. Jessie is like a son to Walter. Recently though he has been struggling with heroin addiction, and Walter feels responsible for his happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jessie fell back into addiction after meeting a neighbor girl. Quickly, she found out about a pile of money that Walter has of Jessie’s which with good intentions he was protecting for Jessie until he’s well. She loses control and makes all these crazy threats about ratting him out and calling the cops and such unless Walter hands over the money. Walter painfully does so, but that night, he returns to set things right and to work it out with Jessie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When he arrives, Jessie and she are out of this world, high on heroin, and he’s forced to break in to make sure everything is okay. Inside the house, the neighbor-girl laying on her back starts to OD. Standing over her, she starts to puke right before his eyes. He has the decision. Be human and save her life-risking being caught. Or let her die in front of him potentially saving Jessie from further drug abuse and certainly saving him from the trouble of what she knows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He watches her choke on her puke…for a deadful minute. God, it’s horrifying.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">In Breaking Bad, a scene that forever scarred me is based in a moral conflict.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lack of control over our future.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/03/Lack-of-control-over-our-future.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lack of control over our future." /><published>2020-09-03T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-03T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/03/Lack-of-control-over-our-future</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/03/Lack-of-control-over-our-future.html">&lt;p&gt;Because it is…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Jonas makes the decision to kill the love of his life it’s a lack of control over his own actions. That’s absolutely horrifying. DARK constantly presents this theme: everything is determined, no matter how much you believe you have free will. And even no matter how it feels and appears you have free will, it’s still all determined. At first that appears to be tragic and sad. Experiencing this, however, experiencing this contradiction of feeling like you’re acting with free will yet this is already determined been liberating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The predicted events of the show always happen as they should, reenforcing everything is determined. Yet moment to moment, we all truly are trying to do what we believe is best. We all are acting with free will. All we can do is what we think is right, then get out of our way. No character is ever doing something that they don’t believe is the right action. They act guided by invisible forces, and whatever happens, happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of us, in our forever misguided ways, is trying. Even the worst among us believe they are doing the right thing. And although it’s completely misguided, sad, horrifying, frustrating, they too are trying their best. We are all in this together.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink," /><category term="humanlearnings" /><summary type="html">Because it is…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Conflicting Moral Decisions</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/02/Conflicting-Moral-Decisions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Conflicting Moral Decisions" /><published>2020-09-02T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-02T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/02/Conflicting-Moral-Decisions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/02/Conflicting-Moral-Decisions.html">&lt;p&gt;The show DARK on Netflix constantly forces characters into conflicting moral decisions, where they must choose between two conflicting paths in life, each path stressing a different moral decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One scene in particular comes to mind. Jonas the protagonist, who seeks to save the world by destroying time travel, re-unites with the love of his life, after many pains and struggles. A few hugs later, his time-traveling future-self walks into the house and tells him, that she must die right now in order to save the world at the hand of young-Jonas. Now he’s presented with two paths and a decision. Young-Jonas still swears he would never do that, even having learned if he doesn’t – no one survives. Although he believes he won’t, we know he will. And we approach that moment with dread, not wanting to believe it’s true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This difference between who we think we are (someone who would choose love over everything) and who we are (someone who will quickly abandon and destroy that love if it means survival) is horrifying. It feels like a lack of control over our own decisions — because it is…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">The show DARK on Netflix constantly forces characters into conflicting moral decisions, where they must choose between two conflicting paths in life, each path stressing a different moral decision.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Studying Scenes on the Fly</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/01/Studying-scenes-on-the-fly.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Studying Scenes on the Fly" /><published>2020-09-01T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-01T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/01/Studying-scenes-on-the-fly</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/01/Studying-scenes-on-the-fly.html">&lt;p&gt;Recently I crossed a threshold in my understanding of how scenes work, an understanding of scene underpinnings. After hundreds of hours, I’ve figured this out so deeply that I can, while watching a show or a movie,  in real-time see the building blocks of these scenes on the fly. This is a superpower, since every scene I consume, I gain associations for scenes in my own story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bolded are the core question I’m able to ask on the fly (for each character in the scene). I included “Going Deeper” as that’s the next threshold to triumphant, being able to answer those questions on the fly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do they want in this scene?&lt;/strong&gt; (Going deeper: how is what they want a stepping stone towards their overarching purpose?)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the first truly unexpected thing? What is the first thing they must choose how they will respond to?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did they choose to respond?&lt;/strong&gt; (Deeper: in what way is that choice meaningful? Who they wish to be verse who they need to be? How it aligned with their overarching yearnings, both internally and externally?)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the consequences of this choice?&lt;/strong&gt; What relationships have changed or how has this character’s world changed? (These are the consequences within the scene. Also we can figure out the consequences in the overall scheme of the story… Deeper: how has this scene affected their overarching purpose? Because of the consequences, how has the pursuit of their goal changed? Have their possibilities in pursuit of their goal shrunken or grown?)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did they learn from this scene?&lt;/strong&gt; (Deeper: why does what they learned matter internally?)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What will they do now?&lt;/strong&gt; (Deeper: what new direction did do they now believe is best in pursuit of their goal?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Okay, too many questions, not enough examples. Future Post: I’ll break down one of my favorite scenes from Game of Thrones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To Note: this list will be ever-updating for me. This is my first draft, expect a second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt; * * * &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Original ideas: I credit Lisa Cron’s Story Genius for the foundation of these questions. She, in that book, presents the idea of a story scene card. It is truly genius. The whole book is.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="writingmentalmodels" /><summary type="html">Recently I crossed a threshold in my understanding of how scenes work, an understanding of scene underpinnings. After hundreds of hours, I’ve figured this out so deeply that I can, while watching a show or a movie, in real-time see the building blocks of these scenes on the fly. This is a superpower, since every scene I consume, I gain associations for scenes in my own story.</summary></entry></feed>