<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-30T12:57:46-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Daily writings from Silence</title><subtitle>God grant me the serenity To accept the things I cannot change; Courage to change the things I can; And wisdom to know the difference.</subtitle><author><name>Silence</name></author><entry><title type="html">Emotional Register: Wedding Speech</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/30/Emotional-register-Wedding-speech.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Emotional Register: Wedding Speech" /><published>2020-08-30T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-30T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/30/Emotional-register-Wedding-speech</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/30/Emotional-register-Wedding-speech.html">&lt;p&gt;On a podcast, Elizabeth Gilbert talked about an emotional register, and I’ve found this idea, not only a fascinating insight into humans, but quite illuminating for fiction writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s her telling the story (original audio included at the bottom):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My friend Kevin once attended a wedding where he heard the world’s most inappropriate wedding toast. The toast began inauspiciously enough. The best man stood up during the meal, clinked his knife against the crystal, and the other guests all quieted down.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“I was thinking on the airplane ride here about what I was going to say today about Danny and Joyce,” the best man began. “And all I could think at first was what a happy day today is.” Good enough start. But then this speech took an interesting turn. “And I realized that what I really wanted to talk about this afternoon is jury duty.”
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“Now, I don’t know how many of you have ever served on a jury,” he went on. “But it’s a fascinating process. I was just on a jury last year for the first time in my life, and I learned a lot about myself and about the legal system. It was a pretty serious case, too. It was actually a murder trial. It was very tragic. It was this old man who got killed. Very sad. He was getting money out of an ATM in the middle of the day and some gang kids came up and robbed him and shot him right in the face.”
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;By now, many of the wedding guests were lowering their champagne glasses gently back down to the table. “It was a cut-and-dry case, really,” he went on. “There were plenty of witnesses, and the forensic evidence pointed straight to one kid as the shooter. The kid was definitely guilty. But here’s the thing. It was actually a capital offense. And my jury had to decide whether or not to give this kid the death penalty.”
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“Now, I don’t know if any of you have ever had to decide whether somebody should live or die, but it’s emotionally intense. We all knew the kid was guilty, but the death penalty is nothing to take lightly. In the end, though, we decided yes, this kid needs to die. And we sent him to his death.”
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The tent was silent. The bride, ashen. The best man took a moment to compose himself and concluded, “That was probably the worst day of my life. And I got to thinking about it on the plane because that day was nothing like today, which is a happy day. A really happy day. So here’s to Danny and Joyce.” Thus concluded the toast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She pondered this story for years, and what she concluded…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I’ve decided that I get it. I’ve heard it said before that the human psyche cannot always tell the difference between good events and bad events. All we can feel is the tremor of the earth. Which is what happened to our best man, I believe. He was so overcome by happiness for his friend and he was so out of touch with his emotions that he couldn’t express that happiness appropriately. All he could do was remember the last time he had felt so moved by something, and so he tried to express that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When he thought of his best friend getting married, he had no relatable thoughts. The only thing his mind presented him was compared in emotional weight. So he tried to express that emotion in the only way he could, by telling about that fateful day when he decided to put a fellow human to death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt; * * * &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The audio:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://shortcut.thisamericanlife.org/#/clipping/234/2884?_k=acgwsc&quot;&gt;Clipping from This American Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="humanlearnings," /><category term="writingconcepts" /><summary type="html">On a podcast, Elizabeth Gilbert talked about an emotional register, and I’ve found this idea, not only a fascinating insight into humans, but quite illuminating for fiction writing.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stories controlling what your mind doesn’t see: Science-Fiction and Fantasy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/29/Stories-controlling-what-your-mind-doesnt-see-Science-fiction-and-fantasy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stories controlling what your mind doesn't see: Science-Fiction and Fantasy" /><published>2020-08-29T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-29T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/29/Stories-controlling-what-your-mind-doesnt-see-Science-fiction-and-fantasy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/29/Stories-controlling-what-your-mind-doesnt-see-Science-fiction-and-fantasy.html">&lt;p&gt;Another captivating way stories convey information, without our minds turning on and questioning it, is by the setting or the genre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say you want to make a point about race issues in America. So you base your movie in America with all the surrounding sides of the issue – Black America, the KKK, the White Americas who don’t speak up, the White Americas who do, all the other cultures and movements, and so on. This clearly will be a movie about that issue. That is fine and great, if that’s your purpose, if you want the audience throughout the film to consciously think about the issue and ask questions around it. If, on the other hand, you want the issue still floating around but hidden in the background, you – as a god – can shift the setting into a new world; let’s call it Pandora. Here, even though the audience experiences the same conflicts, the same issues, they’re not consciously thinking about them, they’re immersed in the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue is hiding in plain sight, unseen by the conscious mind.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="writingmentalmodels" /><summary type="html">Another captivating way stories convey information, without our minds turning on and questioning it, is by the setting or the genre.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Where University Misguides Writers: what matters.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/28/Where-University-misguides-writers-what-matters.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Where University Misguides Writers: what matters." /><published>2020-08-28T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-28T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/28/Where-University-misguides-writers-what-matters</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/28/Where-University-misguides-writers-what-matters.html">&lt;p&gt;To control what the audience doesn’t see, you first and foremost must be in tune with your story, specifically what truly matters in your story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In weird science, they knew the science didn’t matter. They wanted to make a playful, idea story, about a couple dorky high school kids who created a real-life barbie doll slave…who they instantly decided to shower with. Those goofy moments mattered and drove the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Universities (and the majority of non-fiction books on writing) stress things that in the overall picture don’t matter, like lyrical writing or rules of world-building or story structure. Once you start giving importance to those before the story, the audience can feel it. If you’re trying to find the perfect word that completes some poetic pattern instead of finding the perfect word for the story, the audience will know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week’s theme showed up over and over: study, learn, then forget it all, and get hell out of the story’s way.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="writingmentalmodels" /><summary type="html">To control what the audience doesn’t see, you first and foremost must be in tune with your story, specifically what truly matters in your story.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Weird Science</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/27/Weird-Science.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Weird Science" /><published>2020-08-27T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-27T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/27/Weird-Science</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/27/Weird-Science.html">&lt;p&gt;When I browsed trailers, this movie kept showing up because of a 30th-year anniversary. It’s an eighties cult movie with an over the top comical premise which carries us through the movie, laughing and shaking our heads the whole way. What if two teenage boys had a beautiful model as a slave?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create this model, the boys use “science”, computer programming with awful graphics, to bring a doll to life. The movie uses this fake science so overtly, we don’t care. They aren’t trying to pass it off as real, and because of that our minds just accept it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just good communication by the producers. They understood if they walk that line between real and not, the audience will question. But if they show, they themselves don’t care about the science, then a healthy mind naturally understands what they are communicating, and completely neglects it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This is a fundamental skill of a writer: controlling what the audience doesn’t see, controlling what their brain neglects, naturally.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">When I browsed trailers, this movie kept showing up because of a 30th-year anniversary. It’s an eighties cult movie with an over the top comical premise which carries us through the movie, laughing and shaking our heads the whole way. What if two teenage boys had a beautiful model as a slave?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Foreign Films</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/26/Foreign-Films.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Foreign Films" /><published>2020-08-26T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-26T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/26/Foreign-Films</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/26/Foreign-Films.html">&lt;p&gt;Talking with an Argentine movie lover, he told me, he refuses to watch a movie that’s dubbed into Spanish. “It’s loses all its flavor,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing up on Disney and Hollywood films, I wasn’t introduced to foreign films until ‘Crouching Tiger, Hidden Dragon’ became famous, and even then as an egotistical high schooler I wondered why in the world would someone watch a movie that wasn’t in English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, as someone who is constantly controlled by words and thoughts, love picturing how the knowledge isn’t actually in those words. To understand the depth of what’s going on, you don’t even need the words. You just need to experience the tones, the expressions, the emotions of the film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
To taste a new flavor of life, I will try an experiment: Put on a Chinese film, without subtitles, and feel my way through the movie.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="humanlearnings," /><category term="theMuse" /><summary type="html">Talking with an Argentine movie lover, he told me, he refuses to watch a movie that’s dubbed into Spanish. “It’s loses all its flavor,” he said.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What a movie trailer promises: The Graduate</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/25/What-a-movie-trailer-promises-The-Graduate.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What a movie trailer promises: The Graduate" /><published>2020-08-25T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-25T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/25/What-a-movie-trailer-promises-The-Graduate</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/25/What-a-movie-trailer-promises-The-Graduate.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6KnSucVko1s&quot; title=&quot;The Graduate&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://img.youtube.com/vi/6KnSucVko1s/0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Young Dustin Hoffman. Movie from the 60s. It’s difficult to get my girlfriend to watch any movie before the 2000s. But this one, perhaps she would watch because it seems like it could portray a character with some insights into who I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emotion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drama evoked from an insecure young man, who while insecure is sought after. Opening shot: Dustin Hoffman alone, zoomed out he’s surrounded by hundreds of people.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dramas focus on a character acting in such a way that he effects all of those around him. Here, Dustin is in a life-transition, just graduating college, and seems to be lost, sleeping with a married woman while being in love with her daughter. We feel fustration that he’s not embodying the confidence that’s in him.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We’ll be waiting and waiting for him to speak up for himself and take what he wants, instead of allowing other’s desires to control him. This was actually teased in the trailer, the finale, when Dustin stops a wedding for the women he loves.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Why would they show this? I remember watching ‘The Boy who Harnessed the Wind’, a movie about a boy in Africa who created a power generator from a windmill and saved the village from a drought. I remember painfully watching that movie, waiting for the moment to happen we all knew would happen when he finally harnessed the wind. All that anticipation grows into a grand payoff and a huge cathartic release when he finally succeeds. I’m guessing this would have a similar effect.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Externalize, Ripple, &amp;amp; specifically Justify to a root cause</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/24/Externalize-Ripple-specificallyJustify.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Externalize, Ripple, &amp; specifically Justify to a root cause" /><published>2020-08-24T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-24T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/24/Externalize-Ripple-specificallyJustify</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/24/Externalize-Ripple-specificallyJustify.html">&lt;p&gt;My coach grilled me last call. Currently, I’m trying to get a handle on the problem that is taking over my character’s life, more specifically how that problem is ruining his relationship with his lovely girlfriend. My coach said to forget all the concepts, all the ideas, and let my mind create interactions between the two of them. She said when I do that I have it and am able to produce great material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here’s how I’m attempting this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal is to get a sense of their relationship, which isn’t found in asking conceptual questions like “What is the difference in how Josh perceives Em compared to how she really is?” Nor should I try to find the perfect scene to illustrate their differences, to illustrate how Josh focuses on control while Em focuses on experience. Instead, here’s my three-step process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Externalize: state something or ask a simple question focused on an external behavior:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Lately, Josh spends more time at work, later nights away from home.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ripple: watch how that ripples out by freeing the mind to brainstorm, asking and answering whatever questions it wants to:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Why? How was that caused by their relationship differences and problems? How does that in turn cause their problem to grow and ripple? Because he’s working late, he skips her nightly yoga class, which used to be the one time they connected. Now, perhaps Em gives more attention to other guys in the class. And perhaps, now she’s seeing how much less stress a relationship could be with someone she’s naturally more compatible with, someone who naturally likes yoga and likes the spiritual things she likes such as crystals and mantras and the like. Now Josh and Em arrive home at separate times, and started to eat dinner separately.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Justify: find the specific moment that caused him to work late:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;When is this exact moment? Well, ever since Em has felt more distant from Josh because he’s opening up less, she started leveraging her teacher role in yoga classes to try and open him up more. Previously, she would start her classes with meditation. But now, she will try something new, with the hopes that Josh will start to open up more. She says to the class she wants to try a “class building exercise”. She asks them to stand in a circle, across from another student, and to do eye gazing for 1 minute. Josh suffers through the vulnerability. Afterward, for the next class, Josh claims he can’t make it “because of work duties”. And this pattern stuck and they grew further and further apart.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus: if this moment would tell us a lot about our character and who he is, then we could go one more step and write out the scene, to discover even more specifics, exactly how he behaved in this experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Then, I start again, rolling off of this work and stating something again, watching it ripple and justifying it – creating a web of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt; * * * &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t to say all that conceptual work I did before was a waste. On the contrary. In step one, I’m making a statement; these statements and questions must be story significant; they must be something that bumps against the overarching problem that is building in Josh’s life. An example that isn’t story significant: Josh recently started eating more cake, which Em hates, and they grow further apart. Eating cake has nothing to do with his internal problem of being afraid to feel and express emotions. But at this point, stating something story significant isn’t something I need to think about, because of the countless hours thinking about the story problem and figuring out the concepts and pondering the central issue. This is what my coach actually what my coach meant: I tended to force these events by consciously trying to identify what is the most story significant thing. My coach recognized I don’t need that. She recognized how I can — if I allow myself to — let my mind freeform write and watch the images it decides to associate and watch whatever it decides to splurge across my screen.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="writingmentalmodels" /><summary type="html">My coach grilled me last call. Currently, I’m trying to get a handle on the problem that is taking over my character’s life, more specifically how that problem is ruining his relationship with his lovely girlfriend. My coach said to forget all the concepts, all the ideas, and let my mind create interactions between the two of them. She said when I do that I have it and am able to produce great material.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lucilla in Gladiator, what emotion is her storyline evoking?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/23/Lucilla-in-Gladiator-what-emotion-is-her-storyline-evoking.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lucilla in Gladiator, what emotion is her storyline evoking?" /><published>2020-08-23T14:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-23T14:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/23/Lucilla-in-Gladiator-what-emotion-is-her-storyline-evoking</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/23/Lucilla-in-Gladiator-what-emotion-is-her-storyline-evoking.html">&lt;p&gt;Lucilla is Commodus’s sister. Although it’s unspoken, she’s completely under his control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We feel constant dread interacting with the psychopathic ruler (Joaquin Phoenix), and we have no idea what will happen next. Lucilla constantly reacts by seeking control, seeking to tame him, but she knows this is all futile. She knows she’s powerless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We typically think of horror as blood and a scary monster, but this is horrifying. And we feel it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">Lucilla is Commodus’s sister. Although it’s unspoken, she’s completely under his control.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Where’s safety? (how we don’t express what matters)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/22/Wheres-safety-(how-we-dont-express-what-matters).html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Where's safety? (how we don't express what matters)" /><published>2020-08-22T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-22T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/22/Wheres-safety?-(how-we-dont-express-what-matters)</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/22/Wheres-safety-(how-we-dont-express-what-matters).html">&lt;p&gt;Knowing my character hides his true self, hides what matters to him, when I’m learning more specifics about him, I constantly ask, in every situation, where is safety for him. Where’s safety in this conversation? (What is he afraid to say? To ask? Why can’t he say this directly? How will his body language be different than his speech?) Where’s safety in this scene? Maybe he’s afraid of feeling vulnerable, and he seeks safety in filling silence with language. Or maybe, on the other side of that coin, safety is found in experiencing vulnerability with your loved one because that’s when you feel a true connection with them. Maybe safety is found in not making eye contact. Maybe in staying at the office late and working, earning more money. Maybe after a BMW cuts you off, safety is found in speeding up and flicking them the bird. And on and on and on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans are fascinating creatures.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="writingmentalmodels" /><summary type="html">Knowing my character hides his true self, hides what matters to him, when I’m learning more specifics about him, I constantly ask, in every situation, where is safety for him. Where’s safety in this conversation? (What is he afraid to say? To ask? Why can’t he say this directly? How will his body language be different than his speech?) Where’s safety in this scene? Maybe he’s afraid of feeling vulnerable, and he seeks safety in filling silence with language. Or maybe, on the other side of that coin, safety is found in experiencing vulnerability with your loved one because that’s when you feel a true connection with them. Maybe safety is found in not making eye contact. Maybe in staying at the office late and working, earning more money. Maybe after a BMW cuts you off, safety is found in speeding up and flicking them the bird. And on and on and on.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Gods of Egypt: Jordan Peterson</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/21/Gods-of-Egypt-Jordan-Peterson.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gods of Egypt: Jordan Peterson" /><published>2020-08-21T07:09:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-21T07:09:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/21/Gods-of-Egypt:-Jordan-Peterson</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/21/Gods-of-Egypt-Jordan-Peterson.html">&lt;p&gt;The Gods of Egypt movie trailer, &lt;a href=&quot;https://silencevosh.github.io/trailerblink/2020/08/20/What-a-movie-trailer-promises-Gods-of-Egypt.html&quot;&gt;from the last post&lt;/a&gt;, I realized was a story I first heard told by Jordan Peterson, who tells it better than the movie does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His clip here:
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_uIv7elByXY&quot; title=&quot;Gods of Egypt&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://img.youtube.com/vi/_uIv7elByXY/0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="generalblink" /><summary type="html">The Gods of Egypt movie trailer, from the last post, I realized was a story I first heard told by Jordan Peterson, who tells it better than the movie does.</summary></entry></feed>