<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-24T08:05:04-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Daily writings from Silence</title><subtitle>God grant me the serenity To accept the things I cannot change; Courage to change the things I can; And wisdom to know the difference.</subtitle><author><name>Silence</name></author><entry><title type="html">Externalize, Ripple, &amp;amp; specifically Justify to a root cause</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writingmentalmodels/2020/08/24/Externalize-Ripple-specificallyJustify.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Externalize, Ripple, &amp; specifically Justify to a root cause" /><published>2020-08-24T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-24T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writingmentalmodels/2020/08/24/Externalize-Ripple-specificallyJustify</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writingmentalmodels/2020/08/24/Externalize-Ripple-specificallyJustify.html">&lt;p&gt;My coach grilled me last call. Currently, I’m trying to get a handle on the problem that is taking over my character’s life, more specifically how that problem is ruining his relationship with his lovely girlfriend. My coach said to forget all the concepts, all the ideas, and let my mind create interactions between the two of them. She said when I do that I have it and am able to produce great material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here’s how I’m attempting this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal is to get a sense of their relationship, which isn’t found in asking conceptual questions like “What is the difference in how Josh perceives Em compared to how she really is?” Nor should I try to find the perfect scene to illustrate their differences, to illustrate how Josh focuses on control while Em focuses on experience. Instead, here’s my three-step process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Externalize: state something or ask a simple question focused on an external behavior:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Lately, Josh spends more time at work, later nights away from home.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ripple: watch how that ripples out by freeing the mind to brainstorm, asking and answering whatever questions it wants to:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Why? How was that caused by their relationship differences and problems? How does that in turn cause their problem to grow and ripple? Because he’s working late, he skips her nightly yoga class, which used to be the one time they connected. Now, perhaps Em gives more attention to other guys in the class. And perhaps, now she’s seeing how much less stress a relationship could be with someone she’s naturally more compatible with, someone who naturally likes yoga and likes the spiritual things she likes such as crystals and mantras and the like. Now Josh and Em arrive home at separate times, and started to eat dinner separately.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Justify: find the specific moment that caused him to work late:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;When is this exact moment? Well, ever since Em has felt more distant from Josh because he’s opening up less, she started leveraging her teacher role in yoga classes to try and open him up more. Previously, she would start her classes with meditation. But now, she will try something new, with the hopes that Josh will start to open up more. She says to the class she wants to try a “class building exercise”. She asks them to stand in a circle, across from another student, and to do eye gazing for 1 minute. Josh suffers through the vulnerability. Afterward, for the next class, Josh claims he can’t make it “because of work duties”. And this pattern stuck and they grew further and further apart.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus: if this moment would tell us a lot about our character and who he is, then we could go one more step and write out the scene, to discover even more specifics, exactly how he behaved in this experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Then, I start again, rolling off of this work and stating something again, watching it ripple and justifying it – creating a web of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt; * * * &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t to say all that conceptual work I did before was a waste. On the contrary. In step one, I’m making a statement; these statements and questions must be story significant; they must be something that bumps against the overarching problem that is building in Josh’s life. An example that isn’t story significant: Josh recently started eating more cake, which Em hates, and they grow further apart. Eating cake has nothing to do with his internal problem of being afraid to feel and express emotions. But at this point, stating something story significant isn’t something I need to think about, because of the countless hours thinking about the story problem and figuring out the concepts and pondering the central issue. This is what my coach actually what my coach meant: I tended to force these events by consciously trying to identify what is the most story significant thing. My coach recognized I don’t need that. She recognized how I can — if I allow myself to — let the mind freeform write, and watch the images my mind decides to associate and watch whatever it decides to splurge across my screen.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="mistakesmade," /><category term="storycreation" /><summary type="html">My coach grilled me last call. Currently, I’m trying to get a handle on the problem that is taking over my character’s life, more specifically how that problem is ruining his relationship with his lovely girlfriend. My coach said to forget all the concepts, all the ideas, and let my mind create interactions between the two of them. She said when I do that I have it and am able to produce great material.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lucilla in Gladiator, what emotion is her storyline evoking?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/storyblink/2020/08/23/Lucilla-in-Gladiator-what-emotion-is-her-storyline-evoking.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lucilla in Gladiator, what emotion is her storyline evoking?" /><published>2020-08-23T14:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-23T14:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/storyblink/2020/08/23/Lucilla-in-Gladiator-what-emotion-is-her-storyline-evoking</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/storyblink/2020/08/23/Lucilla-in-Gladiator-what-emotion-is-her-storyline-evoking.html">&lt;p&gt;Lucilla is Commodus’s sister. Although it’s unspoken, she’s completely under his control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We feel constant dread interacting with the psychopathic ruler (Joaquin Phoenix), and we have no idea what will happen next. Lucilla constantly reacts by seeking control, seeking to tame him, but she knows this is all futile. She knows she’s powerless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We typically think of horror as blood and a scary monster, but this is horrifying. And we feel it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="emotions," /><category term="elementalgenres" /><summary type="html">Lucilla is Commodus’s sister. Although it’s unspoken, she’s completely under his control.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Where’s safety? (how we don’t express what matters)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writingmentalmodels/2020/08/22/Wheres-safety-(how-we-dont-express-what-matters).html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Where's safety? (how we don't express what matters)" /><published>2020-08-22T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-22T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writingmentalmodels/2020/08/22/Wheres-safety?-(how-we-dont-express-what-matters)</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writingmentalmodels/2020/08/22/Wheres-safety-(how-we-dont-express-what-matters).html">&lt;p&gt;Knowing my character hides his true self, hides what matters to him, when I’m learning more specifics about him, I constantly ask, in every situation, where is safety for him. Where’s safety in this conversation? (What is he afraid to say? To ask? Why can’t he say this directly? How will his body language be different than his speech?) Where’s safety in this scene? Maybe he’s afraid of feeling vulnerable, and he seeks safety in filling silence with language. Or maybe, on the other side of that coin, safety is found in experiencing vulnerability with your loved one because that’s when you feel a true connection with them. Maybe safety is found in not making eye contact. Maybe in staying at the office late and working, earning more money. Maybe after a BMW cuts you off, safety is found in speeding up and flicking them the bird. And on and on and on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans are fascinating creatures.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="mentalmodels" /><summary type="html">Knowing my character hides his true self, hides what matters to him, when I’m learning more specifics about him, I constantly ask, in every situation, where is safety for him. Where’s safety in this conversation? (What is he afraid to say? To ask? Why can’t he say this directly? How will his body language be different than his speech?) Where’s safety in this scene? Maybe he’s afraid of feeling vulnerable, and he seeks safety in filling silence with language. Or maybe, on the other side of that coin, safety is found in experiencing vulnerability with your loved one because that’s when you feel a true connection with them. Maybe safety is found in not making eye contact. Maybe in staying at the office late and working, earning more money. Maybe after a BMW cuts you off, safety is found in speeding up and flicking them the bird. And on and on and on.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Gods of Egypt: Jordan Peterson</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blink/2020/08/21/Gods-of-Egypt-Jordan-Peterson.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gods of Egypt: Jordan Peterson" /><published>2020-08-21T07:09:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-21T07:09:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blink/2020/08/21/Gods-of-Egypt:-Jordan-Peterson</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blink/2020/08/21/Gods-of-Egypt-Jordan-Peterson.html">&lt;p&gt;The Gods of Egypt movie trailer, &lt;a href=&quot;https://silencevosh.github.io/trailerblink/2020/08/20/What-a-movie-trailer-promises-Gods-of-Egypt.html&quot;&gt;from the last post&lt;/a&gt;, I realized was a story I first heard told by Jordan Peterson, who tells it better than the movie does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His clip here:
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_uIv7elByXY&quot; title=&quot;Gods of Egypt&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://img.youtube.com/vi/_uIv7elByXY/0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="humanlearnings" /><summary type="html">The Gods of Egypt movie trailer, from the last post, I realized was a story I first heard told by Jordan Peterson, who tells it better than the movie does.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What a movie trailer promises: Gods of Egypt</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/trailerblink/2020/08/20/What-a-movie-trailer-promises-Gods-of-Egypt.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What a movie trailer promises: Gods of Egypt" /><published>2020-08-20T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-20T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/trailerblink/2020/08/20/What-a-movie-trailer-promises:-Gods-of-Egypt</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/trailerblink/2020/08/20/What-a-movie-trailer-promises-Gods-of-Egypt.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IJBnK2wNQSo&quot; title=&quot;Gods of Egypt&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://img.youtube.com/vi/IJBnK2wNQSo/0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Promises:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A thriller. There are many types of thrillers. Sometimes a character is trying to escape prison without being caught (Escape from Pretoria). Sometimes a character is in a physical life or death chase for his life, (The Game). Sometimes, the world is about to end or a city is about to blow up, and the hero needs to stop that, (The Dark Knight). Gods of Egypt falls into that last category.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Typical emotion experienced: anxiety, stress that the hero won’t save the world, or find the serial killer before he kills again, or escape with his life. We watch them succeed often, yet things get worse and more difficult (Jame Bond movies), and we have that question in the back of our minds: will he save the world in time?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other emotions in this movie:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;wonder, in awe over watching the God battle.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;humor, likely a lot of status changes, humans acting like gods, gods acting like humans. This kind of humor is very common in superhero movies. (Often done at the expense of real emotion. Instead of allowing sadness arise, the writer throws in a cheap joke.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
***&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal here is to better understand movies before watching, by focusing on what emotions will be evoked rather than the movieshelf genres. ‘Captain America: The First Avenger’ is a very different movie from ‘Captain America: Winter Solider’. The first we are going on an adventure, watching this feeble boy become a superhero, the other we are watching a superhero, run for his life verse an evil government while trying to solve a mystery. Same movieshelf genres, completely different emotions evoked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Original idea: https://writingexcuses.com/category/season/season-11/ Element Genres.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="elementalgenre," /><category term="storyreview" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">When something isn’t working, have the opposite happen.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mistakes/2020/08/19/When-something-isn't-working-have-the-opposite-happen.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="When something isn't working, have the opposite happen." /><published>2020-08-19T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-19T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mistakes/2020/08/19/When-something-isn't-working-have-the-opposite-happen</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mistakes/2020/08/19/When-something-isn't-working-have-the-opposite-happen.html">&lt;p&gt;Recently, I was talking a scene out with my coach. The pieces were all known, but the scene wasn’t quite working. The events of the scene weren’t changing my character internally like we wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The climax of the scene was the trouble area, more specifically my character’s last meaningful decision. In the scene, two ten-old-years were at cross purposes about what to play. One character wanted to play baseball outside, while the other wanted to play indoors with G.I. Joes and the like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew at the end of the scene my protagonist would choose to give up his desires and would choose to choke down what he wants to do, in order to fit in with his friend. (This was the end result we were looking for: a character begins his tragic journey of giving up the feeling of belonging for the feeling of fitting in.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it wasn’t clicking with the rest of the pieces in the scene. My coach said, “Sometimes, it’s best to just flip it.” She asked, what if instead it’s the protagonist who suggests to go play baseball outside, out of wanting to reconnect with his friend (even though he rather not play baseball). So he says, “Let’s forget this and go outside to play catch.” And now, his friend catches him off guard, by jumping all over that idea, and says, “Yes, I’m so happy you were thinking the same thing. These games are for babies. I’ll grab my glove.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That shoves a needle into my character’s heart because he loved those games, and now, he’s forced to hide that joy. Now he wouldn’t dare play something that his best friend thinks is childish. So he suppresses to fit in. And that suppression grows, ripples, and evolves throughout his life, and we have a story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
That takes decades of mastering storytelling. In the meantime, perhaps this post will serve as a reminder, so next time I’m stuck, I can hack my way to the answer.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="hacks," /><category term="learnings" /><summary type="html">Recently, I was talking a scene out with my coach. The pieces were all known, but the scene wasn’t quite working. The events of the scene weren’t changing my character internally like we wanted.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What makes me laugh #1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/humorblink/2020/08/18/What-makes-me-laugh-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What makes me laugh #1" /><published>2020-08-18T11:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-18T11:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/humorblink/2020/08/18/What-makes-me-laugh-#1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/humorblink/2020/08/18/What-makes-me-laugh-1.html">&lt;p&gt;Show: The Good Place&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michael, the literal architect of the heavens, helped out a human architect on earth, by gifting him a blueprint of a new building, a dream blueprint. The human’s dream building.
He tells Michael, “This is is the most amazing print I’ve ever seen. But…” he scans around, “Where are the bathrooms?”
Michael goes on to explain how it was silly of him to forget that, and saying how in the world could he forget that, because “I too love and need bathrooms, and the thing you sit on, and shoot into.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I want to stick a pin in these from time to time, to understand why I’m laughing, so I can write humor better.
Here, there were two laughs for me. The first, caused by a status change: we are picturing this godly blueprint, yet, we learn, it’s missing one of the most fundamental pieces to a bathroom. The second: Michael unintentionally using linguist humor, by describing something in an unexpected yet realistic way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mind is trying to understand the two conflicting thoughts, and when realized they’re one and the same, they clash together, releasing the confusion into a laugh.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="humorblink," /><category term="whatmakesmelaugh" /><summary type="html">Show: The Good Place</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hiding our True self: why we don’t express what matters</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/humanlearnings/2020/08/17/Hiding-our-True-self-why-we-don't-express-what-matters.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hiding our True self: why we don't express what matters" /><published>2020-08-17T11:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-17T11:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/humanlearnings/2020/08/17/Hiding-our-True-self:-why-we-don't-express-what-matters</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/humanlearnings/2020/08/17/Hiding-our-True-self-why-we-don't-express-what-matters.html">&lt;p&gt;My biggest lesson during this journey to become a writer: Fictional characters constantly hide what matters most to them, by saying or acting differently on the surface from what is going on inside. For example, after a husband gets home late from work, his wife says dinner might be cold, instead of saying it makes me sad when you’re late because I tell myself you don’t care about the sweat I pour into cooking a nice meal. Or instead a 10-year-old boy, after his friend says toys are for babies, agrees, suppressing the joy and the belonging he feels when playing with toys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do they (we) do this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Once Adam and Eve eat the fruit, “the eyes of both [are] opened,” and they become self-conscious. They realize that they are naked, unprotected, and vulnerable. They realize how they can be hurt, how they will die, and how anyone like them is also vulnerable to death and suffering. With awareness of human vulnerability, the human choice of malevolence becomes possible. Mere animals also die, but they lack the self-consciousness to project their own mortality into the future. Mere animals kill, but the malevolence of Cain against Abel is a possibility only for humankind. – JBP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Showing the world what matters most to us, what we care most about, what we identify with, gives the world a key to our soul. We are saying, hey, look here, to hurt me, attack in this very spot. Tap it if you want to make me wince. Twist if you want me to squirm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead, we put on a mask. We miscommunicate about who we are. And the world – as we all co-participate in this together – becomes increasingly more confused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What can we do? What can we control? The hard one: we can choose the people we surround ourselves with, choose people who we trust to not stomp on our soul. And then, we can continually work to honor who we are. The harder one: we can separate our energy from others and not let other’s opinions shake who we are. And then, we can continually work to honor who we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Personally, I love cat memes and gifs, stupid little pieces of humor that add a spark of laughter to my day. Yet, I know those are immature, they aren’t anything important or vital or spiritual, aren’t anything that gets me ahead in life. So slide my mask on, brilliantly acting like I don’t enjoy them. I go on miscommunicating about them, so much so that the mask becomes more comfortable than my own face. So much so that I lose touch with my own face. I stop seeking out cats altogether. And that spark of laughter dies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog, I hope to honor and even discover who I am, through posting my thoughts, my opinions, and my writings. Perhaps if I can do it here, I can return to the world, passing out keys, to the ones in my life.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="communication," /><category term="likestoriesofold," /><category term="humanlearning" /><summary type="html">My biggest lesson during this journey to become a writer: Fictional characters constantly hide what matters most to them, by saying or acting differently on the surface from what is going on inside. For example, after a husband gets home late from work, his wife says dinner might be cold, instead of saying it makes me sad when you’re late because I tell myself you don’t care about the sweat I pour into cooking a nice meal. Or instead a 10-year-old boy, after his friend says toys are for babies, agrees, suppressing the joy and the belonging he feels when playing with toys.</summary></entry></feed>