<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-24T08:27:04-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Daily writings from Silence</title><subtitle>God grant me the serenity To accept the things I cannot change; Courage to change the things I can; And wisdom to know the difference.</subtitle><author><name>Silence</name></author><entry><title type="html">Why was I so blind, for 4 grueling months? #2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/24/Why-was-I-so-blind-for-4-grueling-months-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why was I so blind, for 4 grueling months? #2" /><published>2020-09-24T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-24T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/24/Why-was-I-so-blind-for-4-grueling-months-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/24/Why-was-I-so-blind-for-4-grueling-months-2.html">&lt;p&gt;Over the last four months, I’ve always done well asking scene level questions and finding scene level answers. Why does my character refuse to sing in the shower? Because he’s afraid that his girlfriend will hear his constricted voice. Why does he like to mimic other’s accents? Because he believes connection (and thus safety) is found in being alike. Why did he decide to be a linguistics major? Because language will give him the power to manipulate people into doing things for him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I focused so eagerly on these, that I forgot how humans are complex characters with a whole hierarchy of driving forces. Forces outside this single scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a doodle to help me.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SilenceVosh/silencevosh.github.io/master/_posts/assets/images/FlyingDragon.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;image info&quot; title=&quot;Life's Purpose&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I was doing before was focusing all my efforts on understanding the iceberg. I was blind to the huge flying dragon which was driving my character into them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I needed to ask questions about the iceberg and about the dragon. How did this iceberg (the scene) affect his dragon (life purpose)? Did the crash even slow his dragon down? Did his dragon tumble out of the air, splashing into the ocean? While in the ocean, did he transform into a sea-serpent and drags him to the depths of the sea? Or was it just a hiccup, the character landed back on his skis, and that continued their path together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This doodle is another way of framing the problem. From here I can see that his dragon and the scenes can’t exist without the other. It’s a dance between them. Without scenes, the dragon would pull our character directly to the end of his life without a single bump in the road, without creating a single memory that mattered. Without the dragon, the iceberg isn’t a problem, doesn’t affect the character. Our character just stays in place, treading water. A purposeless character, on his couch he spends his life tasting new flavors of potato chips, again without creating a single memory that mattered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Closing with an example, a list of moments of this dance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say our skier’s life purpose is to have a big family, dreams of at least 5 children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;He’s drafted into the army just as he met a woman who he believes to be the love of his life.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The love of his life cheats on him while he’s away. In a rage, he leaves camp to get some air, and while away the camp gets bombed. He’s discharged.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;He returns home hateful, and this attitude pushes all women away from him.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thirty years old and still wanting a big family, he begins to date younger. His family becomes judgemental towards him, so much so that the man cuts off all ties with them in order to continue to pursue a big family.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;He meets a lovely girl who also loves kids and wants to get married right now. They go to vegas.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;She’s unable to get pregnant. His hatefulness becomes unbearable and he takes it out on his wife. She now lives scare, and now no longer wants to even adopt kids with him. She leaves him.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The sea-serpent, after crashing into the sea, drags him to the depths.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="writingmentalmodels," /><category term="lifespurpose_series" /><summary type="html">Over the last four months, I’ve always done well asking scene level questions and finding scene level answers. Why does my character refuse to sing in the shower? Because he’s afraid that his girlfriend will hear his constricted voice. Why does he like to mimic other’s accents? Because he believes connection (and thus safety) is found in being alike. Why did he decide to be a linguistics major? Because language will give him the power to manipulate people into doing things for him.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why was I so blind, for 4 grueling months?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/23/Why-was-I-so-blind-for-4-grueling-months.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why was I so blind, for 4 grueling months?" /><published>2020-09-23T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-23T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/23/Why-was-I-so-blind-for-4-grueling-months</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/23/Why-was-I-so-blind-for-4-grueling-months.html">&lt;p&gt;Life purpose: I have thought long and hard about why I was so blind. Why couldn’t I understand my coach’s words, time and time again? Why couldn’t I see the importance of viewing the scenes from my character’s deathbed? Why, instead, was I so focused on scene level consequences rather than life purpose consequences?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest reason was a misfocused frame of mind. Wanting to find &lt;em&gt;external&lt;/em&gt; consequences, I misinterpreted what external meant. In writing, I’ve been taught, external typically means something you can see or take a photo of. So I imagined things ~I~ could see happening. Such as my character, after having a frightful experience at yoga, quits attending the classes and starts working late hours. And externally I stopped there since it felt like a strong consequence. One that ~I~ could see that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I’ve realized it doesn’t matter what ~I~ can see, it matters what my character sees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The definition of what is external completely changes when imagined from his deathbed. From there would my character see that yoga scene? Would this scene &lt;em&gt;matter&lt;/em&gt;? Let’s say his life purpose was to feed the hungry; would this scene matter? No. To Josh reflecting on his life — &lt;em&gt;this scene wouldn’t be seen, it wouldn’t matter. This scene wouldn’t be matter.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wouldn’t exist from Josh’s frame of mind. I had focused so much on what I could see, when in the reality of my story, all that matters or all that is matter is what my character can see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this must be the journey of a writer: movement away from the self, deeper into my character’s skin, crawling layer by layer underneath his skin until you find his soul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt; * * * &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, I see here, there are two steps for it: (1) asking the right questions. (2) asking the questions with the right frame of mind. Professional writers do both of those. The beauty: it can be trained. With enough play and thought, you can train yourself to ask the right questions with the right lenses in mind.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="writingmentalmodels," /><category term="lifespurpose_series" /><summary type="html">Life purpose: I have thought long and hard about why I was so blind. Why couldn’t I understand my coach’s words, time and time again? Why couldn’t I see the importance of viewing the scenes from my character’s deathbed? Why, instead, was I so focused on scene level consequences rather than life purpose consequences?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Decision: Corporation verse Family Saga</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/22/Story-Decision-Corporation-verse-Family-Saga.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Decision: Corporation verse Family Saga" /><published>2020-09-22T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-22T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/22/Story-Decision-Corporation-verse-Family-Saga</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/22/Story-Decision-Corporation-verse-Family-Saga.html">&lt;p&gt;Early on in my coaching, I remember a fork in the road, two directions to drive my novel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally, I envisioned my story to be a family saga, where a family of three journies together into the jungle, and each of them returns having learned something. Back in March, during my 2nd call with my coach, she highlighted a line that I included in the manuscript more as a throwaway line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The organization that hired him to translate the language, a big scary corporation who believes the language holds the potential for new ways of thought, is becoming agitated with how long it’s taking him. They’re the ones who set up this trip for him to travel there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This stood out to my coach. She said that has great potential. This overlording corporation that sends him on this journey, with hidden intentions. They want the language to manipulate people. My character will learn this truth over the course of the story, and towards the end, he will be forced to make a decision to sacrifice everything he worked for or hand the keys to manipulate others to the corporation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not the type of story I had wanted to write. Still, I thought, this year isn’t for that. It’s for going through the whole novel-writing process, to experience what it’s like. It’s to finish a story. That’s my purpose. With that in mind, I must recognize when my own desires are setting up obstacles, such as attempting to write a book that I’m not trained to write. That just adds more idling, more risk of never finished the novel, never experiencing what it’s like to write a whole novel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m leaving my family saga behind me to focus on this overlording corporation and to watch where that journey takes me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Into the jungle!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="professionalwriter" /><summary type="html">Early on in my coaching, I remember a fork in the road, two directions to drive my novel.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A movie providing two distinct emotions: Knives Out</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/21/A-movie-providing-two-distinct-emotions-Knives-Out.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A movie providing two distinct emotions: Knives Out" /><published>2020-09-21T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-21T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/21/A-movie-providing-two-distinct-emotions-Knives-Out</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/21/A-movie-providing-two-distinct-emotions-Knives-Out.html">&lt;p&gt;Many movies focus on one emotion, such as the feeling of adventure that we get when we, through the character, physically explore cool, new lands. Good movies provide more than one emotion. Jurassic Park, as we talked about, giving us adventure and anxiety. The industry default for this is one classic genre emotion, such as thriller causing anxiety or horror causing dread or comedy causing laughter and so on, mixed with a romance or relationship plot, providing some softness and love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great movies give two new emotions which are woven together in an unexpected way. Knives Out does this. It’s introduced as a classic mystery; we discover the body in the first scene, and we start to meet a large cast of interesting characters. We start getting curious, the leading emotion, asking who did it. But 30 minutes later, the movie breaks that storyline by showing us who committed the murder, a harmless, fumbly nurse without a bad bone in her body. Now, we are watching to see if Marta will get away with it, hoping she does. Meanwhile, we are watching the genius detective turn into the fumbly one as he tries to figure out it was her. Just brilliant.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">Many movies focus on one emotion, such as the feeling of adventure that we get when we, through the character, physically explore cool, new lands. Good movies provide more than one emotion. Jurassic Park, as we talked about, giving us adventure and anxiety. The industry default for this is one classic genre emotion, such as thriller causing anxiety or horror causing dread or comedy causing laughter and so on, mixed with a romance or relationship plot, providing some softness and love.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Manuscript Example: life purpose | before and after the realization</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/20/Real-example-before-and-after-life-purpose-realization.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Manuscript Example: life purpose | before and after the realization" /><published>2020-09-20T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-20T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/20/Real-example-before-and-after-life-purpose-realization</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/20/Real-example-before-and-after-life-purpose-realization.html">&lt;p&gt;Before I fall off the deep end, I want to include a concrete example. Here’s the scene sketch I had submitted in a manuscript before I learned about a character’s life purpose. Afterwards, I’ll update it with this new knowledge in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Scene idea: What if Em (female lead character) brings Josh (male lead character) to a painting class; at first Josh is hesitant to go because he paints too much like a robot and doesn’t want Em to see that. Nevertheless, he attends the class. Unexpectedly the opposite happens. Too much of his insides end up on the canvas and he feels vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expanded on this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;He goes to the class and to start he’s rigid, drawing perfect lines. The teacher pacing around sees Josh, stops, and asks if he will try an exercise. “Close your eyes,” he says. Imagine you’re back in first grade, painting. The teacher goes describing a visualization, then says open your eyes and just go. Josh puts the brush down, scoops up a blob of paint with his fingers and just goes. Feeling the paint slide between his fingers, he gets lost in the art, spending the next hour in a state of play. When they’re done, he and Em show each other. Em says something like omg, this might be the first time I truly understand you (or see inside you). [Not so literal but something along those lines.] Josh instantly feels vulnerable and never does that again. Learns that playing like that without control is dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right there I stopped my work on this sketch. I thought, okay, this is a scene caused by his internal problem, the fear of emotions and the feeling vulnerable, and he learns to protect himself. From now on he’ll be careful with creative work. And I thought this has an external cause because Josh going forward no longer will take artistic risks. The scene-sketch felt complete. And I stopped there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, it’s clear to me this isn’t tethered to anything of importance in Josh’s life. It’s a one-off, a scene that just floats away, never to be remembered again. A scene that I could forever forget about without consequences to Josh’s story. The story he sees from his deathbed is the exact same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to add consequences?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting with life purpose: let’s say, Josh has a life’s mission to become a polyglot, speaking 7 languages. Currently, he’s only working to earn money for the next trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And let’s say, recently he and Em started discussing to take their next three-month trip. One of the worries that Em keeps bringing up is about losing their jobs since that happened after their first trip. She wants to ensure they make a responsible decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, this art scene happens. And Em sees Josh’s insides. And Josh believes that she’ll read into it that he’s a mess and that he’s not in a good place to go on this trip. And later that night, they discuss travel again. Josh brings it up. Em says she doesn’t want to leave her job. Josh misreads her meaning, believes she won’t travel. He’s scared they won’t go. He feels like a mess. So, to not feel that way, he gets angry, he yells, he demands they go. He books his ticket in rage. Em leaves him. He goes alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, that has a huge external cause/effect. That he certainly will see on his deathbed. And that resentment or that need to feel put together will carry through and affect more of his decisions. That just doesn’t float away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt; * * * &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To arrive at the above, I actually sketched a doodle out to guide me. Imagining how this scene could affect Josh’s overarching desires in life — here’s the image I saw:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SilenceVosh/silencevosh.github.io/master/_posts/assets/images/ArtClass.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;image info&quot; title=&quot;Life's Purpose&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just something I’ve been as of late childishly playing around with.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="professionalwriter," /><category term="lifespurpose_series" /><summary type="html">Before I fall off the deep end, I want to include a concrete example. Here’s the scene sketch I had submitted in a manuscript before I learned about a character’s life purpose. Afterwards, I’ll update it with this new knowledge in mind.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Coaching: The Power of Deadlines</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/19/Coaching-The-Power-of-Deadlines.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coaching: The Power of Deadlines" /><published>2020-09-19T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-19T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/19/Coaching-The-Power-of-Deadlines</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/19/Coaching-The-Power-of-Deadlines.html">&lt;p&gt;Ever since I started working with a story coach, it has changed the way I manage my writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting back in February, each thrid week, she reviews and we discuss my recent progress on my current novel. Each third week, a deadline, a manuscript due. Forced out of necessity, I’ve designed a system to manage this, a system for processing coaching notes, for deciding what to work on, for managing what to work on (writing, research, digging up scene details), for keeping track of mistakes and learnings. A system for becoming a professional writer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember, after my first call, I had a dozen different things to work on. Completely lost what to start with. With no system, they all floating around my head, never allowing me to be immersed in the task at hand. In the end, I did the bare minimum on each. I was unsatisfied. And learned, if I’m unable to figure a system out, I’m just wasting my money…and what better motivator is there than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next week, I had another dozen things to work on. I spun my wheels some more. I created nothing with substance. Money wasted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chugged forward, learning manuscript by manuscript, how to do each slightly better. Until one day, enough spinning in place, enough unsatisfaction, and enough little tweaks, I suddenly had a system filled with value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would have been impossible without deadlines, I believe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Keep spinning, you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="professionalwriter" /><summary type="html">Ever since I started working with a story coach, it has changed the way I manage my writing.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Setting the Tone: Vikings</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/18/Setting-the-tone-Vikings.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Setting the Tone: Vikings" /><published>2020-09-18T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-18T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/18/Setting-the-tone-Vikings</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/18/Setting-the-tone-Vikings.html">&lt;p&gt;Another example of this. A great one: episode 2 of the show Vikings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few of the Vikings who we’ve been following and have grown to like arrive on an island of monks. I imagined them taking the island, robbing the gold and valuables, and going about their way. Suddenly, my favorite character begins to slice these innocent, arm-less monks into two. The slaughter begins. They massacre every single one of them. Then go on their merry way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
That’s a promise to us. This show will be about a bunch of savages. Get used to it or move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt; * * * &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A final note: pay close attention to the first couple of scenes in anything you watch, anything you read, and you will see these promises. In Indiana Jones, the movie opens with Harrison Ford running from a boulder. After they promise you this adventure, they cut to him in a college where the action slows down, so they can set up some details of the story, before the real adventure. And in Game of Thrones, the show opens with a scene showing the white walkers. We won’t see them again until the last 10 seconds of the season, showing their army approaching.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">Another example of this. A great one: episode 2 of the show Vikings.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jurassic Park: how does it get away with the midpoint change in tone?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/17/Jurassic-Park-how-does-it-get-away-with-the-midpoint-change-in-tone.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jurassic Park: how does it get away with the midpoint change in tone?" /><published>2020-09-17T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-17T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/17/Jurassic-Park-how-does-it-get-away-with-the-midpoint-change-in-tone</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/17/Jurassic-Park-how-does-it-get-away-with-the-midpoint-change-in-tone.html">&lt;p&gt;Where many movies and books go wrong is suddenly changing the tone and the emotions of the story. If you’re going along watching a rom-com and midway through the movie Scream-mask-guy shows up and kills the male protagonist in his sleep and now the female protagonist spends the rest of the movie fighting for her life, you’ve been lied to. At least it feels like it, so you walk out or watch something else. You never agreed to feel those emotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Jurassic Park, they promised horror from the very first scene. The movie opens with a raptor eating a construction worker. Then the danger of them is foreshadowed throughout. On top of that, everyone is asking morality questions, hinting at mother nature having her revenge. So when a T-Rex shreds the lawyer into two, we’re okay with it. We were emotionally prepared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Last night, I watched a movie that played out right on the border of emotional preparation. In ~Drive~, we’re watching a crime film, so we know there will be violence, but it isn’t until 60% into the movie do we watch a girl lose her head from a shotgun. I’m sure that surprised many and even caused some to turn it off.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">Where many movies and books go wrong is suddenly changing the tone and the emotions of the story. If you’re going along watching a rom-com and midway through the movie Scream-mask-guy shows up and kills the male protagonist in his sleep and now the female protagonist spends the rest of the movie fighting for her life, you’ve been lied to. At least it feels like it, so you walk out or watch something else. You never agreed to feel those emotions.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jurassic Park: midpoint genre (emotion) change</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/16/Jurassic-Park-midpoint-genre-(emotion)-change.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jurassic Park: midpoint genre (emotion) change" /><published>2020-09-16T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-16T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/16/Jurassic-Park-midpoint-genre-(emotion)-change</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/16/Jurassic-Park-midpoint-genre-(emotion)-change.html">&lt;p&gt;The first half of Jurassic Park is an idea story: what if we could bring back dinosaurs? As moviegoers, we desire to explore the ramifications of that. Here are some of the beats we get to explore:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When Dr. Grant arrives, in awe, we see the dinosaurs resurrected. Dr. Grant begins to match his theories to their behavior, something he never in his wildest dreams thought would be possible.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next, we learn how it all was possible, how these dinosaurs were brought to life. Climaxed with being able to watch one in real-time hatching out of an egg.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next, in horror, we watch a feeding; a raptor, in a blink, devour a cow.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Triggered by the fright, we begin to discuss the morality of having something that horrifyingly dangerous here.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lastly, we summarized all of this with a grand tour of the park.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a fun, carefree exploration. Never do we feel in danger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Halfway through the movie, everything changes. The storm clouds slide in. Under the moon-light, the monsters are set free. Now we run. We run for our lives, verses something we can’t comprehend. And we spent the rest of the movie in fear and running, unable to do anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I like this pacing, as it gives two different distinct emotions. The first is exploring and awing. The second is anxiety and dread.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="storyblink" /><summary type="html">The first half of Jurassic Park is an idea story: what if we could bring back dinosaurs? As moviegoers, we desire to explore the ramifications of that. Here are some of the beats we get to explore:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">intuition: Confusion verse Questioning</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/15/intuition-confusing-verse-questioning.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="intuition: Confusion verse Questioning" /><published>2020-09-15T07:10:59-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-15T07:10:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/15/intuition-confusing-verse-questioning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/15/intuition-confusing-verse-questioning.html">&lt;p&gt;Let me pause. This series – I realized while writing this post – seemed to be unfocused, debating something incredibly abstract and likely pointless: how do I distinguish thoughts which confuse my direction in life and thoughts which wisely question the decision. So instead I want to slow down and make sure I understand my agenda with this series. The purpose is to understand how I can get in touch with my true desires, with how I feel and what I want, both moment to moment and with life’s big decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I started my blog, for example, I had many internal criticisms: care for the reader; write well; only post essays which have value; no one cares about what makes you laugh. Just laugh and stop thinking about it. Definitively, for the sake of god and all his children, don’t write a whole blog post about what makes you laugh. While these are healthy questions and thoughts, they blocked me from doing what I truly wanted…to blog every day. They caused confusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through this series, I want to figure out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What blocks me?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are the dangers, both with being blocked and being too free?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to distinguish these?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How does someone who’s rightly in touch with their intuition move throughout the world?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To jump the gun, my short answer to my agenda is to simply be in touch with what I want. What do I want in this moment? What do I want in my life? And ensuring I’m healthily in touch with those desires.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Silence</name></author><category term="humanlearnings," /><category term="intuition_series" /><summary type="html">Let me pause. This series – I realized while writing this post – seemed to be unfocused, debating something incredibly abstract and likely pointless: how do I distinguish thoughts which confuse my direction in life and thoughts which wisely question the decision. So instead I want to slow down and make sure I understand my agenda with this series. The purpose is to understand how I can get in touch with my true desires, with how I feel and what I want, both moment to moment and with life’s big decisions.</summary></entry></feed>